<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mteval>
<srcset setid="iwslt2017-tst2017" srclang="english">
<doc docid="2455" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/latif_nasser_you_have_no_idea_where_camels_really_come_from</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Camels are so well adapted to the desert that it's hard to imagine them living anywhere else. But what if we have them pegged all wrong? What if those big humps, feet and eyes were evolved for a different climate and a different time? In this talk, join Radiolab's Latif Nasser as he tells the surprising story of how a very tiny, very strange fossil upended the way he sees camels, and the world. This talk comes from the PBS special "TED Talks: Science &amp; Wonder."</description> 
<keywords>talks, ancient world, animals, biology, curiosity, ecology, environment, evolution, history, life, nature, paleontology, science</keywords> 
<talkid>2455</talkid> 
<title>Latif Nasser: You have no idea where camels really come from</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> So, this is a story  about how we know what we know.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> It's a story about this woman,  Natalia Rybczynski.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> She's a paleobiologist,  which means she specializes in digging up really old dead stuff.    </seg>
<seg id="4">  Natalia Rybczynski: Yeah, I had someone call me "Dr. Dead Things."    </seg>
<seg id="5"> Latif Nasser: And I think she's particularly interesting  because of where she digs that stuff up,  way above the Arctic Circle in the remote Canadian tundra.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> Now, one summer day in 2006,  she was at a dig site called the Fyles Leaf Bed,  which is less than 10 degrees latitude away from the magnetic north pole.    </seg>
<seg id="7">  NR: Really, it's not going to sound very exciting,  because it was a day of walking with your backpack and your GPS  and notebook and just picking up anything that might be a fossil.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> LN: And at some point, she noticed something.    </seg>
<seg id="9">  NR: Rusty, kind of rust-colored,  about the size of the palm of my hand.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> It was just lying on the surface.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> LN: And at first she thought it was just a splinter of wood,  because that's the sort of thing people had found  at the Fyles Leaf Bed before -- prehistoric plant parts.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> But that night, back at camp ...    </seg>
<seg id="13">  NR: ... I get out the hand lens,  I'm looking a little bit more closely and realizing  it doesn't quite look like this has tree rings.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> Maybe it's a preservation thing,  but it looks really like ...    </seg>
<seg id="15"> bone.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> LN: Huh. So over the next four years,  she went to that spot over and over,  and eventually collected 30 fragments of that exact same bone,  most of them really tiny.    </seg>
<seg id="17">  NR: It's not a whole lot. It fits in a small Ziploc bag.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> LN: And she tried to piece them together like a jigsaw puzzle.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> But it was challenging.    </seg>
<seg id="20">  NR: It's broken up into so many little tiny pieces,  I'm trying to use sand and putty, and it's not looking good.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> So finally, we used a 3D surface scanner.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> LN: Ooh! NR: Yeah, right?    </seg>
<seg id="23">   LN: It turns out it was way easier to do it virtually.    </seg>
<seg id="24">  NR: It's kind of magical when it all fits together.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> LN: How certain were you that you had it right,  that you had put it together in the right way?    </seg>
<seg id="26"> Was there a potential that you'd put it together a different way  and have, like, a parakeet or something?    </seg>
<seg id="27">    NR:  Um, no. No, we got this.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> LN: What she had, she discovered, was a tibia, a leg bone,  and specifically, one that belonged to a cloven-hoofed mammal,  so something like a cow or a sheep.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> But it couldn't have been either of those.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> It was just too big.    </seg>
<seg id="31">  NR: The size of this thing, it was huge. It's a really big animal.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> LN: So what animal could it be?    </seg>
<seg id="33"> Having hit a wall, she showed one of the fragments  to some colleagues of hers in Colorado,  and they had an idea.    </seg>
<seg id="34">  NR: We took a saw, and we nicked just the edge of it,  and there was this really interesting smell that comes from it.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> LN: It smelled kind of like singed flesh.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> It was a smell that Natalia recognized  from cutting up skulls in her gross anatomy lab:  collagen.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> Collagen is what gives structure to our bones.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> And usually, after so many years,  it breaks down.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> But in this case, the Arctic had acted like a natural freezer and preserved it.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> Then a year or two later, Natalia was at a conference in Bristol,  and she saw that a colleague of hers named Mike Buckley  was demoing this new process that he called "collagen fingerprinting."    </seg>
<seg id="41"> It turns out that different species have slightly different structures  of collagen,  so if you get a collagen profile of an unknown bone,  you can compare it to those of known species,  and, who knows, maybe you get a match.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> So she shipped him one of the fragments,  FedEx.    </seg>
<seg id="43">  NR: Yeah, you want to track it. It's kind of important.    </seg>
<seg id="44">   LN: And he processed it,  and compared it to 37 known and modern-day mammal species.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> And he found a match.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> It turns out that the 3.5 million-year-old bone  that Natalia had dug out of the High Arctic  belonged to ...    </seg>
<seg id="47"> a camel.    </seg>
<seg id="48">    NR: And I'm thinking, what? That's amazing -- if it's true.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> LN: So they tested a bunch of the fragments,  and they got the same result for each one.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> However, based on the size of the bone that they found,  it meant that this camel was 30 percent larger than modern-day camels.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> So this camel would have been about nine feet tall,  weighed around a ton.    </seg>
<seg id="52">   Yeah.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> Natalia had found a Giant Arctic camel.    </seg>
<seg id="54">   Now, when you hear the word "camel,"  what may come to mind is one of these,  the Bactrian camel of East and Central Asia.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> But chances are the postcard image you have in your brain  is one of these, the dromedary,  quintessential desert creature --  hangs out in sandy, hot places like the Middle East and the Sahara,  has a big old hump on its back  for storing water for those long desert treks,  has big, broad feet to help it tromp over sand dunes.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> So how on earth would one of these guys end up in the High Arctic?    </seg>
<seg id="57"> Well, scientists have known for a long time, turns out,  even before Natalia's discovery,  that camels are actually originally American.    </seg>
<seg id="58">     They started here.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> For nearly 40 of the 45 million years that camels have been around,  you could only find them in North America,  around 20 different species, maybe more.    </seg>
<seg id="60">  LN: If I put them all in a lineup, would they look different?    </seg>
<seg id="61"> NR: Yeah, you're going to have different body sizes.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> You'll have some with really long necks,  so they're actually functionally like giraffes.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> LN: Some had snouts, like crocodiles.    </seg>
<seg id="64">  NR: The really primitive, early ones would have been really small,  almost like rabbits.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> LN: What? Rabbit-sized camels?    </seg>
<seg id="66">  NR: The earliest ones.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> So those ones you probably would not recognize.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> LN: Oh my God, I want a pet rabbit-camel.    </seg>
<seg id="69">  NR: I know, wouldn't that be great?    </seg>
<seg id="70">   LN: And then about three to seven million years ago,  one branch of camels went down to South America,  where they became llamas and alpacas,  and another branch crossed over the Bering Land Bridge  into Asia and Africa.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> And then around the end of the last ice age,  North American camels went extinct.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> So, scientists knew all of that already,  but it still doesn't fully explain how Natalia found one so far north.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> Like, this is, temperature-wise, the polar opposite of the Sahara.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> Now to be fair,  three and a half million years ago,  it was on average 22 degrees Celsius warmer than it is now.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> So it would have been boreal forest,  so more like the Yukon or Siberia today.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> But still, like, they would have six-month-long winters  where the ponds would freeze over.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> You'd have blizzards.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> You'd have 24 hours a day of straight darkness.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> Like, how ... How?    </seg>
<seg id="80"> How is it that one of these Saharan superstars  could ever have survived those arctic conditions?    </seg>
<seg id="81">   Natalia and her colleagues think they have an answer.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> And it's kind of brilliant.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> What if the very features that we imagine make the camel so well-suited  to places like the Sahara,  actually evolved to help it get through the winter?    </seg>
<seg id="84"> What if those broad feet were meant to tromp not over sand,  but over snow, like a pair of snowshoes?    </seg>
<seg id="85"> What if that hump -- which, huge news to me,  does not contain water, it contains fat --    was there to help the camel get through that six-month-long winter,  when food was scarce?    </seg>
<seg id="86"> And then, only later, long after it crossed over the land bridge  did it retrofit those winter features for a hot desert environment?    </seg>
<seg id="87"> Like, for instance, the hump may be helpful to camels in hotter climes  because having all your fat in one place,  like a, you know, fat backpack,  means that you don't have to have that insulation  all over the rest of your body.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> So it helps heat dissipate easier.    </seg>
<seg id="89"> It's this crazy idea,  that what seems like proof of the camel's quintessential desert nature  could actually be proof of its High Arctic past.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> Now, I'm not the first person to tell this story.    </seg>
<seg id="91"> Others have told it as a way to marvel at evolutionary biology  or as a keyhole into the future of climate change.    </seg>
<seg id="92"> But I love it for a totally different reason.    </seg>
<seg id="93"> For me, it's a story about us,  about how we see the world  and about how that changes.    </seg>
<seg id="94"> So I was trained as a historian.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> And I've learned that, actually, a lot of scientists are historians, too.    </seg>
<seg id="96"> They make sense of the past.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> They tell the history of our universe, of our planet, of life on this planet.    </seg>
<seg id="98"> And as a historian,  you start with an idea in your mind of how the story goes.    </seg>
<seg id="99">  NR: We make up stories and we stick with it,  like the camel in the desert, right?    </seg>
<seg id="100"> That's a great story! It's totally adapted for that.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> Clearly, it always lived there.    </seg>
<seg id="102"> LN: But at any moment, you could uncover some tiny bit of evidence.    </seg>
<seg id="103"> You could learn some tiny thing  that forces you to reframe everything you thought you knew.    </seg>
<seg id="104"> Like, in this case, this one scientist finds this one shard  of what she thought was wood,  and because of that, science has a totally new and totally counterintuitive theory  about why this absurd Dr. Seuss-looking creature  looks the way it does.    </seg>
<seg id="105"> And for me, it completely upended the way I think of the camel.    </seg>
<seg id="106"> It went from being this ridiculously niche creature  suited only to this one specific environment,  to being this world traveler that just happens to be in the Sahara,  and could end up virtually anywhere.    </seg>
<seg id="107">   This is Azuri.    </seg>
<seg id="108"> Azuri, hi, how are you doing?    </seg>
<seg id="109"> OK, here, I've got one of these for you here.    </seg>
<seg id="110">   So Azuri is on a break from her regular gig  at the Radio City Music Hall.    </seg>
<seg id="111">   That's not even a joke.    </seg>
<seg id="112"> Anyway --  But really, Azuri is here as a living reminder  that the story of our world is a dynamic one.    </seg>
<seg id="113"> It requires our willingness to readjust, to reimagine.    </seg>
<seg id="114">   Right, Azuri?    </seg>
<seg id="115"> And, really, that we're all just one shard of bone away  from seeing the world anew.    </seg>
<seg id="116"> Thank you very much.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2459" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/meron_gribetz_a_glimpse_of_the_future_through_an_augmented_reality_headset</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: What if technology could connect us more deeply with our surroundings instead of distracting us from the real world? With the Meta 2, an augmented reality headset that makes it possible for users to see, grab and move holograms just like physical objects, Meron Gribetz hopes to extend our senses through a more natural machine. Join Gribetz as he takes the TED stage to demonstrate the reality-shifting Meta 2 for the first time. </description> 
<keywords>talks, Senses, augmented reality, brain, computers, creativity, cyborg, demo, design, engineering, entrepreneur, innovation, interface design, invention, neuroscience, potential, prediction, product design, technology, visualizations</keywords> 
<talkid>2459</talkid> 
<title>Meron Gribetz: A glimpse of the future through an augmented reality headset</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> Today's computers are so amazing  that we fail to notice how terrible they really are.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> I'd like to talk to you today about this problem,  and how we can fix it with neuroscience.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> First, I'd like to take you back to a frosty night in Harlem in 2011  that had a profound impact on me.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> I was sitting in a dive bar outside of Columbia University,  where I studied computer science and neuroscience,  and I was having this great conversation with a fellow student  about the power of holograms to one day replace computers.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> And just as we were getting to the best part of the conversation,  of course, his phone lights up.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> And he pulls it towards himself, and he looks down and he starts typing.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> And then he forces his eyeballs back up to mine and he goes,  "Keep going. I'm with you."    </seg>
<seg id="8"> But of course his eyes were glazed over,  and the moment was dead.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> Meanwhile across the bar,  I noticed another student holding his phone,  this time towards a group.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> He was swiping through pictures on Instagram,  and these kids were laughing hysterically.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> And that dichotomy between how crappy I was feeling  and how happy they were feeling about the same technology,  really got me thinking.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> And the more I thought of it, the more I realized  it was clearly not the digital information that was the bad guy here,  it was simply the display position that was separating me from my friend  and that was binding those kids together.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> See, they were connected around something,  just like our ancestors who evolved their social cognitions  telling stories around the campfire.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> And that's exactly what tools should do, I think.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> They should extend our bodies.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> And I think computers today are doing quite the opposite.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> Whether you're sending an email to your wife  or you're composing a symphony  or just consoling a friend,  you're doing it in pretty much the same way.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> You're hunched over these rectangles,  fumbling with buttons and menus and more rectangles.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> And I think this is the wrong way,  I think we can start using a much more natural machine.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> We should use machines that bring our work back into the world.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> We should use machines that use the principles of neuroscience  to extend our senses versus going against them.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> Now it just so happens that I have such a machine here.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> It's called the Meta 2.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> Let's try it out.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> Now in front of me right now, I can see the audience,  and I can see my very hands.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> And in three, two, one,  we're going to see an immersive hologram appear,  a very realistic hologram appear in front of me,  of our very glasses I'm wearing on my head right now.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> And of course this could be anything that we're shopping for  or learning from,  and I can use my hands  to very nicely kind of move it around with fine control.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> And I think Iron Man would be proud.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> We're going to come back to this in just a bit.    </seg>
<seg id="30">   Now if you're anything like me, your mind is already reeling  with the possibilities of what we can do with this kind of technology,  so let's look at a few.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> My mom is an architect,  so naturally the first thing I imagined  was laying out a building in 3D space  instead of having to use these 2D floor plans.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> She's actually touching graphics right now  and selecting an interior decor.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> This was all shot through a GoPro through our very glasses.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> And this next use case is very personal to me,  it's Professor Adam Gazzaley's glass brain project,  courtesy of UCSF.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> As a neuroscience student,  I would always fantasize  about the ability to learn and memorize these complex brain structures  with an actual machine,  where I could touch and play with the various brain structures.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> Now what you're seeing is called augmented reality,  but to me, it's part of a much more important story --  a story of how we can begin to extend our bodies with digital devices,  instead of the other way around.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> Now ...    </seg>
<seg id="38"> in the next few years, humanity's going to go through a shift, I think.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> We're going to start putting an entire layer of digital information  on the real world.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> Just imagine for a moment  what this could mean for storytellers,  for painters,  for brain surgeons,  for interior decorators  and maybe for all of us here today.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> And what I think we need to do as a community,  is really try and make an effort  to imagine how we can create this new reality  in a way that extends the human experience,  instead of gamifying our reality  or cluttering it with digital information.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> And that's what I'm very passionate about.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> Now, I want to tell you a little secret.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> In about five years --  this is not the smallest device --  in about five years,  these are all going to look like strips of glass on our eyes  that project holograms.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> And just like we don't care so much about which phone we buy  in terms of the hardware -- we buy it for the operating system --  as a neuroscientist,  I always dreamt of building the iOS of the mind, if you will.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> And it's very, very important that we get this right,  because we might be living inside of these things  for at least as long as we've lived  with the Windows graphical user interface.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> And I don't know about you,  but living inside of Windows scares me.    </seg>
<seg id="48">   To isolate the single most intuitive interface out of infinity,  we use neuroscience to drive our design guidelines,  instead of letting a bunch of designers fight it out in the boardroom.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> And the principle we all revolve around  is what's called the "Neural Path of Least Resistance."    </seg>
<seg id="50"> At every turn, we're connecting the iOS of the brain with our brain  on, for the first time, our brain's terms.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> In other words, we're trying to create a zero learning-curve computer.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> We're building a system that you've always known how to use.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> Here are the first three design guidelines that we employ  in this brand-new form of user experience.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> First and foremost, you are the operating system.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> Traditional file systems are complex and abstract,  and they take your brain extra steps to decode them.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> We're going against the Neural Path of Least Resistance.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> Meanwhile, in augmented reality,  you can of course place your holographic TED panel over here,  and your holographic email on the other side of the desk,  and your spatial memory evolved just fine to go ahead and retrieve them.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> You could put your holographic Tesla that you're shopping for --  or whatever model my legal team told me to put in right before the show.    </seg>
<seg id="59">   Perfect. And your brain knows exactly how to get it back.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> The second interface guideline we call "touch to see."    </seg>
<seg id="61"> What do babies do when they see something that grabs their interest?    </seg>
<seg id="62"> They try and reach out and touch it.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> And that's exactly how the natural machine should work as well.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> Turns out the visual system gets a fundamental boost  from a sense we call proprioception --  that's the sense of our body parts in space.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> So by touching our work directly, we're not only going to control it better,  we're also going to understand it much more deeply.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> Hence, touch to see.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> But it's not enough to experience things ourselves.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> We're inherently these social primates.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> And this leads me to our third guideline,  the holographic campfire from our first story.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> Our mirror-neuron subsystem suggests  that we can connect with each other and with our work much better  if we can see each other's faces and hands in 3D.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> So if you look at the video behind me,  you can see two Meta users playing around with the same hologram,  making eye contact, connected around this thing,  instead of being distracted by external devices.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> Let's go ahead and try this again with neuroscience in mind.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> So again, our favorite interface, the iOS of the mind.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> I'm going to now take a step further  and go ahead and grab this pair of glasses  and leave it right here by the desk.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> I'm now with you, I'm in the moment,  we're connecting.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> My spatial memory kicks in, and I can go ahead and grab it  and bring it right back here, reminding me  that I am the operating system.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> And now my proprioception is working,  and I can go ahead and explode these glasses into a thousand parts  and touch the very sensor that is currently scanning my hand.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> But it's not enough to see things alone,  so in a second, my co-founder Ray is going to make a 3D call --  Ray?    </seg>
<seg id="79">   Hey Ray, how's it going?    </seg>
<seg id="80"> Guys, I can see this guy in front me in full 3D.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> And he is photo-realistic.    </seg>
<seg id="82">   Thank you.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> My mirror-neuron subsystem suggests that this is going to replace phones  in not too long.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> Ray, how's it going?    </seg>
<seg id="85"> Ray: Great. We're live today.    </seg>
<seg id="86">   MG: Ray, give the crowd a gift  of the holographic brain we saw from the video earlier.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> Guys, this is not only going to change phones,  it's also going to change the way we collaborate.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> Thank you so much.    </seg>
<seg id="89"> Thanks, Ray.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> Ray: You're welcome.    </seg>
<seg id="91">   MG: So folks, this is the message that I discovered in that bar in 2011:  The future of computers is not locked inside one of these screens.    </seg>
<seg id="92"> It's right here, inside of us.    </seg>
<seg id="93">   So if there's one idea that I could leave you with here today,  it's that the natural machine is not some figment of the future,  it's right here in 2016.    </seg>
<seg id="94"> Which is why all hundred of us at Meta,  including the administrative staff,  the executives,  the designers, the engineers --  before TED2017,  we're all going to be throwing away our external monitors  and replacing them with a truly and profoundly more natural machine.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> Thank you very much.    </seg>
<seg id="96">   Thank you, appreciate it.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> Thanks, guys.    </seg>
<seg id="98"> Chris Anderson: So help me out on one thing,  because there've been a few augmented reality demos  shown over the last year or so out there.    </seg>
<seg id="99"> And there's sometimes a debate among technologists  about, are we really seeing the real thing on-screen?    </seg>
<seg id="100"> There's this issue of field of view,  that somehow the technology is showing a broader view  than you would actually see wearing the glasses.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> Were we seeing the real deal there?    </seg>
<seg id="102"> MG: Absolutely the real deal.    </seg>
<seg id="103"> Not only that,  we took extra measures to shoot it with a GoPro through the actual lens  in the various videos that you've seen here.    </seg>
<seg id="104"> We want to try to simulate the experience for the world  that we're actually seeing through the glasses,  and not cut any corners.    </seg>
<seg id="105"> CA: Thank you so much for showing us that.    </seg>
<seg id="106"> MG: Thanks so much, I appreciate that.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2456" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/arthur_brooks_a_conservative_s_plea_let_s_work_together</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Conservatives and liberals both believe that they alone are motivated by love while their opponents are motivated by hate. How can we solve problems with so much polarization? In this talk, social scientist Arthur Brooks shares ideas for what we can each do as individuals to break the gridlock. "We might just be able to take the ghastly holy war of ideology that we're suffering under and turn it into a competition of ideas," he says.</description> 
<keywords>talks, Debate, big problems, business, capitalism, collaboration, community, democracy, economics, global issues, government, identity, leadership, philosophy, policy, politics, social change, society</keywords> 
<talkid>2456</talkid> 
<title>Arthur Brooks: A conservative's plea: Let's work together</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> I come from one of the most liberal,  tolerant, progressive places in the United States,  Seattle, Washington.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> And I grew up with a family of great Seattlites.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> My mother was an artist, my father was a college professor,  and I am truly grateful for my upbringing,  because I always felt completely comfortable designing my life  exactly as I saw fit.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> And in point of fact,  I took a route that was not exactly what my parents had in mind.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> When I was 19, I dropped out of college --  dropped out, kicked out, splitting hairs.    </seg>
<seg id="6">   And I went on the road as a professional French horn player,  which was my lifelong dream.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> I played chamber music all over the United States and Europe,  and I toured for a couple of years  with a great jazz guitar player named Charlie Bird.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> And by the end of my 20s,  I wound up as a member of the Barcelona Symphony Orchestra in Spain.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> What a great life.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> And you know, my parents never complained.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> They supported me all the way through it.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> It wasn't their dream.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> They used to tell their neighbors and friends,  "Our son, he's taking a gap decade."    </seg>
<seg id="14">   And --  There was, however, one awkward conversation about my lifestyle  that I want to tell you about.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> I was 27, and I was home from Barcelona,  and I was visiting my parents for Christmas,  and I was cooking dinner with my mother, and we were alone in the kitchen.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> And she was quiet, too quiet.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> Something was wrong.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> And so I said, "Mom, what's on your mind?"    </seg>
<seg id="19"> And she said, "Your dad and I are really worried about you."    </seg>
<seg id="20"> And I said, "What?" I mean, what could it be, at this point?    </seg>
<seg id="21"> And she said, "I want you to be completely honest with me:  have you been voting for Republicans?"    </seg>
<seg id="22">   Now, the truth is,  I wasn't really political, I was just a French horn player.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> But I had a bit of an epiphany,  and they had detected it, and it was causing some confusion.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> You see, I had become an enthusiast for capitalism,  and I want to tell you why that is.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> It stems from a lifelong interest of mine  in, believe it or not, poverty.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> See, when I was a kid growing up in Seattle,  I remember the first time I saw real poverty.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> We were a lower middle class family, but that's of course not real poverty.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> That's not even close.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> The first time I saw poverty, and poverty's face,  was when I was six or seven years old, early 1970s.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> And it was like a lot of you, kind of a prosaic example, kind of trite.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> It was a picture in the National Geographic Magazine  of a kid who was my age in East Africa,  and there were flies on his face and a distended belly.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> And he wasn't going to make it, and I knew that, and I was helpless.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> Some of you remember that picture,  not exactly that picture, one just like it.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> It introduced the West to grinding poverty around the world.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> Well, that vision kind of haunted me as I grew up and I went to school  and I dropped out and dropped in  and started my family.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> And I wondered, what happened to that kid?    </seg>
<seg id="37"> Or to people just like him all over the world?    </seg>
<seg id="38"> And so I started to study, even though I wasn't in college,  I was looking for the answer:  what happened to the world's poorest people?    </seg>
<seg id="39"> Has it gotten worse? Has it gotten better? What?    </seg>
<seg id="40"> And I found the answer, and it changed my life,  and I want to share it with you.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> See --  most Americans believe that poverty has gotten worse  since we were children, since they saw that vision.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> If you ask Americans, "Has poverty gotten worse or better around the world?",  70 percent will say that hunger has gotten worse since the early 1970s.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> But here's the truth.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> Here's the epiphany that I had that changed my thinking.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> From 1970 until today,  the percentage of the world's population  living in starvation levels,  living on a dollar a day or less, obviously adjusted for inflation,  that percentage has declined  by 80 percent.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> There's been an 80 percent decline in the world's worst poverty  since I was a kid.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> And I didn't even know about it.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> This, my friends, that's a miracle.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> That's something we ought to celebrate.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> It's the greatest antipoverty achievement in the history of mankind,  and it happened in our lifetimes.    </seg>
<seg id="51">   So when I learned this, I asked, what did that? What made it possible?    </seg>
<seg id="52"> Because if you don't know why, you can't do it again.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> If you want to replicate it  and get the next two billion people out of poverty,  because that's what we're talking about: since I was a kid,  two billion of the least of these, our brothers and sisters,  have been pulled out of poverty.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> I want the next two billion, so I've got to know why.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> And I went in search of an answer.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> And it wasn't a political answer, because I didn't care.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> You know what, I still don't care.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> I wanted the best answer from mainstream economists  left, right and center.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> And here it is.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> Here are the reasons.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> There are five reasons that two billion of our brothers and sisters  have been pulled out of poverty since I was a kid.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> Number one: globalization.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> Number two: free trade.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> Number three: property rights.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> Number four: rule of law.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> Number five: entrepreneurship.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> It was the free enterprise system spreading around the world  after 1970 that did that.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> Now, I'm not naive.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> I know that free enterprise isn't perfect,  and I know that free enterprise isn't everything we need  to build a better world.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> But that is great.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> And that's beyond politics.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> Here's what I learned. This is the epiphany.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> Capitalism is not just about accumulation.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> At its best, it's about aspiration,  which is what so many people on this stage talk about,  is the aspiration that comes from dreams  that are embedded in the free enterprise system.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> And we've got to share it with more people.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> Now, I want to tell you about a second epiphany  that's related to that first one  that I think can bring us progress, not just around the world,  but right here at home.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> The best quote I've ever heard  to summarize the thoughts that I've just given you  about pulling people out of poverty  is as follows:  "Free markets have created more wealth than any system in history.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> They have lifted billions out of poverty."    </seg>
<seg id="79"> Who said it?    </seg>
<seg id="80"> It sounds like Milton Friedman or Ronald Reagan.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> Wrong.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> President Barack Obama said that.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> Why do I know it by heart?    </seg>
<seg id="84"> Because he said it to me.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> Crazy.    </seg>
<seg id="86"> And I said, "Hallelujah."    </seg>
<seg id="87"> But more than that, I said,  "What an opportunity."    </seg>
<seg id="88"> You know what I was thinking?    </seg>
<seg id="89"> It was at an event that we were doing on the subject  at Georgetown University in May of 2015.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> And I thought, this is the solution  to the biggest problem facing America today. What?    </seg>
<seg id="91"> It's coming together around these ideas,  liberals and conservatives,  to help people who need us the most.    </seg>
<seg id="92"> Now, I don't have to tell anybody in this room that we're in a crisis,  in America and many countries around the world with political polarization.    </seg>
<seg id="93"> It's risen to critical, crisis levels.    </seg>
<seg id="94"> It's unpleasant. It's not right.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> There was an article last year  in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences,  which is one of the most prestigious scientific journals  published in the West.    </seg>
<seg id="96"> And it was an article in 2014  on political motive asymmetry.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> What's that? That's what psychologists call the phenomenon  of assuming that your ideology is based in love  but your opponents' ideology is based in hate.    </seg>
<seg id="98"> It's common in world conflict.    </seg>
<seg id="99"> You expect to see this between Palestinians and Israelis, for example.    </seg>
<seg id="100"> What the authors of this article found  was that in America today, a majority of Republicans and Democrats  suffer from political motive asymmetry.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> A majority of people in our country today who are politically active believe  that they are motivated by love but the other side is motivated by hate.    </seg>
<seg id="102"> Think about it. Think about it.    </seg>
<seg id="103"> Most people are walking around saying,  "You know, my ideology is based on basic benevolence,  I want to help people,  but the other guys, they're evil and out to get me."    </seg>
<seg id="104"> You can't progress as a society when you have this kind of asymmetry.    </seg>
<seg id="105"> It's impossible.    </seg>
<seg id="106"> How do we solve it?    </seg>
<seg id="107"> Well, first, let's be honest: there are differences.    </seg>
<seg id="108"> Let's not minimize the differences. That would be really naïve.    </seg>
<seg id="109"> There's a lot of good research on this.    </seg>
<seg id="110"> A veteran of the TED stage is my friend Jonathan Haidt.    </seg>
<seg id="111"> He's a psychology professor at New York University.    </seg>
<seg id="112"> He does work on the ideology and values and morals of different people  to see how they differ.    </seg>
<seg id="113"> And he's shown, for example, that conservatives and liberals  have a very different emphasis on what they think is important.    </seg>
<seg id="114"> For example, Jon Haidt has shown  that liberals care about poverty  59 percent more than they care about economic liberty.    </seg>
<seg id="115"> And conservatives care about economic liberty  28 percent more than they care about poverty.    </seg>
<seg id="116"> Irreconcilable differences, right?    </seg>
<seg id="117"> We'll never come together. Wrong.    </seg>
<seg id="118"> That is diversity in which lies our strength.    </seg>
<seg id="119"> Remember what pulled up the poor.    </seg>
<seg id="120"> It was the obsession with poverty,  accompanied by the method of economic freedom  spreading around the world.    </seg>
<seg id="121"> We need each other, in other words,  if we want to help people and get the next two billion people out of poverty.    </seg>
<seg id="122"> There's no other way.    </seg>
<seg id="123"> How are we going to get that?    </seg>
<seg id="124"> It's a tricky thing, isn't it.    </seg>
<seg id="125"> We need innovative thinking.    </seg>
<seg id="126"> A lot of it's on this stage.    </seg>
<seg id="127"> Social entrepreneurship. Yeah. Absolutely. Phenomenal.    </seg>
<seg id="128"> We need investment overseas  in a sustainable, responsible, ethical and moral way. Yes. Yes.    </seg>
<seg id="129"> But you know what we really need?    </seg>
<seg id="130"> We need a new day in flexible ideology.    </seg>
<seg id="131"> We need to be less predictable.    </seg>
<seg id="132"> Don't we?    </seg>
<seg id="133"> Do you ever feel like your own ideology is starting to get predictable?    </seg>
<seg id="134"> Kinda conventional?    </seg>
<seg id="135"> Do you ever feel like you're always listening to people who agree with you?    </seg>
<seg id="136"> Why is that dangerous?    </seg>
<seg id="137"> Because when we talk in this country about economics,  on the right, conservatives,  you're always talking about taxes and regulations and big government.    </seg>
<seg id="138"> And on the left, liberals, you're talking about economics,  it's always about income inequality.    </seg>
<seg id="139"> Right? Now those are important things,  really important to me, really important to you.    </seg>
<seg id="140"> But when it comes to lifting people up  who are starving and need us today, those are distractions.    </seg>
<seg id="141"> We need to come together around the best ways  to mitigate poverty using the best tools at our disposal,  and that comes only when conservatives recognize that they need liberals  and their obsession with poverty,  and liberals need conservatives and their obsession with free markets.    </seg>
<seg id="142"> That's the diversity in which lies the future strength of this country,  if we choose to take it.    </seg>
<seg id="143"> So how are we going to do it? How are we going to do it together?    </seg>
<seg id="144"> I've got to have some action items, not just for you but for me.    </seg>
<seg id="145"> Number one. Action item number one:  remember, it's not good enough just to tolerate people who disagree.    </seg>
<seg id="146"> It's not good enough.    </seg>
<seg id="147"> We have to remember that we need people who disagree with us,  because there are people who need all of us  who are still waiting for these tools.    </seg>
<seg id="148"> Now, what are you going to do? How are you going to express that?    </seg>
<seg id="149"> Where does this start? It starts here.    </seg>
<seg id="150"> You know, all of us in this room, we're blessed.    </seg>
<seg id="151"> We're blessed with people who listen to us.    </seg>
<seg id="152"> We're blessed with prosperity. We're blessed with leadership.    </seg>
<seg id="153"> When people hear us, with the kind of unpredictable ideology,  then maybe people will listen.    </seg>
<seg id="154"> Maybe progress will start at that point.    </seg>
<seg id="155"> That's number one. Number two.    </seg>
<seg id="156"> Number two: I'm asking you and I'm asking me  to be the person specifically who blurs the lines,  who is ambiguous, who is hard to classify.    </seg>
<seg id="157"> If you're a conservative,  be the conservative who is always going on about poverty  and the moral obligation to be a warrior for the poor.    </seg>
<seg id="158"> And if you're a liberal, be a liberal who is always talking  about the beauty of free markets to solve our problems  when we use them responsibly.    </seg>
<seg id="159"> If we do that, we get two things.    </seg>
<seg id="160"> Number one: we get to start to work on the next two billion  and be the solution that we've seen so much of in the past  and we need to see more of in the future. That's what we get.    </seg>
<seg id="161"> And the second is that we might just be able  to take the ghastly holy war of ideology that we're suffering under in this country  and turn it into a competition of ideas  based on solidarity and mutual respect.    </seg>
<seg id="162"> And then maybe, just maybe,  we'll all realize that our big differences  aren't really that big after all.    </seg>
<seg id="163"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2458" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/tim_urban_inside_the_mind_of_a_master_procrastinator</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Tim Urban knows that procrastination doesn't make sense, but he's never been able to shake his habit of waiting until the last minute to get things done. In this hilarious and insightful talk, Urban takes us on a journey through YouTube binges, Wikipedia rabbit holes and bouts of staring out the window -- and encourages us to think harder about what we're really procrastinating on, before we run out of time.</description> 
<keywords>talks, Internet, brain, choice, comedy, decision-making, entertainment, goal-setting, humor, mind, online video, productivity, time, visualizations, work, writing</keywords> 
<talkid>2458</talkid> 
<title>Tim Urban: Inside the mind of a master procrastinator</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> So in college,  I was a government major,  which means I had to write a lot of papers.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> Now, when a normal student writes a paper,  they might spread the work out a little like this.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> So, you know --    you get started maybe a little slowly,  but you get enough done in the first week  that, with some heavier days later on,  everything gets done, things stay civil.    </seg>
<seg id="4">   And I would want to do that like that.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> That would be the plan. I would have it all ready to go,  but then, actually, the paper would come along,  and then I would kind of do this.    </seg>
<seg id="6">   And that would happen every single paper.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> But then came my 90-page senior thesis,  a paper you're supposed to spend a year on.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> And I knew for a paper like that, my normal work flow was not an option.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> So I planned things out,  and I decided I kind of had to go something like this.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> This is how the year would go.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> So I'd start off light,  and I'd bump it up in the middle months,  and then at the end, I would kick it up into high gear  just like a little staircase.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> How hard could it be to walk up the stairs?    </seg>
<seg id="13"> No big deal, right?    </seg>
<seg id="14"> But then, the funniest thing happened.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> Those first few months?    </seg>
<seg id="16"> They came and went, and I couldn't quite do stuff.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> So we had an awesome new revised plan.    </seg>
<seg id="18">   And then --    But then those middle months actually went by,  and I didn't really write words,  and so we were here.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> And then two months turned into one month,  which turned into two weeks.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> And one day I woke up  with three days until the deadline,  still not having written a word,  and so I did the only thing I could:  I wrote 90 pages over 72 hours,  pulling not one but two all-nighters --  humans are not supposed to pull two all-nighters --  sprinted across campus,  dove in slow motion,  and got it in just at the deadline.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> I thought that was the end of everything.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> But a week later I get a call,  and it's the school.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> And they say, "Is this Tim Urban?"    </seg>
<seg id="24"> And I say, "Yeah."    </seg>
<seg id="25"> And they say, "We need to talk about your thesis."    </seg>
<seg id="26"> And I say, "OK."    </seg>
<seg id="27"> And they say,  "It's the best one we've ever seen."    </seg>
<seg id="28">     That did not happen.    </seg>
<seg id="29">   It was a very, very bad thesis.    </seg>
<seg id="30">   I just wanted to enjoy that one moment when all of you thought,  "This guy is amazing!"    </seg>
<seg id="31">   No, no, it was very, very bad.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> Anyway, today I'm a writer-blogger guy.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> I write the blog Wait But Why.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> And a couple of years ago, I decided to write about procrastination.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> My behavior has always perplexed the non-procrastinators around me,  and I wanted to explain to the non-procrastinators of the world what goes on in the heads of procrastinators,  and why we are the way we are.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> Now, I had a hypothesis  that the brains of procrastinators were actually different  than the brains of other people.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> And to test this, I found an MRI lab  that actually let me scan both my brain  and the brain of a proven non-procrastinator, so I could compare them.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> I actually brought them here to show you today.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> I want you to take a look carefully to see if you can notice a difference.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> I know that if you're not a trained brain expert,  it's not that obvious, but just take a look, OK?    </seg>
<seg id="41"> So here's the brain of a non-procrastinator.    </seg>
<seg id="42">   Now ...    </seg>
<seg id="43"> here's my brain.    </seg>
<seg id="44">   There is a difference.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> Both brains have a Rational Decision-Maker in them,  but the procrastinator's brain  also has an Instant Gratification Monkey.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> Now, what does this mean for the procrastinator?    </seg>
<seg id="47"> Well, it means everything's fine until this happens.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> [This is a perfect time to get some work done.] [Nope!]  So the Rational Decision-Maker will make the rational decision  to do something productive,  but the Monkey doesn't like that plan,  so he actually takes the wheel,  and he says, "Actually, let's read the entire Wikipedia page  of the Nancy Kerrigan/ Tonya Harding scandal,  because I just remembered that that happened.    </seg>
<seg id="49">   Then --    Then we're going to go over to the fridge,  to see if there's anything new in there since 10 minutes ago.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> After that, we're going to go on a YouTube spiral  that starts with videos of Richard Feynman talking about magnets  and ends much, much later with us watching interviews  with Justin Bieber's mom.    </seg>
<seg id="51">   "All of that's going to take a while,  so we're not going to really have room on the schedule for any work today. Sorry!"    </seg>
<seg id="52"> Now, what is going on here?    </seg>
<seg id="53"> The Instant Gratification Monkey does not seem like a guy you want behind the wheel.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> He lives entirely in the present moment.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> He has no memory of the past, no knowledge of the future,  and he only cares about two things:  easy and fun.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> Now, in the animal world, that works fine.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> If you're a dog  and you spend your whole life doing nothing other than easy and fun things,  you're a huge success!    </seg>
<seg id="58">   And to the Monkey,  humans are just another animal species.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> You have to keep well-slept, well-fed and propagating into the next generation,  which in tribal times might have worked OK.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> But, if you haven't noticed, now we're not in tribal times.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> We're in an advanced civilization, and the Monkey does not know what that is.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> Which is why we have another guy in our brain,  the Rational Decision-Maker,  who gives us the ability to do things no other animal can do.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> We can visualize the future.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> We can see the big picture.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> We can make long-term plans.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> And he wants to take all of that into account.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> And he wants to just have us do whatever makes sense to be doing right now.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> Now, sometimes it makes sense to be doing things that are easy and fun,  like when you're having dinner or going to bed  or enjoying well-earned leisure time.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> That's why there's an overlap. Sometimes they agree.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> But other times, it makes much more sense  to be doing things that are harder and less pleasant,  for the sake of the big picture.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> And that's when we have a conflict.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> And for the procrastinator,  that conflict tends to end a certain way every time,  leaving him spending a lot of time in this orange zone,  an easy and fun place that's entirely out of the Makes Sense circle.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> I call it the Dark Playground.    </seg>
<seg id="74">   Now, the Dark Playground is a place  that all of you procrastinators out there know very well.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> It's where leisure activities happen  at times when leisure activities are not supposed to be happening.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> The fun you have in the Dark Playground  isn't actually fun, because it's completely unearned,  and the air is filled with guilt, dread, anxiety, self-hatred --  all of those good procrastinator feelings.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> And the question is, in this situation, with the Monkey behind the wheel,  how does the procrastinator ever get himself over here to this blue zone,  a less pleasant place, but where really important things happen?    </seg>
<seg id="78"> Well, turns out the procrastinator has a guardian angel,  someone who's always looking down on him and watching over him in his darkest moments --  someone called the Panic Monster.    </seg>
<seg id="79">   Now, the Panic Monster is dormant most of the time,  but he suddenly wakes up anytime a deadline gets too close  or there's danger of public embarrassment,  a career disaster or some other scary consequence.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> And importantly, he's the only thing the Monkey is terrified of.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> Now, he became very relevant in my life pretty recently,  because the people of TED reached out to me about six months ago  and invited me to do a TED Talk.    </seg>
<seg id="82">   Now, of course, I said yes.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> It's always been a dream of mine to have done a TED Talk in the past.    </seg>
<seg id="84">     But in the middle of all this excitement,  the Rational Decision-Maker seemed to have something else on his mind.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> He was saying, "Are we clear on what we just accepted?    </seg>
<seg id="86"> Do we get what's going to be now happening one day in the future?    </seg>
<seg id="87"> We need to sit down and work on this right now."    </seg>
<seg id="88"> And the Monkey said, "Totally agree, but let's just open Google Earth  and zoom in to the bottom of India, like 200 feet above the ground,  and scroll up for two and a half hours til we get to the top of the country,  so we can get a better feel for India."    </seg>
<seg id="89">   So that's what we did that day.    </seg>
<seg id="90">   As six months turned into four and then two and then one,  the people of TED decided to release the speakers.    </seg>
<seg id="91"> And I opened up the website, and there was my face  staring right back at me.    </seg>
<seg id="92"> And guess who woke up?    </seg>
<seg id="93">   So the Panic Monster starts losing his mind,  and a few seconds later, the whole system's in mayhem.    </seg>
<seg id="94">   And the Monkey -- remember, he's terrified of the Panic Monster --  boom, he's up the tree!    </seg>
<seg id="95"> And finally,  finally, the Rational Decision-Maker can take the wheel  and I can start working on the talk.    </seg>
<seg id="96"> Now, the Panic Monster explains  all kinds of pretty insane procrastinator behavior,  like how someone like me could spend two weeks  unable to start the opening sentence of a paper,  and then miraculously find the unbelievable work ethic  to stay up all night and write eight pages.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> And this entire situation, with the three characters --  this is the procrastinator's system.    </seg>
<seg id="98"> It's not pretty, but in the end, it works.    </seg>
<seg id="99"> This is what I decided to write about on the blog a couple of years ago.    </seg>
<seg id="100"> When I did, I was amazed by the response.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> Literally thousands of emails came in,  from all different kinds of people from all over the world,  doing all different kinds of things.    </seg>
<seg id="102"> These are people who were nurses, bankers, painters, engineers  and lots and lots of PhD students.    </seg>
<seg id="103">   And they were all writing, saying the same thing:  "I have this problem too."    </seg>
<seg id="104"> But what struck me was the contrast between the light tone of the post  and the heaviness of these emails.    </seg>
<seg id="105"> These people were writing with intense frustration  about what procrastination had done to their lives,  about what this Monkey had done to them.    </seg>
<seg id="106"> And I thought about this, and I said,  well, if the procrastinator's system works, then what's going on?    </seg>
<seg id="107"> Why are all of these people in such a dark place?    </seg>
<seg id="108"> Well, it turns out that there's two kinds of procrastination.    </seg>
<seg id="109"> Everything I've talked about today, the examples I've given,  they all have deadlines.    </seg>
<seg id="110"> And when there's deadlines,  the effects of procrastination are contained to the short term  because the Panic Monster gets involved.    </seg>
<seg id="111"> But there's a second kind of procrastination  that happens in situations when there is no deadline.    </seg>
<seg id="112"> So if you wanted a career where you're a self-starter --  something in the arts, something entrepreneurial --  there's no deadlines on those things at first, because nothing's happening,  not until you've gone out and done the hard work  to get momentum, get things going.    </seg>
<seg id="113"> There's also all kinds of important things outside of your career that don't involve any deadlines,  like seeing your family or exercising and taking care of your health,  working on your relationship or getting out of a relationship that isn't working.    </seg>
<seg id="114"> Now if the procrastinator's only mechanism of doing these hard things  is the Panic Monster, that's a problem,  because in all of these non-deadline situations,  the Panic Monster doesn't show up. He has nothing to wake up for,  so the effects of procrastination, they're not contained; they just extend outward forever.    </seg>
<seg id="115"> And it's this long-term kind of procrastination  that's much less visible and much less talked about  than the funnier, short-term deadline-based kind.    </seg>
<seg id="116"> It's usually suffered quietly and privately.    </seg>
<seg id="117"> And it can be the source  of a huge amount of long-term unhappiness, and regrets.    </seg>
<seg id="118"> And I thought, that's why those people are emailing,  and that's why they're in such a bad place.    </seg>
<seg id="119"> It's not that they're cramming for some project.    </seg>
<seg id="120"> It's that long-term procrastination has made them feel like a spectator,  at times, in their own lives.    </seg>
<seg id="121"> The frustration is not that they couldn't achieve their dreams;  it's that they weren't even able to start chasing them.    </seg>
<seg id="122"> So I read these emails and I had a little bit of an epiphany --  that I don't think non-procrastinators exist.    </seg>
<seg id="123"> That's right -- I think all of you are procrastinators.    </seg>
<seg id="124"> Now, you might not all be a mess,  like some of us,    and some of you may have a healthy relationship with deadlines,  but remember: the Monkey's sneakiest trick  is when the deadlines aren't there.    </seg>
<seg id="125"> Now, I want to show you one last thing.    </seg>
<seg id="126"> I call this a Life Calendar.    </seg>
<seg id="127"> That's one box for every week of a 90-year life.    </seg>
<seg id="128"> That's not that many boxes,  especially since we've already used a bunch of those.    </seg>
<seg id="129"> So I think we need to all take a long, hard look at that calendar.    </seg>
<seg id="130"> We need to think about what we're really procrastinating on,  because everyone is procrastinating on something in life.    </seg>
<seg id="131"> We need to stay aware of the Instant Gratification Monkey.    </seg>
<seg id="132"> That's a job for all of us.    </seg>
<seg id="133"> And because there's not that many boxes on there,  it's a job that should probably start today.    </seg>
<seg id="134"> Well, maybe not today, but ...    </seg>
<seg id="135">   You know.    </seg>
<seg id="136"> Sometime soon.    </seg>
<seg id="137"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2451" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/casey_gerald_the_gospel_of_doubt</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: What do you do when your firmly held beliefs turn out not to be true? When Casey Gerald's religion failed him, he searched for something new to believe in -- in business, in government, in philanthropy -- but found only false saviors. In this moving talk, Gerald urges us all to question our beliefs and embrace uncertainty.</description> 
<keywords>talks, God, big problems, business, capitalism, community, education, faith, inequality, social change, society</keywords> 
<talkid>2451</talkid> 
<title>Casey Gerald: The gospel of doubt</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> There we were,  souls and bodies packed into a Texas church  on the last night of our lives.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> Packed into a room just like this,  but with creaky wooden pews draped in worn-down red fabric,  with an organ to my left and a choir at my back  and a baptism pool built into the wall behind them.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> A room like this, nonetheless.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> With the same great feelings of suspense,  the same deep hopes for salvation,  the same sweat in the palms  and the same people in the back not paying attention.    </seg>
<seg id="5">   This was December 31, 1999,  the night of the Second Coming of Christ,  and the end of the world as I knew it.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> I had turned 12 that year  and had reached the age of accountability.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> And once I stopped complaining  about how unfair it was that Jesus would return  as soon as I had to be accountable for all that I had done,  I figured I had better get my house in order very quickly.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> So I went to church as often as I could.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> I listened for silence as anxiously as one might listen for noise,  trying to be sure that the Lord hadn't pulled a fast one on me  and decided to come back early.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> And just in case he did,  I built a backup plan,  by reading the "Left Behind" books that were all the rage at the time.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> And I found in their pages  that if I was not taken in the rapture at midnight,  I had another shot.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> All I had to do was avoid taking the mark of the beast,  fight off demons, plagues and the Antichrist himself.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> It would be hard --    but I knew I could do it.    </seg>
<seg id="14">   But planning time was over now.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> It was 11:50pm.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> We had 10 minutes left,  and my pastor called us out of the pews and down to the altar  because he wanted to be praying when midnight struck.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> So every faction of the congregation  took its place.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> The choir stayed in the choir stand,  the deacons and their wives --  or the Baptist Bourgeoisie as I like to call them --    took first position in front of the altar.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> You see, in America,  even the Second Coming of Christ has a VIP section.    </seg>
<seg id="20">     And right behind the Baptist Bourgeoisie  were the elderly --  these men and women whose young backs had been bent under hot suns  in the cotton fields of East Texas,  and whose skin seemed to be burnt a creaseless noble brown,  just like the clay of East Texas,  and whose hopes and dreams for what life might become  outside of East Texas  had sometimes been bent and broken    </seg>
<seg id="21"> even further than their backs.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> Yes, these men and women were the stars of the show for me.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> They had waited their whole lives for this moment,  just as their medieval predecessors had longed for the end of the world,  and just as my grandmother waited for the Oprah Winfrey Show  to come on Channel 8 every day at 4 o'clock.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> And as she made her way to the altar,  I snuck right in behind her,  because I knew for sure  that my grandmother was going to heaven.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> And I thought that if I held on to her hand during this prayer,  I might go right on with her.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> So I held on  and I closed my eyes  to listen,  to wait.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> And the prayers got louder.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> And the shouts of response to the call of the prayer  went up higher even still.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> And the organ rolled on in to add the dirge.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> And the heat came on to add to the sweat.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> And my hand gripped firmer,  so I wouldn't be the one left in the field.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> My eyes clenched tighter  so I wouldn't see the wheat being separated from the chaff.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> And then a voice rang out above us:  "Amen."    </seg>
<seg id="34"> It was over.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> I looked at the clock.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> It was after midnight.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> I looked at the elder believers  whose savior had not come,  who were too proud to show any signs of disappointment,  who had believed too much and for too long  to start doubting now.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> But I was upset on their behalf.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> They had been duped,  hoodwinked, bamboozled,  and I had gone right along with them.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> I had prayed their prayers,  I had yielded not to temptation as best I could.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> I had dipped my head not once, but twice  in that snot-inducing baptism pool.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> I had believed.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> Now what?    </seg>
<seg id="44"> I got home just in time to turn on the television  and watch Peter Jennings announce the new millennium  as it rolled in around the world.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> It struck me that it would have been strange anyway,  for Jesus to come back again and again  based on the different time zones.    </seg>
<seg id="46">   And this made me feel even more ridiculous --  hurt, really.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> But there on that night, I did not stop believing.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> I just believed a new thing:  that it was possible not to believe.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> It was possible the answers I had were wrong,  that the questions themselves were wrong.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> And now, where there was once a mountain of certitude,  there was, running right down to its foundation,  a spring of doubt,  a spring that promised rivers.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> I can trace the whole drama of my life  back to that night in that church  when my savior did not come for me;  when the thing I believed most certainly  turned out to be, if not a lie,  then not quite the truth.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> And even though most of you prepared for Y2K in a very different way,  I'm convinced that you are here  because some part of you has done the same thing that I have done  since the dawn of this new century,  since my mother left and my father stayed away  and my Lord refused to come.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> And I held out my hand,  reaching for something to believe in.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> I held on when I arrived at Yale at 18,  with the faith that my journey from Oak Cliff, Texas  was a chance to leave behind all the challenges I had known,  the broken dreams and broken bodies I had seen.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> But when I found myself back home one winter break,  with my face planted in the floor,  my hands tied behind my back  and a burglar's gun pressed to my head,  I knew that even the best education couldn't save me.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> I held on when I showed up at Lehman Brothers  as an intern in 2008.    </seg>
<seg id="57">   So hopeful --    that I called home to inform my family  that we'd never be poor again.    </seg>
<seg id="58">   But as I witnessed this temple of finance  come crashing down before my eyes,  I knew that even the best job couldn't save me.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> I held on when I showed up in Washington DC as a young staffer,  who had heard a voice call out from Illinois,  saying, "It's been a long time coming,  but in this election, change has come to America."    </seg>
<seg id="60"> But as the Congress ground to a halt and the country ripped at the seams  and hope and change began to feel like a cruel joke,  I knew that even the political second coming  could not save me.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> I had knelt faithfully at the altar of the American Dream,  praying to the gods of my time  of success,  and money,  and power.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> But over and over again,  midnight struck, and I opened my eyes  to see that all of these gods were dead.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> And from that graveyard, I began the search once more,  not because I was brave,  but because I knew that I would either believe  or I would die.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> So I took a pilgrimage to yet another mecca,  Harvard Business School --    this time, knowing that I could not simply accept the salvation  that it claimed to offer.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> No, I knew there'd be more work to do.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> The work began in the dark corner of a crowded party,  in the late night of an early, miserable Cambridge winter,  when three friends and I asked a question  that young folks searching for something real have asked  for a very long time:  "What if we took a road trip?"    </seg>
<seg id="67">   We didn't know where'd we go or how we'd get there,  but we knew we had to do it.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> Because all our lives we yearned, as Jack Kerouac wrote,  to "sneak out into the night and disappear somewhere,"  and go find out what everybody was doing  all over the country.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> So even though there were other voices who said  that the risk was too great and the proof too thin,  we went on anyhow.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> We went on 8,000 miles across America in the summer of 2013,  through the cow pastures of Montana, through the desolation of Detroit,  through the swamps of New Orleans,  where we found and worked with men and women  who were building small businesses  that made purpose their bottom line.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> And having been trained at the West Point of capitalism,  this struck us as a revolutionary idea.    </seg>
<seg id="72">   And this idea spread,  growing into a nonprofit called MBAs Across America,  a movement that landed me here on this stage today.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> It spread because we found a great hunger in our generation  for purpose, for meaning.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> It spread because we found countless entrepreneurs  in the nooks and crannies of America  who were creating jobs and changing lives  and who needed a little help.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> But if I'm being honest, it also spread  because I fought to spread it.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> There was no length to which I would not go to preach this gospel,  to get more people to believe  that we could bind the wounds of a broken country,  one social business at a time.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> But it was this journey of evangelism  that led me to the rather different gospel  that I've come to share with you today.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> It began one evening almost a year ago  at the Museum of Natural History in New York City,  at a gala for alumni of Harvard Business School.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> Under a full-size replica of a whale,  I sat with the titans of our time  as they celebrated their peers and their good deeds.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> There was pride in a room  where net worth and assets under management  surpassed half a trillion dollars.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> We looked over all that we had made,  and it was good.    </seg>
<seg id="82">   But it just so happened, two days later,  I had to travel up the road to Harlem,  where I found myself sitting in an urban farm  that had once been a vacant lot,  listening to a man named Tony tell me of the kids  that showed up there every day.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> All of them lived below the poverty line.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> Many of them carried all of their belongings in a backpack  to avoid losing them in a homeless shelter.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> Some of them came to Tony's program,  called Harlem Grown,  to get the only meal they had each day.    </seg>
<seg id="86"> Tony told me that he started Harlem Grown with money from his pension,  after 20 years as a cab driver.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> He told me that he didn't give himself a salary,  because despite success, the program struggled for resources.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> He told me that he would take any help  that he could get.    </seg>
<seg id="89"> And I was there as that help.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> But as I left Tony, I felt the sting and salt of tears  welling up in my eyes.    </seg>
<seg id="91"> I felt the weight of revelation  that I could sit in one room on one night,  where a few hundred people had half a trillion dollars,  and another room, two days later,  just 50 blocks up the road,  where a man was going without a salary  to get a child her only meal of the day.    </seg>
<seg id="92"> And it wasn't the glaring inequality that made me want to cry,  it wasn't the thought of hungry, homeless kids,  it wasn't rage toward the one percent  or pity toward the 99.    </seg>
<seg id="93"> No, I was disturbed because I had finally realized  that I was the dialysis  for a country that needed a kidney transplant.    </seg>
<seg id="94"> I realized that my story stood in for all those  who were expected to pick themselves up by their bootstraps,  even if they didn't have any boots;  that my organization stood in  for all the structural, systemic help that never went to Harlem  or Appalachia or the Lower 9th Ward;  that my voice stood in for all those voices  that seemed too unlearned, too unwashed, too unaccommodated.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> And the shame of that,  that shame washed over me  like the shame of sitting in front of the television,  watching Peter Jennings announce the new millennium  again  and again  and again.    </seg>
<seg id="96"> I had been duped,  hoodwinked,  bamboozled.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> But this time, the false savior was me.    </seg>
<seg id="98"> You see, I've come a long way from that altar  on the night I thought the world would end,  from a world where people spoke in tongues  and saw suffering as a necessary act of God  and took a text to be infallible truth.    </seg>
<seg id="99"> Yes, I've come so far  that I'm right back where I started.    </seg>
<seg id="100"> Because it simply is not true to say  that we live in an age of disbelief --  no, we believe today just as much as any time that came before.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> Some of us may believe in the prophecy of Brené Brown  or Tony Robbins.    </seg>
<seg id="102"> We may believe in the bible of The New Yorker  or the Harvard Business Review.    </seg>
<seg id="103"> We may believe most deeply  when we worship right here at the church of TED,  but we desperately want to believe,  we need to believe.    </seg>
<seg id="104"> We speak in the tongues of charismatic leaders  that promise to solve all our problems.    </seg>
<seg id="105"> We see suffering as a necessary act of the capitalism that is our god,  we take the text of technological progress  to be infallible truth.    </seg>
<seg id="106"> And we hardly realize the human price we pay  when we fail to question one brick,  because we fear it might shake our whole foundation.    </seg>
<seg id="107"> But if you are disturbed  by the unconscionable things that we have come to accept,  then it must be questioning time.    </seg>
<seg id="108"> So I have not a gospel of disruption or innovation  or a triple bottom line.    </seg>
<seg id="109"> I do not have a gospel of faith to share with you today, in fact.    </seg>
<seg id="110"> I have and I offer a gospel of doubt.    </seg>
<seg id="111"> The gospel of doubt does not ask that you stop believing,  it asks that you believe a new thing:  that it is possible not to believe.    </seg>
<seg id="112"> It is possible the answers we have are wrong,  it is possible the questions themselves are wrong.    </seg>
<seg id="113"> Yes, the gospel of doubt means that it is possible that we,  on this stage, in this room,  are wrong.    </seg>
<seg id="114"> Because it raises the question, "Why?"    </seg>
<seg id="115"> With all the power that we hold in our hands,  why are people still suffering so bad?    </seg>
<seg id="116"> This doubt leads me to share that we are putting my organization,  MBAs Across America,  out of business.    </seg>
<seg id="117"> We have shed our staff and closed our doors  and we will share our model freely  with anyone who sees their power to do this work  without waiting for our permission.    </seg>
<seg id="118"> This doubt compels me  to renounce the role of savior that some have placed on me,  because our time is too short and our odds are too long  to wait for second comings,  when the truth is that there will be no miracles here.    </seg>
<seg id="119"> And this doubt, it fuels me,  it gives me hope  that when our troubles overwhelm us,  when the paths laid out for us seem to lead to our demise,  when our healers bring no comfort to our wounds,  it will not be our blind faith --  no, it will be our humble doubt  that shines a little light into the darkness of our lives  and of our world  and lets us raise our voice to whisper    </seg>
<seg id="120"> or to shout  or to say simply,  very simply,  "There must be another way."    </seg>
<seg id="121"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2432" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/caleb_harper_this_computer_will_grow_your_food_in_the_future</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: What if we could grow delicious, nutrient-dense food, indoors anywhere in the world? Caleb Harper, director of the Open Agriculture Initiative at the MIT Media Lab, wants to change the food system by connecting growers with technology. Get to know Harper's "food computers" and catch a glimpse of what the future of farming might look like.</description> 
<keywords>talks, Vaccines, agriculture, biomechanics, biotech, botany, chemistry, climate change, collaboration, data, design, ebola, ecology, education, engineering, environment, food, future, garden, green, innovation, nature, open-source, potential, science, software, sustainability, technology, virus, water</keywords> 
<talkid>2432</talkid> 
<title>Caleb Harper: This computer will grow your food in the future</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> Food crisis.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> It's in the news every day.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> But what is it?    </seg>
<seg id="4"> Some places in the world it's too little food,  maybe too much.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> Other places, GMO is saving the world.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> Maybe GMO is the problem?    </seg>
<seg id="7"> Too much agricultural runoff creating bad oceans, toxic oceans,  attenuation of nutrition.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> They go on and on.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> And I find the current climate of this discussion  incredibly disempowering.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> So how do we bring that to something that we understand?    </seg>
<seg id="11"> How is this apple food crisis?    </seg>
<seg id="12"> You've all eaten an apple in the last week, I'm sure.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> How old do you think it was from when it was picked?    </seg>
<seg id="14"> Two weeks?    </seg>
<seg id="15"> Two months?    </seg>
<seg id="16"> Eleven months --  the average age of an apple in a grocery store in the United States.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> And I don't expect it to be much different in Europe  or anywhere else in the world.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> We pick them,  we put them in cold storage,  we gas the cold storage --  there's actually documented proof  of workers trying to go into these environments  to retrieve an apple,  and dying,  because the atmosphere  that they slow down the process of the apple with is also toxic to humans.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> How is it that none of you knew this?    </seg>
<seg id="20"> Why didn't I know this?    </seg>
<seg id="21"> Ninety percent of the quality of that apple --  all of the antioxidants -- are gone by the time we get it.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> It's basically a little ball of sugar.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> How did we get so information poor  and how can we do better?    </seg>
<seg id="24"> I think what's missing is a platform.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> I know platforms -- I know computers,  they put me on the Internet when I was young.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> I did very weird things --  on this platform.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> But I met people, and I could express myself.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> How do you express yourself in food?    </seg>
<seg id="29"> If we had a platform,  we might feel empowered to question: What if?    </seg>
<seg id="30"> For me, I questioned:  What if climate was democratic?    </seg>
<seg id="31"> So, this is a map of climate in the world.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> The most productive areas in green, the least productive in red.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> They shift and they change,  and Californian farmers now become Mexican farmers.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> China picks up land in Brazil to grow better food,  and we're a slave to climate.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> What if each country had its own productive climate?    </seg>
<seg id="36"> What would that change about how we live?    </seg>
<seg id="37"> What would that change about quality of life and nutrition?    </seg>
<seg id="38"> The last generation's problem was, we need more food  and we need it cheap.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> Welcome to your global farm.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> We built a huge analog farm.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> All these traces --  these are cars, planes, trains and automobiles.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> It's a miracle that we feed seven billion people  with just a few of us involved in the production of food.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> What if ...    </seg>
<seg id="44"> we built a digital farm?    </seg>
<seg id="45"> A digital world farm.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> What if you could take this apple,  digitize it somehow,  send it through particles in the air  and reconstitute it on the other side?    </seg>
<seg id="47"> What if?    </seg>
<seg id="48"> Going through some of these quotes,  you know, they inspire me to do what I do.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> First one:  ["Japanese farming has no youth, no water, no land and no future."]  That's what I landed to the day that I went to Minamisanriku,  one stop south of Fukushima,  after the disaster.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> The kids have headed to Sendai and Tokyo,  the land is contaminated,  they already import 70 percent of their own food.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> But it's not unique to Japan.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> Two percent of the American population is involved in farming.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> What good answer comes from two percent of any population?    </seg>
<seg id="54"> As we go around the world,  50 percent of the African population is under 18.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> Eighty percent don't want to be farmers.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> Farming is hard.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> The life of a small-shareholder farmer is miserable.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> They go into the city.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> In India:  farmers' families not being able to have basic access to utilities,  more farmer suicides this year and the previous 10 before that.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> It's uncomfortable to talk about.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> Where are they going?    </seg>
<seg id="62"> Into the city.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> No young people, and everyone's headed in.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> So how do we build this platform that inspires the youth?    </seg>
<seg id="65"> Welcome to the new tractor.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> This is my combine.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> A number of years ago now,  I went to Bed Bath and Beyond and Home Depot  and I started hacking.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> And I built silly things  and I made plants dance  and I attached them to my computer  and I killed them all --  a lot.    </seg>
<seg id="69">   I eventually got them to survive.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> And I created one of the most intimate relationships  I've ever had in my life,  because I was learning the language of plants.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> I wanted to make it bigger.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> They said, "Knock yourself out, kid!    </seg>
<seg id="73"> Here's an old electronics room that nobody wants.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> What can you do?"    </seg>
<seg id="75"> With my team, we built a farm inside of the media lab,  a place historically known not for anything about biology  but everything about digital life.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> Inside of these 60 square feet,  we produced enough food to feed about 300 people once a month --  not a lot of food.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> And there's a lot of interesting technology in there.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> But the most interesting thing?    </seg>
<seg id="79"> Beautiful, white roots,  deep, green colors  and a monthly harvest.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> Is this a new cafeteria?    </seg>
<seg id="81"> Is this a new retail experience?    </seg>
<seg id="82"> Is this a new grocery store?    </seg>
<seg id="83"> I can tell you one thing for sure:  this is the first time  anybody in the media lab ripped the roots off of anything.    </seg>
<seg id="84">   We get our salad in bags;  there's nothing wrong with that.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> But what happens  when you have an image-based processing expert,  a data scientist,  a roboticist,  ripping roots off and thinking,  "Huh. I know something about --  I could make this happen, I want to try."    </seg>
<seg id="86"> In that process we would bring the plants out  and we would take some back to the lab,  because if you grew it, you don't throw it away;  it's kind of precious to you.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> I have this weird tongue now,  because I'm afraid to let anybody eat anything until I've eaten it first,  because I want it to be good.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> So I eat lettuce every day  and I can tell the pH of a lettuce within .1.    </seg>
<seg id="89">   I'm like, "No, that's 6.1 -- no, no, you can't eat it today."    </seg>
<seg id="90">   This lettuce that day was hyper sweet.    </seg>
<seg id="91"> It was hyper sweet because the plant had been stressed  and it created a chemical reaction in the plant to protect itself:  "I'm not going to die!"    </seg>
<seg id="92"> And the plants not-going-to-die, taste sweet to me.    </seg>
<seg id="93"> Technologists falling backwards into plant physiology.    </seg>
<seg id="94"> So we thought other people needed to be able to try this.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> We want to see what people can create,  so we conceived of a lab that could be shipped anywhere.    </seg>
<seg id="96"> And then we built it.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> So on the facade of the media lab is my lab,  that has about 30 points of sensing per plant.    </seg>
<seg id="98"> If you know about the genome or genetics,  this is the phenome, right?    </seg>
<seg id="99"> The phenomena.    </seg>
<seg id="100"> When you say, "I like the strawberries from Mexico,"  you really like the strawberries from the climate  that produced the expression that you like.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> So if you're coding climate --  this much CO2, this much O2 creates a recipe -- you're coding  the expression of that plant, the nutrition of that plant,  the size of that plant, the shape, the color, the texture.    </seg>
<seg id="102"> We need data,  so we put a bunch of sensors in there  to tell us what's going on.    </seg>
<seg id="103"> If you think of your houseplants,  and you look at your houseplant  and you're super sad, because you're like,  "Why are you dying? Won't you talk to me?"    </seg>
<seg id="104">   Farmers develop the most beautiful fortune-telling eyes  by the time they're in their late 60s and 70s.    </seg>
<seg id="105"> They can tell you when you see that plant dying  that it's a nitrogen deficiency, a calcium deficiency  or it needs more humidity.    </seg>
<seg id="106"> Those beautiful eyes are not being passed down.    </seg>
<seg id="107"> These are eyes in the cloud of a farmer.    </seg>
<seg id="108"> We trend those data points over time.    </seg>
<seg id="109"> We correlate those data points to individual plants.    </seg>
<seg id="110"> These are all the broccoli in my lab that day, by IP address.    </seg>
<seg id="111">   We have IP-addressable broccoli.    </seg>
<seg id="112">   So if that's not weird enough,  you can click one and you get a plant profile.    </seg>
<seg id="113"> And what this tells you is downloadable progress on that plant,  but not like you'd think,  it's not just when it's ready.    </seg>
<seg id="114"> When does it achieve the nutrition that I need?    </seg>
<seg id="115"> When does it achieve the taste that I desire?    </seg>
<seg id="116"> Is it getting too much water?    </seg>
<seg id="117"> Is it getting too much sun?    </seg>
<seg id="118"> Alerts.    </seg>
<seg id="119"> It can talk to me, it's conversant,  we have a language.    </seg>
<seg id="120">     I think of that as the first user on the plant Facebook, right?    </seg>
<seg id="121"> That's a plant profile  and that plant will start making friends.    </seg>
<seg id="122">   And I mean it -- it will make friends with other plants  that use less nitrogen, more phosphorus,  less potassium.    </seg>
<seg id="123"> We're going to learn about a complexity  that we can only guess at now.    </seg>
<seg id="124"> And they may not friend us back -- I don't know, they might friend us back,  it depends on how we act.    </seg>
<seg id="125"> So this is my lab now.    </seg>
<seg id="126"> It's a little bit more systematized,  my background is designing data centers in hospitals of all things,  so I know a little bit about creating a controlled environment.    </seg>
<seg id="127"> And so --  inside of this environment,  we're experimenting with all kinds of things.    </seg>
<seg id="128"> This process, aeroponics, was developed by NASA for Mir Space Station  for reducing the amount of water they send into space.    </seg>
<seg id="129"> What it really does is give the plant exactly what it wants:  water, minerals and oxygen.    </seg>
<seg id="130"> Roots are not that complicated,  so when you give them that, you get this amazing expression.    </seg>
<seg id="131"> It's like the plant has two hearts.    </seg>
<seg id="132"> And because it has two hearts,  it grows four or five times faster.    </seg>
<seg id="133"> It's a perfect world.    </seg>
<seg id="134"> We've gone a long way into technology and seed for an adverse world  and we're going to continue to do that,  but we're going to have a new tool, too,  which is perfect world.    </seg>
<seg id="135"> So we've grown all kinds of things.    </seg>
<seg id="136"> These tomatoes hadn't been in commercial production for 150 years.    </seg>
<seg id="137"> Do you know that we have rare and ancient seed banks?    </seg>
<seg id="138"> Banks of seed.    </seg>
<seg id="139"> It's amazing.    </seg>
<seg id="140"> They have germplasm alive and things that you've never eaten.    </seg>
<seg id="141"> I am the only person in this room that's eaten that kind of tomato.    </seg>
<seg id="142"> Problem is it was a sauce tomato and we don't know how to cook,  so we ate a sauce tomato, which is not that great.    </seg>
<seg id="143"> But we've done things with protein -- we've grown all kinds of things.    </seg>
<seg id="144"> We've grown humans --    Well maybe you could, but we didn't.    </seg>
<seg id="145"> But what we realized is,  the tool was too big, it was too expensive.    </seg>
<seg id="146"> I was starting to put them around the world  and they were about 100,000 dollars.    </seg>
<seg id="147"> Finding somebody with 100 grand in their back pocket isn't easy,  so we wanted to make a small one.    </seg>
<seg id="148"> This project was actually one of my student's --  mechanical engineering undergraduate, Camille.    </seg>
<seg id="149"> So Camille and I and my team,  we iterated all summer,  how to make it cheaper, how to make it work better,  how to make it so other people can make it.    </seg>
<seg id="150"> Then we dropped them off in schools, seventh through eleventh grade.    </seg>
<seg id="151"> And if you want to be humbled, try to teach a kid something.    </seg>
<seg id="152"> So I went into this school and I said,  "Set it to 65 percent humidity."    </seg>
<seg id="153"> The seventh grader said, "What's humidity?"    </seg>
<seg id="154"> And I said, "Oh, it's water in air."    </seg>
<seg id="155"> He said, "There's no water in air, you're an idiot."    </seg>
<seg id="156">   And I was like, "Alright, don't trust me.    </seg>
<seg id="157"> Actually -- don't trust me, right?    </seg>
<seg id="158"> Set it to 100.    </seg>
<seg id="159"> He sets it to 100 and what happens?    </seg>
<seg id="160"> It starts to condense, make a fog and eventually drip.    </seg>
<seg id="161"> And he says, "Oh. Humidity is rain.    </seg>
<seg id="162"> Why didn't you just tell me that?"    </seg>
<seg id="163">   We've created an interface for this that's much like a game.    </seg>
<seg id="164"> They have a 3D environment,  they can log into it anywhere in the world  on their smartphone, on their tablet.    </seg>
<seg id="165"> They have different parts of the bots -- the physical, the sensors.    </seg>
<seg id="166"> They select recipes that have been created by other kids  anywhere in the world.    </seg>
<seg id="167"> They select and activate that recipe, they plant a seedling.    </seg>
<seg id="168"> While it's growing, they make changes.    </seg>
<seg id="169"> They're like, "Why does a plant need CO2 anyway? Isn't CO2 bad?    </seg>
<seg id="170"> It kills people."    </seg>
<seg id="171"> Crank up CO2, plant dies.    </seg>
<seg id="172"> Or crank down CO2, plant does very well.    </seg>
<seg id="173"> Harvest plant,  and you've created a new digital recipe.    </seg>
<seg id="174"> It's an iterative design and development  and exploration process.    </seg>
<seg id="175"> They can download, then,  all of the data about that new plant that they developed  or the new digital recipe and what did it do --  was it better or was it worse?    </seg>
<seg id="176"> Imagine these as little cores of processing.    </seg>
<seg id="177"> We're going to learn so much.    </seg>
<seg id="178"> Here's one of the food computers, as we call them,  in a school in three weeks' time.    </seg>
<seg id="179"> This is three weeks of growth.    </seg>
<seg id="180"> But more importantly,  it was the first time that this kid ever thought he could be a farmer --  or that he would want to be a farmer.    </seg>
<seg id="181"> So, we've open-sourced all of this.    </seg>
<seg id="182"> It's all online; go home, try to build your first food computer.    </seg>
<seg id="183"> It's going to be difficult -- I'm just telling you.    </seg>
<seg id="184"> We're in the beginning, but it's all there.    </seg>
<seg id="185"> It's very important to me that this is easily accessible.    </seg>
<seg id="186"> We're going to keep making it more so.    </seg>
<seg id="187"> These are farmers,  electrical engineer, mechanical engineer,  environmental engineer, computer scientist,  plant scientist, economist, urban planners.    </seg>
<seg id="188"> On one platform, doing what they're good at.    </seg>
<seg id="189"> But we got a little too big.    </seg>
<seg id="190"> This is my new facility that I'm just starting.    </seg>
<seg id="191"> This warehouse could be anywhere.    </seg>
<seg id="192"> That's why I chose it.    </seg>
<seg id="193"> And inside of this warehouse  we're going to build something kind of like this.    </seg>
<seg id="194"> These exist right now.    </seg>
<seg id="195"> Take a look at it.    </seg>
<seg id="196"> These exist, too.    </seg>
<seg id="197"> One grows greens,  one grows Ebola vaccine.    </seg>
<seg id="198"> Pretty amazing that plants and this DARPA Grand Challenge winner  is one of the reasons we're getting ahead of Ebola.    </seg>
<seg id="199"> The plants are producing the protein that's Ebola resistant.    </seg>
<seg id="200"> So pharmaceuticals, nutraceuticals,  all they way down to lettuce.    </seg>
<seg id="201"> But these two things look nothing alike,  and that's where I am with my field.    </seg>
<seg id="202"> Everything is different.    </seg>
<seg id="203"> We're in that weird "We're alright" stage  and it's like, "Here's my black box --"  "No, buy mine."    </seg>
<seg id="204"> "No, no, no -- I've got intellectual property that's totally valuable.    </seg>
<seg id="205"> Don't buy his, buy mine."    </seg>
<seg id="206"> And the reality is, we're just at the beginning,  in a time when society is shifting, too.    </seg>
<seg id="207"> When we ask for more, cheaper food,  we're now asking for better, environmentally friendly food.    </seg>
<seg id="208"> And when you have McDonald's advertising what's in the Chicken McNugget,  the most mysterious food item of all time --  they are now basing their marketing plan on that --  everything is changing.    </seg>
<seg id="209"> So into the world now.    </seg>
<seg id="210"> Personal food computers,  food servers  and food data centers  run on the open phenome.    </seg>
<seg id="211"> Think open genome, but we're going to put little climate recipes,  like Wikipedia,  that you can pull down, actuate and grow.    </seg>
<seg id="212"> What does this look like in a world?    </seg>
<seg id="213"> You remember the world connected by strings?    </seg>
<seg id="214"> We start having beacons.    </seg>
<seg id="215"> We start sending information about food,  rather than sending food.    </seg>
<seg id="216"> This is not just my fantasy,  this is where we're already deploying.    </seg>
<seg id="217"> Food computers, food servers,  soon-to-be food data centers,  connecting people together to share information.    </seg>
<seg id="218"> The future of food is not about fighting over what's wrong with this.    </seg>
<seg id="219"> We know what's wrong with this.    </seg>
<seg id="220"> The future of food is about networking the next one billion farmers  and empowering them with a platform  to ask and answer the question,  "What if?"    </seg>
<seg id="221"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2449" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/alexander_betts_our_refugee_system_is_failing_here_s_how_we_can_fix_it</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: A million refugees arrived in Europe this year, says Alexander Betts, and "our response, frankly, has been pathetic." Betts studies forced migration, the impossible choice for families between the camps, urban poverty and dangerous illegal journeys to safety. In this insightful talk, he offers four ways to change the way we treat refugees, so they can make an immediate contribution to their new homes. "There's nothing inevitable about refugees being a cost," Betts says. "They're human beings with skills, talents, aspirations, with the ability to make contributions -- if we let them."</description> 
<keywords>talks, Europe, Middle East, big problems, disaster relief, economics, failure, fear, future, global issues, government, policy, politics, potential, refugees, security, social change</keywords> 
<talkid>2449</talkid> 
<title>Alexander Betts: Our refugee system is failing. Here's how we can fix it</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> There are times when I feel really quite ashamed  to be a European.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> In the last year,  more than a million people arrived in Europe in need of our help,  and our response, frankly, has been pathetic.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> There are just so many contradictions.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> We mourn the tragic death  of two-year-old Alan Kurdi,  and yet, since then, more than 200 children  have subsequently drowned in the Mediterranean.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> We have international treaties  that recognize that refugees are a shared responsibility,  and yet we accept that tiny Lebanon  hosts more Syrians than the whole of Europe combined.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> We lament the existence of human smugglers,  and yet we make that the only viable route  to seek asylum in Europe.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> We have labor shortages,  and yet we exclude people who fit our economic and demographic needs  from coming to Europe.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> We proclaim our liberal values in opposition to fundamentalist Islam,  and yet --  we have repressive policies  that detain child asylum seekers,  that separate children from their families,  and that seize property from refugees.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> What are we doing?    </seg>
<seg id="10"> How has the situation come to this,  that we've adopted such an inhumane response to a humanitarian crisis?    </seg>
<seg id="11"> I don't believe it's because people don't care,  or at least I don't want to believe it's because people don't care.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> I believe it's because our politicians lack a vision,  a vision for how to adapt an international refugee system  created over 50 years ago  for a changing and globalized world.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> And so what I want to do is take a step back  and ask two really fundamental questions,  the two questions we all need to ask.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> First, why is the current system not working?    </seg>
<seg id="15"> And second, what can we do to fix it?    </seg>
<seg id="16"> So the modern refugee regime  was created in the aftermath of the Second World War by these guys.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> Its basic aim is to ensure  that when a state fails, or worse, turns against its own people,  people have somewhere to go,  to live in safety and dignity until they can go home.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> It was created precisely for situations like the situation we see in Syria today.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> Through an international convention signed by 147 governments,  the 1951 Convention on the Status of Refugees,  and an international organization, UNHCR,  states committed to reciprocally admit people onto their territory  who flee conflict and persecution.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> But today, that system is failing.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> In theory, refugees have a right to seek asylum.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> In practice, our immigration policies block the path to safety.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> In theory, refugees have a right to a pathway to integration,  or return to the country they've come from.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> But in practice, they get stuck in almost indefinite limbo.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> In theory, refugees are a shared global responsibility.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> In practice, geography means that countries proximate the conflict  take the overwhelming majority of the world's refugees.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> The system isn't broken because the rules are wrong.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> It's that we're not applying them adequately to a changing world,  and that's what we need to reconsider.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> So I want to explain to you a little bit about how the current system works.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> How does the refugee regime actually work?    </seg>
<seg id="31"> But not from a top-down institutional perspective,  rather from the perspective of a refugee.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> So imagine a Syrian woman.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> Let's call her Amira.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> And Amira to me represents many of the people I've met in the region.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> Amira, like around 25 percent of the world's refugees,  is a woman with children,  and she can't go home because she comes from this city  that you see before you, Homs,  a once beautiful and historic city  now under rubble.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> And so Amira can't go back there.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> But Amira also has no hope of resettlement to a third country,  because that's a lottery ticket  only available to less than one percent of the world's refugees.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> So Amira and her family  face an almost impossible choice.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> They have three basic options.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> The first option is that Amira can take her family to a camp.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> In the camp, she might get assistance,  but there are very few prospects for Amira and her family.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> Camps are in bleak, arid locations,  often in the desert.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> In the Zaatari refugee camp in Jordan,  you can hear the shells across the border in Syria at nighttime.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> There's restricted economic activity.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> Education is often of poor quality.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> And around the world,  some 80 percent of refugees who are in camps  have to stay for at least five years.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> It's a miserable existence,  and that's probably why, in reality,  only nine percent of Syrians choose that option.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> Alternatively, Amira can head to an urban area  in a neighboring country, like Amman or Beirut.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> That's an option that about 75 percent of Syrian refugees have taken.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> But there, there's great difficulty as well.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> Refugees in such urban areas don't usually have the right to work.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> They don't usually get significant access to assistance.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> And so when Amira and her family have used up their basic savings,  they're left with very little and likely to face urban destitution.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> So there's a third alternative,  and it's one that increasing numbers of Syrians are taking.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> Amira can seek some hope for her family  by risking their lives on a dangerous and perilous journey  to another country,  and it's that which we're seeing in Europe today.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> Around the world, we present refugees with an almost impossible choice  between three options:  encampment, urban destitution and dangerous journeys.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> For refugees, that choice is the global refugee regime today.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> But I think it's a false choice.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> I think we can reconsider that choice.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> The reason why we limit those options  is because we think  that those are the only options that are available to refugees,  and they're not.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> Politicians frame the issue as a zero-sum issue,  that if we benefit refugees, we're imposing costs on citizens.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> We tend to have a collective assumption  that refugees are an inevitable cost or burden to society.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> But they don't have to. They can contribute.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> So what I want to argue  is there are ways in which we can expand that choice set  and still benefit everyone else:  the host states and communities,  our societies and refugees themselves.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> And I want to suggest four ways  we can transform the paradigm of how we think about refugees.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> All four ways have one thing in common:  they're all ways in which we take the opportunities of globalization,  mobility and markets,  and update the way we think about the refugee issue.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> The first one I want to think about  is the idea of enabling environments,  and it starts from a very basic recognition  that refugees are human beings like everyone else,  but they're just in extraordinary circumstances.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> Together with my colleagues in Oxford,  we've embarked on a research project in Uganda  looking at the economic lives of refugees.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> We chose Uganda not because it's representative of all host countries.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> It's not. It's exceptional.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> Unlike most host countries around the world,  what Uganda has done  is give refugees economic opportunity.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> It gives them the right to work. It gives them freedom of movement.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> And the results of that are extraordinary  both for refugees and the host community.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> In the capital city, Kampala,  we found that 21 percent of refugees own a business that employs other people,  and 40 percent of those employees  are nationals of the host country.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> In other words, refugees are making jobs  for citizens of the host country.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> Even in the camps, we found extraordinary examples  of vibrant, flourishing and entrepreneurial businesses.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> For example, in a settlement called Nakivale,  we found examples of Congolese refugees  running digital music exchange businesses.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> We found a Rwandan who runs a business that's available  to allow the youth to play computer games  on recycled games consoles and recycled televisions.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> Against the odds of extreme constraint,  refugees are innovating,  and the gentleman you see before you is a Congolese guy called Demou-Kay.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> Demou-Kay arrived in the settlement with very little,  but he wanted to be a filmmaker.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> So with friends and colleagues, he started a community radio station,  he rented a video camera,  and he's now making films.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> He made two documentary films  with and for our team,  and he's making a successful business out of very little.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> It's those kinds of examples  that should guide our response to refugees.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> Rather than seeing refugees  as inevitably dependent upon humanitarian assistance,  we need to provide them with opportunities for human flourishing.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> Yes, clothes, blankets, shelter, food  are all important in the emergency phase,  but we need to also look beyond that.    </seg>
<seg id="86"> We need to provide opportunities to connectivity, electricity,  education, the right to work,  access to capital and banking.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> All the ways in which we take for granted  that we are plugged in to the global economy  can and should apply to refugees.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> The second idea I want to discuss is economic zones.    </seg>
<seg id="89"> Unfortunately, not every host country in the world  takes the approach Uganda has taken.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> Most host countries don't open up their economies to refugees  in the same way.    </seg>
<seg id="91"> But there are still pragmatic alternative options that we can use.    </seg>
<seg id="92"> Last April, I traveled to Jordan with my colleague,  the development economist Paul Collier,  and we brainstormed an idea while we were there  with the international community and the government,  an idea to bring jobs to Syrians  while supporting Jordan's national development strategy.    </seg>
<seg id="93"> The idea is for an economic zone,  one in which we could potentially integrate the employment of refugees  alongside the employment of Jordanian host nationals.    </seg>
<seg id="94"> And just 15 minutes away from the Zaatari refugee camp,  home to 83,000 refugees, is an existing economic zone  called the King Hussein Bin Talal Development Area.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> The government has spent over a hundred million dollars  connecting it to the electricity grid, connecting it to the road network,  but it lacked two things:  access to labor and inward investment.    </seg>
<seg id="96"> So what if refugees were able to work there  rather than being stuck in camps,  able to support their families and develop skills through vocational training  before they go back to Syria?    </seg>
<seg id="97"> We recognized that that could benefit Jordan,  whose development strategy requires it to make the leap  as a middle income country to manufacturing.    </seg>
<seg id="98"> It could benefit refugees, but it could also contribute  to the postconflict reconstruction of Syria  by recognizing that we need to incubate refugees  as the best source of eventually rebuilding Syria.    </seg>
<seg id="99"> We published the idea in the journal Foreign Affairs.    </seg>
<seg id="100"> King Abdullah has picked up on the idea.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> It was announced at the London Syria Conference two weeks ago,  and a pilot will begin in the summer.    </seg>
<seg id="102">   The third idea that I want to put to you  is preference matching between states and refugees  to lead to the kinds of happy outcomes you see here in the selfie  featuring Angela Merkel and a Syrian refugee.    </seg>
<seg id="103"> What we rarely do is ask refugees what they want, where they want to go,  but I'd argue we can do that  and still make everyone better off.    </seg>
<seg id="104"> The economist Alvin Roth has developed the idea of matching markets,  ways in which the preference ranking of the parties shapes an eventual match.    </seg>
<seg id="105"> My colleagues Will Jones and Alex Teytelboym  have explored ways in which that idea could be applied to refugees,  to ask refugees to rank their preferred destinations,  but also allow states to rank the types of refugees they want  on skills criteria or language criteria  and allow those to match.    </seg>
<seg id="106"> Now, of course you'd need to build in quotas  on things like diversity and vulnerability,  but it's a way of increasing the possibilities of matching.    </seg>
<seg id="107"> The matching idea has been successfully used  to match, for instance, students with university places,  to match kidney donors with patients,  and it underlies the kind of algorithms that exist on dating websites.    </seg>
<seg id="108"> So why not apply that to give refugees greater choice?    </seg>
<seg id="109"> It could also be used at the national level,  where one of the great challenges we face  is to persuade local communities to accept refugees.    </seg>
<seg id="110"> And at the moment, in my country, for instance,  we often send engineers to rural areas and farmers to the cities,  which makes no sense at all.    </seg>
<seg id="111"> So matching markets offer a potential way to bring those preferences together  and listen to the needs and demands of the populations that host  and the refugees themselves.    </seg>
<seg id="112"> The fourth idea I want to put to you is of humanitarian visas.    </seg>
<seg id="113"> Much of the tragedy and chaos we've seen in Europe  was entirely avoidable.    </seg>
<seg id="114"> It stems from a fundamental contradiction in Europe's asylum policy,  which is the following:  that in order to seek asylum in Europe,  you have to arrive spontaneously by embarking on those dangerous journeys  that I described.    </seg>
<seg id="115"> But why should those journeys be necessary in an era of the budget airline  and modern consular capabilities?    </seg>
<seg id="116"> They're completely unnecessary journeys,  and last year, they led to the deaths of over 3,000 people  on Europe's borders and within European territory.    </seg>
<seg id="117"> If refugees were simply allowed  to travel directly and seek asylum in Europe,  we would avoid that,  and there's a way of doing that  through something called a humanitarian visa,  that allows people to collect a visa at an embassy  or a consulate in a neighboring country  and then simply pay their own way  through a ferry or a flight to Europe.    </seg>
<seg id="118"> It costs around a thousand euros  to take a smuggler from Turkey to the Greek islands.    </seg>
<seg id="119"> It costs 200 euros to take a budget airline from Bodrum to Frankfurt.    </seg>
<seg id="120"> If we allowed refugees to do that, it would have major advantages.    </seg>
<seg id="121"> It would save lives,  it would undercut the entire market for smugglers,  and it would remove the chaos we see from Europe's front line  in areas like the Greek islands.    </seg>
<seg id="122"> It's politics that prevents us doing that rather than a rational solution.    </seg>
<seg id="123"> And this is an idea that has been applied.    </seg>
<seg id="124"> Brazil has adopted a pioneering approach  where over 2,000 Syrians have been able to get humanitarian visas,  enter Brazil, and claim refugee status on arrival in Brazil.    </seg>
<seg id="125"> And in that scheme, every Syrian who has gone through it  has received refugee status and been recognized as a genuine refugee.    </seg>
<seg id="126"> There is a historical precedent for it as well.    </seg>
<seg id="127"> Between 1922 and 1942,  these Nansen passports were used as travel documents  to allow 450,000 Assyrians, Turks and Chechens  to travel across Europe  and claim refugee status elsewhere in Europe.    </seg>
<seg id="128"> And the Nansen International Refugee Office  received the Nobel Peace Prize  in recognition of this being a viable strategy.    </seg>
<seg id="129"> So all four of these ideas that I've presented you  are ways in which we can expand Amira's choice set.    </seg>
<seg id="130"> They're ways in which we can have greater choice for refugees  beyond those basic, impossible three options  I explained to you  and still leave others better off.    </seg>
<seg id="131"> In conclusion, we really need a new vision,  a vision that enlarges the choices of refugees  but recognizes that they don't have to be a burden.    </seg>
<seg id="132"> There's nothing inevitable about refugees being a cost.    </seg>
<seg id="133"> Yes, they are a humanitarian responsibility,  but they're human beings with skills, talents, aspirations,  with the ability to make contributions -- if we let them.    </seg>
<seg id="134"> In the new world,  migration is not going to go away.    </seg>
<seg id="135"> What we've seen in Europe will be with us for many years.    </seg>
<seg id="136"> People will continue to travel,  they'll continue to be displaced,  and we need to find rational, realistic ways of managing this --  not based on the old logics of humanitarian assistance,  not based on logics of charity,  but building on the opportunities  offered by globalization, markets and mobility.    </seg>
<seg id="137"> I'd urge you all to wake up and urge our politicians  to wake up to this challenge.    </seg>
<seg id="138"> Thank you very much.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2434" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/thomas_peschak_dive_into_an_ocean_photographer_s_world</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Somersaulting manta rays, dashing dolphins, swarming schools of fish and munching sharks inhabit a world beneath the ocean's surface that few get a chance to see. Conservation photographer Thomas Peschak visits incredible seascapes around the world, and his photos reveal these hidden ecosystems. "You can't love something and become a champion for it if you don't know it exists," he says. Join Peschak in a new, immersive TED Talk format as he shares his stunning work and his dream for a future of respectful coexistence with the ocean.</description> 
<keywords>talks, adventure, animals, beauty, biodiversity, conservation, curiosity, ecology, environment, exploration, fish, future, global issues, mission blue, nature, oceans, photography, science and art, sustainability, water</keywords> 
<talkid>2434</talkid> 
<title>Thomas Peschak: Dive into an ocean photographer's world</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> As a kid, I used to dream about the ocean.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> It was this wild place full of color and life,  home to these alien-looking, fantastical creatures.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> I pictured big sharks ruling the food chain  and saw graceful sea turtles dancing across coral reefs.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> As a marine biologist turned photographer,  I've spent most of my career looking for places  as magical as those I used to dream about when I was little.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> As you can see,  I began exploring bodies of water at a fairly young age.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> But the first time I truly went underwater,  I was about 10 years old.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> And I can still vividly remember furiously finning  to reach this old, encrusted cannon on a shallow coral reef.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> And when I finally managed to grab hold of it,  I looked up, and I was instantly surrounded by fish  in all colors of the rainbow.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> That was the day I fell in love with the ocean.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> Thomas Peschak  Conservation Photographer  In my 40 years on this planet,  I've had the great privilege to explore  some of its most incredible seascapes  for National Geographic Magazine  and the Save Our Seas Foundation.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> I've photographed everything from really, really big sharks  to dainty ones that fit in the palm of your hand.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> I've smelled the fishy, fishy breath of humpback whales  feeding just feet away from me  in the cold seas off Canada's Great Bear Rainforest.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> And I've been privy to the mating rituals of green sea turtles  in the Mozambique Channel.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> Everyone on this planet affects and is affected by the ocean.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> And the pristine seas I used to dream of as a child  are becoming harder and harder to find.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> They are becoming more compressed  and more threatened.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> As we humans continue to maintain our role  as the leading predator on earth,  I've witnessed and photographed many of these ripple effects firsthand.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> For a long time, I thought I had to shock my audience  out of their indifference with disturbing images.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> And while this approach has merits,  I have come full circle.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> I believe that the best way for me to effect change  is to sell love.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> I guess I'm a matchmaker of sorts  and as a photographer,  I have the rare opportunity  to reveal animals and entire ecosystems  that lie hidden beneath the ocean's surface.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> You can't love something and become a champion for it  if you don't know it exists.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> Uncovering this -- that is the power of conservation photography.    </seg>
<seg id="24">   I've visited hundreds of marine locations,  but there are a handful of seascapes  that have touched me incredibly deeply.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> The first time I experienced that kind of high  was about 10 years ago,  off South Africa's rugged, wild coast.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> And every June and July,  enormous shoals of sardines travel northwards  in a mass migration we call the Sardine Run.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> And boy, do those fish have good reason to run.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> In hot pursuit are hoards of hungry and agile predators.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> Common dolphins hunt together  and they can separate some of the sardines from the main shoal  and they create bait balls.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> They drive and trap the fish upward against the ocean surface  and then they rush in to dine  on this pulsating and movable feast.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> Close behind are sharks.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> Now, most people believe  that sharks and dolphins are these mortal enemies,  but during the Sardine Run, they actually coexist.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> In fact, dolphins actually help sharks feed more effectively.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> Without dolphins, the bait balls are more dispersed  and sharks often end up with what I call a sardine donut,  or a mouth full of water.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> Now, while I've had a few spicy moments with sharks on the sardine run,  I know they don't see me as prey.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> However, I get bumped and tail-slapped just like any other guest  at this rowdy, rowdy banquet.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> From the shores of Africa we travel east,  across the vastness that is the Indian Ocean  to the Maldives, an archipelago of coral islands.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> And during the stormy southwest monsoon,  manta rays from all across the archipelago  travel to a tiny speck in Baa Atoll called Hanifaru.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> Armies of crustaceans,  most no bigger than the size of your pupils,  are the mainstay of the manta ray's diet.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> When plankton concentrations become patchy,  manta rays feed alone  and they somersault themselves backwards again and again,  very much like a puppy chasing its own tail.    </seg>
<seg id="41">   However, when plankton densities increase,  the mantas line up head-to-tail to form these long feeding chains,  and any tasty morsel that escapes the first or second manta in line  is surely to be gobbled up by the next or the one after.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> As plankton levels peak in the bay,  the mantas swim closer and closer together  in a unique behavior we call cyclone feeding.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> And as they swirl in tight formation,  this multi-step column of mantas  creates its own vortex, sucking in and delivering the plankton  right into the mantas' cavernous mouths.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> The experience of diving amongst such masses of hundreds of rays  is truly unforgettable.    </seg>
<seg id="45">   When I first photographed Hanifaru,  the site enjoyed no protection  and was threatened by development.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> And working with NGOs like the Manta Trust,  my images eventually helped Hanifaru  become a marine-protected area.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> Now, fisherman from neighboring islands,  they once hunted these manta rays  to make traditional drums from their skins.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> Today, they are the most ardent conservation champions  and manta rays earn the Maldivian economy  in excess of 8 million dollars every single year.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> I have always wanted to travel back in time  to an era where maps were mostly blank  or they read, "There be dragons."    </seg>
<seg id="50"> And today, the closest I've come is visiting remote atolls  in the western Indian Ocean.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> Far, far away from shipping lanes and fishing fleets,  diving into these waters is a poignant reminder  of what our oceans once looked like.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> Very few people have heard of Bassas da India,  a tiny speck of coral in the Mozambique Channel.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> Its reef forms a protective outer barrier  and the inner lagoon is a nursery ground  for Galapagos sharks.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> These sharks are anything but shy, even during the day.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> I had a bit of a hunch that they'd be even bolder  and more abundant at night.    </seg>
<seg id="56">   Never before have I encountered  so many sharks on a single coral outcrop.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> Capturing and sharing moments like this --  that reminds me why I chose my path.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> Earlier this year, I was on assignment for National Geographic Magazine  in Baja California.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> And about halfway down the peninsula on the Pacific side  lies San Ignacio Lagoon,  a critical calving ground for gray whales.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> For 100 years, this coast was the scene of a wholesale slaughter,  where more than 20,000 gray whales were killed,  leaving only a few hundred survivors.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> Today the descendents of these same whales  nudge their youngsters to the surface  to play and even interact with us.    </seg>
<seg id="62">   This species truly has made a remarkable comeback.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> Now, on the other side of the peninsula lies Cabo Pulmo,  a sleepy fishing village.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> Decades of overfishing had brought them close to collapse.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> In 1995, local fisherman convinced the authorities  to proclaim their waters a marine reserve.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> But what happened next was nothing short of miraculous.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> In 2005, after only a single decade of protection,  scientists measured the largest recovery of fish ever recorded.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> But don't take my word for it -- come with me.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> On a single breath, swim with me in deep,  into one of the largest and densest schools of fish  I have ever encountered.    </seg>
<seg id="70">   We all have the ability to be creators of hope.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> And through my photography,  I want to pass on the message that it is not too late for our oceans.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> And particularly, I want to focus on nature's resilience  in the face of 7.3 billion people.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> My hope is that in the future,  I will have to search much, much harder  to make photographs like this,  while creating images that showcase  our respectful coexistence with the ocean.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> Those will hopefully become an everyday occurrence for me.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> To thrive and survive in my profession,  you really have to be a hopeless optimist.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> And I always operate on the assumption  that the next great picture that will effect change  is right around the corner,  behind the next coral head,  inside the next lagoon  or possibly, in the one after it.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2445" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/mary_bassett_why_your_doctor_should_care_about_social_justice</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: In Zimbabwe in the 1980s, Mary Bassett witnessed the AIDS epidemic firsthand, and she helped set up a clinic to treat and educate local people about the deadly virus. But looking back, she regrets not sounding the alarm for the real problem: the structural inequities embedded in the world's political and economic organizations, inequities that make marginalized people more vulnerable. These same structural problems exist in the United States today, and as New York City's Health Commissioner, Bassett is using every chance she has to rally support for health equity and speak out against racism. "We don't have to have all the answers to call for change," she says. "We just need courage."</description> 
<keywords>talks, AIDS, Africa, TEDMED, United States, big problems, disease, global issues, government, health, health care, illness, inequality, medical research, medicine, public health, race, social change, virus</keywords> 
<talkid>2445</talkid> 
<title>Mary Bassett: Why your doctor should care about social justice</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> When I moved to Harare in 1985,  social justice was at the core of Zimbabwe's national health policy.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> The new government emerged from a long war of independence  and immediately proclaimed a socialist agenda:  health care services, primary education  became essentially free.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> A massive expansion of rural health centers  placed roughly 80 percent of the population  less than a two-hour walk from these facilities,  a truly remarkable accomplishment.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> In 1980, the year of independence,  25 percent of Zimbabwean children were fully immunized.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> By 1990, a mere decade later,  this proportion stood at 80 percent.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> I felt tremendously privileged to be part of this transformation,  a revolution.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> The excitement, the camaraderie, was palpable.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> Working side by side with brilliant Zimbabweans --  scientists, doctors, activists --  I felt connected not only to an African independence movement,  but to a global progressive public health movement.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> But there were daunting challenges.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> Zimbabwe reported its first AIDS case in 1985, the year I arrived.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> I had taken care of a few patients with AIDS in the early 1980s,  when I did my medical training at Harlem Hospital, but --  we had no idea what lay in store for Africa.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> Infection rate stood at about two percent in my early days there.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> These would soar  to one out of every four adults  by the time I left Harare 17 years later.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> By the mid-1990s,  I'd told hundreds of people in the prime of life  that they were HIV-positive.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> I saw colleagues and friends die,  my students, hospital patients, die.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> In response, my colleagues and I set up a clinic.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> We did condom demonstrations.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> We launched school education and workplace interventions.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> We did research. We counseled the partners of infected men  about how to protect themselves.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> We worked hard, and at the time, I believed that I was doing my best.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> I was providing excellent treatment,  such as it was.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> But I was not talking about structural change.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> Former UN Secretary Kofi Annan has spoken candidly  about his personal failure  leading to the Rwandan genocide.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> In 1994, he was head of the UN peacekeeping department.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> At a 10-year memorial for the genocide,  he reflected, "I believed at the time I was doing my best,  but I realized after the genocide  that there was more I could and should have done  to sound the alarm and rally support."    </seg>
<seg id="26"> The AIDS epidemic caught the health community unprepared,  and today, when the World Health Organization estimates  that 39 million people have lost their lives to this disease,  I'm not alone in feeling remorse and regret  at not having done more earlier.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> But while living in Zimbabwe,  I didn't see my role as an advocacy or a political one.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> I was there for my technical skills,  both my clinical and my research epidemiology skills.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> And in my mind, my job was to take care of patients  and to do research to better understand the population patterns of transmission,  and I hoped that we'd slow the spread of the virus.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> I was aware that socially marginalized populations were at disproportionate risk  of getting and dying of AIDS.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> And on the sugar plantations,  which really more closely resembled feudal fiefdoms  than any modern enterprise,  60 percent of pregnant women  tested HIV-positive.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> I worked to show how getting infected was not a moral failure  but instead related to a culture of male superiority,  to forced migrant labor and to colonialism.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> Whites were largely unscathed.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> As health professionals,  our tools were pitifully weak:  imploring people to change their individual behaviors,  use condoms, reduce number of partners.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> Infection rates climbed,  and when treatment became available in the West,  treatment that remains our most potent weapon  against this virus,  it was unaffordable to the public sector across Africa.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> I didn't speak out  about the unequal access to these life-saving drugs  or about the underlying economic and political systems  that were driving infection rates  in such huge swaths of the population.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> I rationalized my silence  by reminding myself that I was a guest in the country,  that sounding the alarm could even get me kicked out,  keep me from doing good work,  taking care of my patients,  doing much-needed research.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> So I didn't speak out  about the government's early stance on AIDS.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> I didn't voice my concerns loudly enough.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> Many doctors, health professionals,  may think I did nothing wrong.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> Our pact with our patients,  the Hippocratic Oath and its variants,  is about the sanctity of the patient-doctor relationship.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> And I did everything I could  for each and every patient of mine.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> But I knew  that epidemics emerge along the fissures of our society,  reflecting not only biology,  but more importantly patterns of marginalization, exclusion,  discrimination related to race, gender, sexuality, class and more.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> It was true of AIDS.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> It was true just recently of Ebola.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> Medical anthropologists such as Paul Farmer,  who worked on AIDS in Haiti,  call this structural violence:  structural because inequities are embedded  in the political and economic organization of our social world,  often in ways that are invisible to those with privilege and power;  and violence because its impact --  premature deaths, suffering, illness -- is violent.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> We do little for our patients  if we fail to recognize  these social injustices.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> Sounding the alarm is the first step towards doing public health right,  and it's how we may rally support  to break through and create real change together.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> So these days, I'm not staying quiet.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> I'm speaking up about a lot of things,  even when it makes listeners uncomfortable,  even when it makes me uncomfortable.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> And a lot of this is about racial disparities  and institutionalized racism,  things that we're not supposed to have in this country anymore,  certainly not in the practice of medicine  or public health.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> But we have them,  and we pay for them in lives cut short.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> That's why sounding the alarm  about the impact of racism on health in the United States,  the ongoing institutional and interpersonal violence  that people of color face,  compounded by our tragic legacy  of 250 years of slavery,  90 years of Jim Crow  and 60 years of imperfect equality,  sounding the alarm about this  is central to doing my job right  as New York City's Health Commissioner.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> In New York City, premature mortality -- that's death before the age of 65 --  is 50 percent higher for black men than white ones.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> A black woman in 2012  faced more than 10 times the risk of dying related to childbirth  as a white woman.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> And though we've made enormous strides  in reducing infant mortality rates,  a black baby still faces  nearly three times the risk of death in its first year of life  as compared to a white baby.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> New York City's not exceptional.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> These statistics are paralleled  by statistics found across the United States.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> A recent New York Times analysis  reported that there are 1.5 million missing black men across the country.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> They noted that more than one  out of every six black men  who today should be between the ages of 25 and 54 years  have disappeared from daily life,  lost either to prison or premature death.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> There is great injustice  in the daily and disproportionate violence faced by young black men,  the focus of recent protests under the banner #BlackLivesMatter.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> But we have to remember  that enduring and disparate rates  and the occurrence and outcome of common medical conditions --  heart disease, cancer, diabetes, HIV --  diseases that may kill slowly and quietly  and take even more black lives prematurely.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> As the #BlackLivesMatter movement unfolded,  I felt frustrated and angry  that the medical community  has been reluctant to even use the word "racism"  in our research and our work.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> You've probably felt something every time I've said it.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> Our medical students held die-ins in their white coats,  but the medical community has largely stood by passively  as ongoing discrimination continues to affect  the disease profile and mortality.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> And I worry  that the trend towards personalized and precision medicine,  looking for biological or genetic targets to better tailor treatment,  may inadvertently cause us to lose sight of the big picture,  that it is the daily context,  where a person lives, grows,  works, loves,  that most importantly determines population health,  and for too many of us, poor health.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> As health professionals in our daily work,  whether in the clinic or doing research,  we are witness to great injustice:  the homeless person who is unable to follow medical advice  because he has more pressing priorities;  the transgender youth who is contemplating suicide  because our society is just so harsh;  the single mother who has been made to feel that she is responsible  for the poor health of her child.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> Our role as health professionals  is not just to treat our patients  but to sound the alarm  and advocate for change.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> Rightfully or not,  our societal position gives our voices great credibility,  and we shouldn't waste that.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> I regret not speaking up in Zimbabwe,  and I've promised myself  that as New York City's Health Commissioner,  I will use every opportunity I have  to sound the alarm  and rally support for health equity.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> I will speak out against racism,  and I hope you will join me,  and I will join you when you speak out against sexism  or any other form of inequality.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> It's time for us to rise up  and collectively speak up  about structural inequality.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> We don't have to have all the answers  to call for change.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> We just need courage.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> The health of our patients,  the health of us all, depends on it.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2435" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/celeste_headlee_10_ways_to_have_a_better_conversation</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: When your job hinges on how well you talk to people, you learn a lot about how to have conversations -- and that most of us don't converse very well. Celeste Headlee has worked as a radio host for decades, and she knows the ingredients of a great conversation: Honesty, brevity, clarity and a healthy amount of listening. In this insightful talk, she shares 10 useful rules for having better conversations. "Go out, talk to people, listen to people," she says. "And, most importantly, be prepared to be amazed."</description> 
<keywords>talks, TEDx, communication, interview, language, personal growth</keywords> 
<talkid>2435</talkid> 
<title>Celeste Headlee: 10 ways to have a better conversation</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> All right, I want to see a show of hands:  how many of you have unfriended someone on Facebook  because they said something offensive about politics or religion,  childcare, food?    </seg>
<seg id="2">   And how many of you know at least one person that you avoid  because you just don't want to talk to them?    </seg>
<seg id="3">   You know, it used to be that in order to have a polite conversation,  we just had to follow the advice of Henry Higgins in "My Fair Lady":  Stick to the weather and your health.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> But these days, with climate change and anti-vaxxing, those subjects --    are not safe either.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> So this world that we live in,  this world in which every conversation  has the potential to devolve into an argument,  where our politicians can't speak to one another  and where even the most trivial of issues  have someone fighting both passionately for it and against it, it's not normal.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> Pew Research did a study of 10,000 American adults,  and they found that at this moment, we are more polarized,  we are more divided,  than we ever have been in history.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> We're less likely to compromise,  which means we're not listening to each other.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> And we make decisions about where to live,  who to marry and even who our friends are going to be,  based on what we already believe.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> Again, that means we're not listening to each other.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> A conversation requires a balance between talking and listening,  and somewhere along the way, we lost that balance.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> Now, part of that is due to technology.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> The smartphones that you all either have in your hands  or close enough that you could grab them really quickly.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> According to Pew Research,  about a third of American teenagers send more than a hundred texts a day.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> And many of them, almost most of them, are more likely to text their friends  than they are to talk to them face to face.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> There's this great piece in The Atlantic.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> It was written by a high school teacher named Paul Barnwell.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> And he gave his kids a communication project.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> He wanted to teach them how to speak on a specific subject without using notes.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> And he said this: "I came to realize..."    </seg>
<seg id="20">   "I came to realize that conversational competence  might be the single most overlooked skill we fail to teach.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> Kids spend hours each day engaging with ideas and each other through screens,  but rarely do they have an opportunity  to hone their interpersonal communications skills.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> It might sound like a funny question, but we have to ask ourselves:  Is there any 21st-century skill  more important than being able to sustain coherent, confident conversation?"    </seg>
<seg id="23"> Now, I make my living talking to people:  Nobel Prize winners, truck drivers,  billionaires, kindergarten teachers,  heads of state, plumbers.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> I talk to people that I like. I talk to people that I don't like.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> I talk to some people that I disagree with deeply on a personal level.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> But I still have a great conversation with them.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> So I'd like to spend the next 10 minutes or so teaching you how to talk  and how to listen.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> Many of you have already heard a lot of advice on this,  things like look the person in the eye,  think of interesting topics to discuss in advance,  look, nod and smile to show that you're paying attention,  repeat back what you just heard or summarize it.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> So I want you to forget all of that.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> It is crap.    </seg>
<seg id="31">   There is no reason to learn how to show you're paying attention  if you are in fact paying attention.    </seg>
<seg id="32">     Now, I actually use the exact same skills as a professional interviewer  that I do in regular life.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> So, I'm going to teach you how to interview people,  and that's actually going to help you learn how to be better conversationalists.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> Learn to have a conversation  without wasting your time, without getting bored,  and, please God, without offending anybody.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> We've all had really great conversations.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> We've had them before. We know what it's like.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> The kind of conversation where you walk away feeling engaged and inspired,  or where you feel like you've made a real connection  or you've been perfectly understood.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> There is no reason  why most of your interactions can't be like that.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> So I have 10 basic rules. I'm going to walk you through all of them,  but honestly, if you just choose one of them and master it,  you'll already enjoy better conversations.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> Number one: Don't multitask.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> And I don't mean just set down your cell phone  or your tablet or your car keys or whatever is in your hand.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> I mean, be present.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> Be in that moment.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> Don't think about your argument you had with your boss.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> Don't think about what you're going to have for dinner.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> If you want to get out of the conversation,  get out of the conversation,  but don't be half in it and half out of it.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> Number two: Don't pontificate.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> If you want to state your opinion  without any opportunity for response or argument or pushback or growth,  write a blog.    </seg>
<seg id="49">   Now, there's a really good reason why I don't allow pundits on my show:  Because they're really boring.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> If they're conservative, they're going to hate Obama and food stamps and abortion.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> If they're liberal, they're going to hate  big banks and oil corporations and Dick Cheney.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> Totally predictable.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> And you don't want to be like that.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> You need to enter every conversation assuming that you have something to learn.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> The famed therapist M. Scott Peck said  that true listening requires a setting aside of oneself.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> And sometimes that means setting aside your personal opinion.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> He said that sensing this acceptance,  the speaker will become less and less vulnerable  and more and more likely to open up the inner recesses  of his or her mind to the listener.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> Again, assume that you have something to learn.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> Bill Nye: "Everyone you will ever meet knows something that you don't."    </seg>
<seg id="60"> I put it this way:  Everybody is an expert in something.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> Number three: Use open-ended questions.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> In this case, take a cue from journalists.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> Start your questions with who, what, when, where, why or how.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> If you put in a complicated question, you're going to get a simple answer out.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> If I ask you, "Were you terrified?"    </seg>
<seg id="66"> you're going to respond to the most powerful word in that sentence,  which is "terrified," and the answer is "Yes, I was" or "No, I wasn't."    </seg>
<seg id="67"> "Were you angry?" "Yes, I was very angry."    </seg>
<seg id="68"> Let them describe it. They're the ones that know.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> Try asking them things like, "What was that like?"    </seg>
<seg id="70"> "How did that feel?"    </seg>
<seg id="71"> Because then they might have to stop for a moment and think about it,  and you're going to get a much more interesting response.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> Number four: Go with the flow.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> That means thoughts will come into your mind  and you need to let them go out of your mind.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> We've heard interviews often  in which a guest is talking for several minutes  and then the host comes back in and asks a question  which seems like it comes out of nowhere, or it's already been answered.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> That means the host probably stopped listening two minutes ago  because he thought of this really clever question,  and he was just bound and determined to say that.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> And we do the exact same thing.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> We're sitting there having a conversation with someone,  and then we remember that time that we met Hugh Jackman in a coffee shop.    </seg>
<seg id="78">   And we stop listening.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> Stories and ideas are going to come to you.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> You need to let them come and let them go.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> Number five: If you don't know, say that you don't know.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> Now, people on the radio, especially on NPR,  are much more aware that they're going on the record,  and so they're more careful about what they claim to be an expert in  and what they claim to know for sure.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> Do that. Err on the side of caution.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> Talk should not be cheap.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> Number six: Don't equate your experience with theirs.    </seg>
<seg id="86"> If they're talking about having lost a family member,  don't start talking about the time you lost a family member.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> If they're talking about the trouble they're having at work,  don't tell them about how much you hate your job.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> It's not the same. It is never the same.    </seg>
<seg id="89"> All experiences are individual.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> And, more importantly, it is not about you.    </seg>
<seg id="91"> You don't need to take that moment to prove how amazing you are  or how much you've suffered.    </seg>
<seg id="92"> Somebody asked Stephen Hawking once what his IQ was, and he said,  "I have no idea. People who brag about their IQs are losers."    </seg>
<seg id="93">   Conversations are not a promotional opportunity.    </seg>
<seg id="94"> Number seven:  Try not to repeat yourself.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> It's condescending, and it's really boring,  and we tend to do it a lot.    </seg>
<seg id="96"> Especially in work conversations or in conversations with our kids,  we have a point to make,  so we just keep rephrasing it over and over.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> Don't do that.    </seg>
<seg id="98"> Number eight: Stay out of the weeds.    </seg>
<seg id="99"> Frankly, people don't care  about the years, the names,  the dates, all those details  that you're struggling to come up with in your mind.    </seg>
<seg id="100"> They don't care. What they care about is you.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> They care about what you're like,  what you have in common.    </seg>
<seg id="102"> So forget the details. Leave them out.    </seg>
<seg id="103"> Number nine:  This is not the last one, but it is the most important one.    </seg>
<seg id="104"> Listen.    </seg>
<seg id="105"> I cannot tell you how many really important people have said  that listening is perhaps the most, the number one most important skill that you could develop.    </seg>
<seg id="106"> Buddha said, and I'm paraphrasing,  "If your mouth is open, you're not learning."    </seg>
<seg id="107"> And Calvin Coolidge said, "No man ever listened his way out of a job."    </seg>
<seg id="108">   Why do we not listen to each other?    </seg>
<seg id="109"> Number one, we'd rather talk.    </seg>
<seg id="110"> When I'm talking, I'm in control.    </seg>
<seg id="111"> I don't have to hear anything I'm not interested in.    </seg>
<seg id="112"> I'm the center of attention.    </seg>
<seg id="113"> I can bolster my own identity.    </seg>
<seg id="114"> But there's another reason:  We get distracted.    </seg>
<seg id="115"> The average person talks at about 225 word per minute,  but we can listen at up to 500 words per minute.    </seg>
<seg id="116"> So our minds are filling in those other 275 words.    </seg>
<seg id="117"> And look, I know, it takes effort and energy  to actually pay attention to someone,  but if you can't do that, you're not in a conversation.    </seg>
<seg id="118"> You're just two people shouting out barely related sentences  in the same place.    </seg>
<seg id="119">   You have to listen to one another.    </seg>
<seg id="120"> Stephen Covey said it very beautifully.    </seg>
<seg id="121"> He said, "Most of us don't listen with the intent to understand.    </seg>
<seg id="122"> We listen with the intent to reply."    </seg>
<seg id="123"> One more rule, number 10, and it's this one: Be brief.    </seg>
<seg id="124"> [A good conversation is like a miniskirt; short enough to retain interest,  but long enough to cover the subject. -- My Sister]     All of this boils down to the same basic concept, and it is this one:  Be interested in other people.    </seg>
<seg id="125"> You know, I grew up with a very famous grandfather,  and there was kind of a ritual in my home.    </seg>
<seg id="126"> People would come over to talk to my grandparents,  and after they would leave, my mother would come over to us,  and she'd say, "Do you know who that was?    </seg>
<seg id="127"> She was the runner-up to Miss America.    </seg>
<seg id="128"> He was the mayor of Sacramento.    </seg>
<seg id="129"> She won a Pulitzer Prize. He's a Russian ballet dancer."    </seg>
<seg id="130"> And I kind of grew up assuming  everyone has some hidden, amazing thing about them.    </seg>
<seg id="131"> And honestly, I think it's what makes me a better host.    </seg>
<seg id="132"> I keep my mouth shut as often as I possibly can,  I keep my mind open,  and I'm always prepared to be amazed,  and I'm never disappointed.    </seg>
<seg id="133"> You do the same thing.    </seg>
<seg id="134"> Go out, talk to people,  listen to people,  and, most importantly, be prepared to be amazed.    </seg>
<seg id="135"> Thanks.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2426" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/matthew_williams_special_olympics_let_me_be_myself_a_champion</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: How much do you know about intellectual disabilities? Special Olympics champion and ambassador Matthew Williams is proof that athletic competition and the camaraderie it fosters can transform lives, both on and off the field. Together with his fellow athletes, he invites you to join him at the next meet -- and challenges you to walk away with your heart unchanged.</description> 
<keywords>talks, TEDx, bullying, community, disability, health, identity, inequality, motivation, personal growth, play, potential, self, social change, sports</keywords> 
<talkid>2426</talkid> 
<title>Matthew Williams: Special Olympics let me be myself -- a champion</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> Hello.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> My name is Matthew Williams,  and I am a champion.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> I have won medals in three different sports  and national games in Canada,  competed at the international level in basketball  and was proud to represent Canada  on the world stage.    </seg>
<seg id="4">   I train five days a week for basketball and speed skating,  work with top quality coaches  and mental performance consultants  to be at my best in my sport.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> By the way, all that is through Special Olympics.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> Does that change the way you think of me  and my accomplishments?    </seg>
<seg id="7"> The world does not see all people like me as champions.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> Not long ago, people like me were shunned and hidden away.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> There has been lots of change since Special Olympics began in 1968,  but in too many cases,  people with intellectual disabilities  are invisible to the wider population.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> People use the r-word in front of me, and they think it doesn't matter.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> That's the word "retard" or "retarded"  used in a derogatory manner.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> They're not thinking about how much it hurts me and my friends.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> I don't want you to think I'm here because I'm a charity case.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> I am here because there is still a big problem with the way  many people see individuals with intellectual disabilities,  or, too often,  how they don't see them at all.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> Did you know the World Games happened this year?    </seg>
<seg id="16"> I was one of over 6,500 athletes with intellectual disabilities  from 165 countries who competed in LA.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> There was over 62,000 spectators watching opening ceremonies,  and there was live coverage on TSN and ESPN.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> Did you even know that happened?    </seg>
<seg id="19"> What do you think of when you see someone like me?    </seg>
<seg id="20"> I am here today to challenge you  to look at us as equals.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> Special Olympics transforms the self-identity of athletes  with intellectual disabilities  and the perceptions of everyone watching.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> For those of you who aren't familiar,  Special Olympics is for athletes with intellectual disabilities.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> Special Olympics is separate from the Paralympics and Olympics.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> We offer high-quality, year round sports programs  for people with intellectual disabilities  that changes lives and perceptions.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> This movement has changed my life  and those of so many others.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> And it has changed the way  the world sees people with intellectual disabilities.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> I was born with epilepsy and an intellectual disability.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> Growing up, I played hockey until I was 12 years old.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> The older I got, the more I felt  it was harder to keep up with everyone else,  and I was angry and frustrated.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> For a while, I did not play any sports,  didn't have many friends  and felt left out and sad.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> There was a time when people with intellectual disabilities  were hidden away from society.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> No one thought they could participate in sports,  let alone be a valued member of society.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> In the 1960s, Dr. Frank Hayden,  a scientist at the University of Toronto,  was studying the effects of regular exercise  on the fitness levels of children with intellectual disabilities.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> Using rigorous scientific research,  Dr. Hayden and other researchers  came to the conclusion  that it was simply the lack of opportunity to participate  that caused their fitness levels to suffer.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> Lots of people doubted that people with intellectual disabilities  could benefit from fitness programs  and sports competition opportunities.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> But pioneers like Dr. Hayden and Eunice Kennedy Shriver,  the founder of Special Olympics,  persevered,  and Special Olympics athletes have proved them right  four and a half million times over.    </seg>
<seg id="37">   Before I joined Special Olympics,  I was nervous  because I was young, shy, not confident  and didn't have many friends.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> When I got there, though, everyone was very encouraging,  supportive, and let me be myself  without being judged.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> Now, I am a basketball player and speed skater  who has competed at provincial, national games,  and this year made it all the way to the World Summer Games in LA,  where I was part of the first ever Canadian basketball team  to compete at World Games.    </seg>
<seg id="40">   I am one of more than four and a half million athletes around the globe,  and I've heard so many similar stories.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> Being Special Olympics athletes  restores our pride and dignity.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> Special Olympics also addresses critical health needs.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> Studies have shown that, on average,  men with intellectual disabilities  die 13 years younger than men without,  and women with intellectual disabilities  die 20 years younger than women without.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> Special Olympics keeps us healthy  by getting us active  and participating in sport.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> Also, our coaches teach us about nutrition and health.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> Special Olympics also provides free health screening  for athletes who have difficulty communicating with their doctor  or accessing health care.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> At the 2015 World Summer Games,  my Team Canada teammates and I played the Nigerian basketball team.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> The day before our game,  the Nigerian basketball team went to the World Games Healthy Athlete screening,  where seven of 10 members  were given hearing aids for free  and got to hear clearly for the first time.    </seg>
<seg id="49">   The change in them was amazing.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> They were more excited, happy and confident,  because their coach could vocally communicate with them.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> And they were emotional  because they could hear the sounds of the basketball,  the sounds of the whistle  and the cheering fans in the stands --  sounds that we take for granted.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> Special Olympics is transforming more than just the athlete in their sport.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> Special Olympics is transforming their lives off the field.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> This year, research findings showed  that nearly half of the adults in the US  don't know a single person with an intellectual disability,  and the 44 percent of Americans  who don't have personal contact with intellectual disabilities  are significantly less accepting and positive.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> Then there's the r-word,  proving that people with intellectual disabilities  are still invisible  to far too many people.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> People use it as a casual term or an insult.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> It was tweeted more than nine million times last year,  and it is deeply hurtful  to me and my four and a half million fellow athletes around the planet.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> People don't think it's insulting,  but it is.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> As my fellow athlete and global messenger John Franklin Stephens wrote  in an open letter to a political pundit  who used the r-word as an insult,  "Come join us someday at Special Olympics.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> See if you walk away with your heart unchanged."    </seg>
<seg id="61">   This year, at the 2015 World Summer Games,  people lined up for hours  to get into the final night of powerlifting competition.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> So it was standing room only when my teammate Jackie Barrett,  the Newfoundland Moose,  deadlifted 655 pounds  and lifted 611 pounds in the squat --    setting huge new records for Special Olympics.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> Jackie is a record holder among all powerlifters in Newfoundland --  not just Special Olympics, all powerlifters.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> Jackie was a huge star in LA,  and ESPN live-tweeted his record-breaking lifts  and were wowed by his performance.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> Fifty years ago, few imagined individuals with intellectual disabilities  could do anything like that.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> This year, 60,000 spectators filled the famous LA Memorial Coliseum  to watch the opening ceremonies of World Games  and cheer athletes from 165 countries  around the world.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> Far from being hidden away,  we were cheered and celebrated.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> Special Olympics teaches athletes  to be confident and proud of themselves.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> Special Olympics teaches the world  that people with intellectual disabilities  deserve respect and inclusion.    </seg>
<seg id="70">   Now, I have dreams and achievements in my sport,  great coaches,  respect and dignity,  better health,  and I am pursuing a career as a personal trainer.    </seg>
<seg id="71">   I am no longer hidden, bullied  and I am here doing a TED Talk.    </seg>
<seg id="72">   The world is a different place because of Special Olympics,  but there is still farther to go.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> So the next time you see someone with an intellectual disability,  I hope you will see their ability.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> The next time someone uses the r-word near you,  I hope you will tell them how much it hurts.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> I hope you will think about getting involved with Special Olympics.    </seg>
<seg id="76">   I would like to leave you with one final thought.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> Nelson Mandela said,  "Sports has the power to change the world."    </seg>
<seg id="78"> Special Olympics is changing the world  by transforming four and a half million athletes  and giving us a place to be confident,  meet friends,  not be judged  and get to feel like and be champions.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> Thank you very much.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2425" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/pardis_sabeti_how_we_ll_fight_the_next_deadly_virus</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: When Ebola broke out in March 2014, Pardis Sabeti and her team got to work sequencing the virus's genome, learning how it mutated and spread. Sabeti immediately released her research online, so virus trackers and scientists from around the world could join in the urgent fight. In this talk, she shows how open cooperation was key to halting the virus ... and to attacking the next one to come along. "We had to work openly, we had to share and we had to work together," Sabeti says. "Let us not let the world be defined by the destruction wrought by one virus, but illuminated by billions of hearts and minds working in unity."</description> 
<keywords>talks, Africa, big problems, disease, ebola, future, genetics, global issues, health, humanity, illness, innovation, medical research, medicine, pandemic, public health, science</keywords> 
<talkid>2425</talkid> 
<title>Pardis Sabeti: How we'll fight the next deadly virus</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> You may never have heard of Kenema, Sierra Leone  or Arua, Nigeria.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> But I know them as two of the most extraordinary places on earth.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> In hospitals there, there's a community of nurses, physicians and scientists  that have been quietly battling  one of the deadliest threats to humanity for years:  Lassa virus.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> Lassa virus is a lot like Ebola.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> It can cause a severe fever and can often be fatal.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> But these individuals, they risk their lives every day  to protect the individuals in their communities,  and by doing so, protect us all.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> But one of the most extraordinary things I learned about them  on one of my first visits out there many years ago  was that they start each morning --  these challenging, extraordinary days on the front lines -- by singing.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> They gather together, and they show their joy.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> And over the years, from year after year as I've visited them and they've visited me,  I get to gather with them and I sing  and we write and we love it,  because it reminds us that we're not just there to pursue science together;  we're bonded through a shared humanity.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> And that of course, as you can imagine, becomes extremely important,  even essential, as things begin to change.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> And that changed a great deal in March of 2014,  when the Ebola outbreak was declared in Guinea.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> This is the first outbreak in West Africa,  near the border of Sierra Leone and Liberia.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> And it was frightening, frightening for us all.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> We had actually suspected for some time  that Lassa and Ebola were more widespread than thought,  and we thought it could one day come to Kenema.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> And so members of my team immediately went out  and joined Dr. Humarr Khan and his team there,  and we set up diagnostics to be able to have sensitive molecular tests  to pick up Ebola if it came across the border and into Sierra Leone.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> We'd already set up this kind of capacity for Lassa virus,  we knew how to do it, the team is outstanding.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> We just had to give them the tools and place to survey for Ebola.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> And unfortunately, that day came.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> On May 23, 2014, a woman checked into the maternity ward at the hospital,  and the team ran those important molecular tests  and they identified the first confirmed case of Ebola in Sierra Leone.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> This was an exceptional work that was done.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> They were able to diagnose the case immediately,  to safely treat the patient  and to begin to do contact tracing to follow what was going on.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> It could've stopped something.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> But by the time that day came,  the outbreak had already been breeding for months.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> With hundreds of cases, it had already eclipsed all previous outbreaks.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> And it came into Sierra Leone not as that singular case,  but as a tidal wave.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> We had to work with the international community,  with the Ministry of Health, with Kenema, to begin to deal with the cases,  as the next week brought 31,  then 92, then 147 cases -- all coming to Kenema,  one of the only places in Sierra Leone that could deal with this.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> And we worked around the clock trying to do everything we could,  trying to help the individuals, trying to get attention,  but we also did one other simple thing.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> From that specimen that we take from a patient's blood to detect Ebola,  The other thing we can do is, actually, put in a chemical and deactivate it,  so just place it into a box and ship it across the ocean, and that's what we did.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> We sent it to Boston, where my team works.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> And we also worked around the clock doing shift work, day after day,  and we quickly generated 99 genomes of the Ebola virus.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> This is the blueprint -- the genome of a virus is the blueprint.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> We all have one.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> It says everything that makes up us,  and it tells us so much information.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> The results of this kind of work are simple and they're powerful.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> We could actually take these 99 different viruses, look at them and compare them,  and we could see, actually, compared to three genomes  that had been previously published from Guinea,  we could show that the outbreak emerged in Guinea months before,  once into the human population, and from there had been transmitting from human to human.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> Now, that's incredibly important when you're trying to figure out how to intervene,  but the important thing is contact tracing.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> We also could see that as the virus was moving between humans, it was mutating.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> And each of those mutations are so important,  because the diagnostics, the vaccines, the therapies that we're using,  are all based on that genome sequence, fundamentally --  that's what drives it.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> And so global health experts would need to respond,  would have to develop, to recalibrate everything that they were doing.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> But the way that science works, the position I was in at that point  is, I had the data, and I could have worked in a silo for many, many months,  analyzed the data carefully, slowly,  submitted the paper for publication, gone through a few back-and-forths,  and then finally when the paper came out, might release that data.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> That's the way the status quo works.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> Well, that was not going to work at this point, right?    </seg>
<seg id="43"> We had friends on the front lines  and to us it was just obvious that what we needed is help,  lots of help.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> So the first thing we did is,  as soon as the sequences came off the machines,  we published it to the web.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> We just released it to the whole world and said, "Help us."    </seg>
<seg id="46"> And help came.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> we were being contacted from people all over,  surprised to see the data out there and released.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> Some of the greatest viral trackers in the world  were suddenly part of our community.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> We were working together in this virtual way,  sharing, regular calls, communications,  trying to follow the virus minute by minute,  to see ways that we could stop it.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> And there are so many ways that we can form communities like that.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> Everybody, particularly when the outbreak started to expand globally,  was reaching out to learn, to participate, to engage.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> Everybody wants to play a part.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> The amount of human capacity out there is just amazing,  and the Internet connects us all.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> And could you imagine that instead of being frightened of each other,  that we all just said, "Let's do this.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> Let's work together, and let's make this happen."    </seg>
<seg id="56"> But the problem is that the data that all of us are using,  Googling on the web, is just too limited to do what we need to do.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> And so many opportunities get missed when that happens.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> So in the early part of the epidemic from Kenema,  we'd had 106 clinical records from patients,  and we once again made that publicly available to the world.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> And in our own lab, we could show that you could take those 106 records,  we could train computers to predict the prognosis for Ebola patients  to near 100 percent accuracy.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> And we made an app that could release that,  to make that available to health-care workers in the field.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> But 106 is just not enough to make it powerful, to validate it.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> So we were waiting for more data to release that.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> and the data has still not come.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> We are still waiting, tweaking away,  in silos rather than working together.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> And this just -- we can't accept that.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> Right? You, all of you, cannot accept that.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> It's our lives on the line.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> many lives were lost, many health-care workers,  including beloved colleagues of mine,  five colleagues: Mbalu Fonnie, Alex Moigboi,  Dr. Humarr Khan, Alice Kovoma and Mohamed Fullah.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> These are just five of many health-care workers at Kenema and beyond  that died while the world waited and while we all worked,  quietly and separately.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> See, Ebola, like all threats to humanity,  it's fueled by mistrust and distraction and division.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> When we build barriers amongst ourselves and we fight amongst ourselves,  the virus thrives.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> But unlike all threats to humanity,  Ebola is one where we're actually all the same.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> We're all in this fight together.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> Ebola on one person's doorstep could soon be on ours.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> And so in this place with the same vulnerabilities,  the same strengths, the same fears, the same hopes,  I hope that we work together with joy.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> A graduate student of mine was reading a book about Sierra Leone,  and she discovered that the word "Kenema,"  the hospital that we work at and the city where we work in Sierra Leone,  is named after the Mende word for "clear like a river, translucent  and open to the public gaze."    </seg>
<seg id="77"> That was really profound for us,  because without knowing it, we'd always felt  that in order to honor the individuals in Kenema where we worked,  we had to work openly, we had to share and we had to work together.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> And we have to do that.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> We all have to demand that of ourselves and others --  to be open to each other when an outbreak happens,  to fight in this fight together.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> Because this is not the first outbreak of Ebola, it will not be the last,  and there are many other microbes out there that are lying in wait,  like Lassa virus and others.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> And the next time this happens, it could happen in a city of millions, it could start there.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> It could be something that's transmitted through the air.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> It could even be disseminated intentionally.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> And I know that that is frightening, I understand that,  but I know also, and this experience shows us,  that we have the technology and we have the capacity to win this thing,  to win this and have the upper hand over viruses.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> But we can only do it if we do it together and we do it with joy.    </seg>
<seg id="86"> So for Dr. Khan and for all of those who sacrificed their lives on the front lines  in this fight with us always,  let us be in this fight with them always.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> And let us not let the world be defined by the destruction wrought by one virus,  but illuminated by billions of hearts and minds  working in unity.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
</srcset>
</mteval>
