<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mteval>
<srcset setid="iwslt2017-tst2016" srclang="english">
<doc docid="2227" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/lucianne_walkowicz_let_s_not_use_mars_as_a_backup_planet</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Stellar astronomer and TED Senior Fellow Lucianne Walkowicz works on NASA's Kepler mission, searching for places in the universe that could support life. So it's worth a listen when she asks us to think carefully about Mars. In this short talk, she suggests that we stop dreaming of Mars as a place that we'll eventually move to when we've messed up Earth, and to start thinking of planetary exploration and preservation of the Earth as two sides of the same goal. As she says, "The more you look for planets like Earth, the more you appreciate our own planet."</description> 
<keywords>talks, Mars, NASA, Planets, TED Fellows, astronomy, exploration, future, humanity, solar system, space, universe</keywords> 
<talkid>2227</talkid> 
<title>Lucianne Walkowicz: Let's not use Mars as a backup planet</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> We're at a tipping point in human history,  a species poised between gaining the stars and losing the planet we call home.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> Even in just the past few years, we've greatly expanded  our knowledge of how Earth fits within the context of our universe.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> NASA's Kepler mission has discovered  thousands of potential planets around other stars,  indicating that Earth is but one of billions of planets in our galaxy.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> Kepler is a space telescope  that measures the subtle dimming of stars as planets pass in front of them,  blocking just a little bit of that light from reaching us.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> Kepler's data reveals planets' sizes  as well as their distance from their parent star.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> Together, this helps us understand whether these planets are small and rocky,  like the terrestrial planets in our own Solar System,  and also how much light they receive from their parent sun.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> In turn, this provides clues as to whether these planets that we discover  might be habitable or not.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> Unfortunately, at the same time as we're discovering this treasure trove  of potentially habitable worlds,  our own planet is sagging under the weight of humanity.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> 2014 was the hottest year on record.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> Glaciers and sea ice that have been with us for millennia  are now disappearing in a matter of decades.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> These planetary-scale environmental changes that we have set in motion  are rapidly outpacing our ability to alter their course.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> But I'm not a climate scientist, I'm an astronomer.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> I study planetary habitability as influenced by stars  with the hopes of finding the places in the universe  where we might discover life beyond our own planet.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> You could say that I look for choice alien real estate.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> Now, as somebody who is deeply embedded in the search for life in the universe,  I can tell you that the more you look for planets like Earth,  the more you appreciate our own planet itself.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> Each one of these new worlds invites a comparison  between the newly discovered planet and the planets we know best:  those of our own Solar System.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> Consider our neighbor, Mars.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> Mars is small and rocky, and though it's a bit far from the Sun,  if found by a mission like Kepler.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> Indeed, it's possible that Mars was habitable in the past,  and in part, this is why we study Mars so much.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> Our rovers, like Curiosity, crawl across its surface,  scratching for clues as to the origins of life as we know it.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> Orbiters like the MAVEN mission sample the Martian atmosphere,  trying to understand how Mars might have lost its past habitability.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> Private spaceflight companies now offer not just a short trip to near space  but the tantalizing possibility of living our lives on Mars.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> But though these Martian vistas  resemble the deserts of our own home world,  places that are tied in our imagination to ideas about pioneering and frontiers,  compared to Earth  Mars is a pretty terrible place to live.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> Consider the extent to which we have not colonized  the deserts of our own planet,  places that are lush by comparison with Mars.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> Even in the driest, highest places on Earth,  the air is sweet and thick with oxygen  exhaled from thousands of miles away by our rainforests.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> I worry -- I worry that this excitement about colonizing Mars and other planets  carries with it a long, dark shadow:  the implication and belief by some  that Mars will be there to save us from the self-inflicted destruction of the only truly habitable planet we know of, the Earth.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> As much as I love interplanetary exploration,  I deeply disagree with this idea.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> There are many excellent reasons to go to Mars,  but for anyone to tell you that Mars will be there to back up humanity  is like the captain of the Titanic telling you that the real party  is happening later on the lifeboats.    </seg>
<seg id="29">     Thank you.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> But the goals of interplanetary exploration and planetary preservation  are not opposed to one another.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> No, they're in fact two sides of the same goal:  to understand, preserve and improve life into the future.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> The extreme environments of our own world are alien vistas.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> They're just closer to home.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> If we can understand how to create and maintain habitable spaces  out of hostile, inhospitable spaces here on Earth,  perhaps we can meet the needs of both preserving our own environment  and moving beyond it.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> I leave you with a final thought experiment:  Fermi's paradox.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> Many years ago, the physicist Enrico Fermi asked that, given the fact  that our universe has been around for a very long time  and we expect that there are many planets within it,  we should have found evidence for alien life by now.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> So where are they?    </seg>
<seg id="38"> Well, one possible solution to Fermi's paradox  is that, as civilizations become technologically advanced enough  to consider living amongst the stars,  they lose sight of how important it is  to safeguard the home worlds that fostered that advancement to begin with.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> It is hubris to believe that interplanetary colonization alone  will save us from ourselves,  but planetary preservation and interplanetary exploration  can work together.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> If we truly believe in our ability  to bend the hostile environments of Mars for human habitation,  then we should be able to surmount the far easier task of preserving  the habitability of the Earth.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2361" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/daniel_levitin_how_to_stay_calm_when_you_know_you_ll_be_stressed</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: You're not at your best when you're stressed. In fact, your brain has evolved over millennia to release cortisol in stressful situations, inhibiting rational, logical thinking but potentially helping you survive, say, being attacked by a lion. Neuroscientist Daniel Levitin thinks there's a way to avoid making critical mistakes in stressful situations, when your thinking becomes clouded -- the pre-mortem. "We all are going to fail now and then," he says. "The idea is to think ahead to what those failures might be."</description> 
<keywords>talks, brain, cognitive science, health, medicine, memory, mental health, neuroscience</keywords> 
<talkid>2361</talkid> 
<title>Daniel Levitin: How to stay calm when you know you'll be stressed</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> A few years ago, I broke into my own house.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> I had just driven home,  it was around midnight in the dead of Montreal winter,  I had been visiting my friend, Jeff, across town,  and the thermometer on the front porch read minus 40 degrees --  and don't bother asking if that's Celsius or Fahrenheit,  minus 40 is where the two scales meet --  it was very cold.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> And as I stood on the front porch fumbling in my pockets,  I found I didn't have my keys.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> In fact, I could see them through the window,  lying on the dining room table where I had left them.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> So I quickly ran around and tried all the other doors and windows,  and they were locked tight.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> I thought about calling a locksmith -- at least I had my cellphone,  but at midnight, it could take a while for a locksmith to show up,  and it was cold.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> I couldn't go back to my friend Jeff's house for the night  because I had an early flight to Europe the next morning,  and I needed to get my passport and my suitcase.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> So, desperate and freezing cold,  I found a large rock and I broke through the basement window,  cleared out the shards of glass,  I crawled through,  I found a piece of cardboard and taped it up over the opening,  figuring that in the morning, on the way to the airport,  I could call my contractor and ask him to fix it.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> This was going to be expensive,  but probably no more expensive than a middle-of-the-night locksmith,  so I figured, under the circumstances, I was coming out even.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> Now, I'm a neuroscientist by training  and I know a little bit about how the brain performs under stress.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> It releases cortisol that raises your heart rate,  it modulates adrenaline levels  and it clouds your thinking.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> So the next morning,  when I woke up on too little sleep,  worrying about the hole in the window,  and a mental note that I had to call my contractor,  and the freezing temperatures,  and the meetings I had upcoming in Europe,  and, you know, with all the cortisol in my brain,  my thinking was cloudy,  but I didn't know it was cloudy because my thinking was cloudy.    </seg>
<seg id="13">   And it wasn't until I got to the airport check-in counter,  that I realized I didn't have my passport.    </seg>
<seg id="14">   So I raced home in the snow and ice, 40 minutes,  got my passport, raced back to the airport,  I made it just in time,  but they had given away my seat to someone else,  so I got stuck in the back of the plane, next to the bathrooms,  in a seat that wouldn't recline, on an eight-hour flight.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> Well, I had a lot of time to think during those eight hours and no sleep.    </seg>
<seg id="16">   And I started wondering, are there things that I can do,  systems that I can put into place,  that will prevent bad things from happening?    </seg>
<seg id="17"> Or at least if bad things happen,  will minimize the likelihood of it being a total catastrophe.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> So I started thinking about that,  but my thoughts didn't crystallize until about a month later.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> I was having dinner with my colleague, Danny Kahneman, the Nobel Prize winner,  and I somewhat embarrassedly told him about having broken my window,  and, you know, forgotten my passport,  and Danny shared with me  that he'd been practicing something called prospective hindsight.    </seg>
<seg id="20">   It's something that he had gotten from the psychologist Gary Klein,  who had written about it a few years before,  also called the pre-mortem.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> Now, you all know what the postmortem is.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> Whenever there's a disaster,  a team of experts come in and they try to figure out what went wrong, right?    </seg>
<seg id="23"> Well, in the pre-mortem, Danny explained,  you look ahead and you try to figure out all the things that could go wrong,  and then you try to figure out what you can do  to prevent those things from happening, or to minimize the damage.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> So what I want to talk to you about today  are some of the things we can do in the form of a pre-mortem.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> Some of them are obvious, some of them are not so obvious.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> I'll start with the obvious ones.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> Around the home, designate a place for things that are easily lost.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> Now, this sounds like common sense, and it is,  but there's a lot of science to back this up,  based on the way our spatial memory works.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> There's a structure in the brain called the hippocampus,  that evolved over tens of thousands of years,  to keep track of the locations of important things --  where the well is, where fish can be found,  that stand of fruit trees,  where the friendly and enemy tribes live.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> The hippocampus is the part of the brain  that in London taxicab drivers becomes enlarged.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> It's the part of the brain that allows squirrels to find their nuts.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> And if you're wondering, somebody actually did the experiment  where they cut off the olfactory sense of the squirrels,  and they could still find their nuts.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> They weren't using smell, they were using the hippocampus,  this exquisitely evolved mechanism in the brain for finding things.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> But it's really good for things that don't move around much,  not so good for things that move around.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> So this is why we lose car keys and reading glasses and passports.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> So in the home, designate a spot for your keys --  a hook by the door, maybe a decorative bowl.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> For your passport, a particular drawer.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> For your reading glasses, a particular table.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> If you designate a spot and you're scrupulous about it,  your things will always be there when you look for them.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> What about travel?    </seg>
<seg id="41"> Take a cell phone picture of your credit cards,  your driver's license, your passport,  mail it to yourself so it's in the cloud.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> If these things are lost or stolen, you can facilitate replacement.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> Now these are some rather obvious things.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> Remember, when you're under stress, the brain releases cortisol.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> Cortisol is toxic, and it causes cloudy thinking.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> So part of the practice of the pre-mortem  is to recognize that under stress you're not going to be at your best,  and you should put systems in place.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> And there's perhaps no more stressful a situation  than when you're confronted with a medical decision to make.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> And at some point, all of us are going to be in that position,  where we have to make a very important decision  about the future of our medical care or that of a loved one,  to help them with a decision.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> And so I want to talk about that.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> And I'm going to talk about a very particular medical condition.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> But this stands as a proxy for all kinds of medical decision-making,  and indeed for financial decision-making, and social decision-making --  any kind of decision you have to make  that would benefit from a rational assessment of the facts.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> So suppose you go to your doctor and the doctor says,  "I just got your lab work back, your cholesterol's a little high."    </seg>
<seg id="53"> Now, you all know that high cholesterol  is associated with an increased risk of cardiovascular disease,  heart attack, stroke.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> And so you're thinking  having high cholesterol isn't the best thing,  and so the doctor says, "You know, I'd like to give you a drug  that will help you lower your cholesterol, a statin."    </seg>
<seg id="55"> And you've probably heard of statins,  you know that they're among the most widely prescribed drugs  you probably even know people who take them.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> And so you're thinking, "Yeah! Give me the statin."    </seg>
<seg id="57"> But there's a question you should ask at this point,  a statistic you should ask for that most doctors don't like talking about,  and pharmaceutical companies like talking about even less.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> It's for the number needed to treat.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> Now, what is this, the NNT?    </seg>
<seg id="60"> It's the number of people that need to take a drug  or undergo a surgery or any medical procedure  before one person is helped.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> And you're thinking, what kind of crazy statistic is that?    </seg>
<seg id="62"> The number should be one.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> My doctor wouldn't prescribe something to me  if it's not going to help.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> But actually, medical practice doesn't work that way.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> And it's not the doctor's fault,  if it's anybody's fault, it's the fault of scientists like me.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> We haven't figured out the underlying mechanisms well enough.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> But GlaxoSmithKline estimates  that 90 percent of the drugs work in only 30 to 50 percent of the people.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> So the number needed to treat for the most widely prescribed statin,  what do you suppose it is?    </seg>
<seg id="69"> How many people have to take it before one person is helped?    </seg>
<seg id="70"> 300.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> This is according to research  by research practitioners Jerome Groopman and Pamela Hartzband,  independently confirmed by Bloomberg.com.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> I ran through the numbers myself.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> 300 people have to take the drug for a year  before one heart attack, stroke or other adverse event is prevented.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> Now you're probably thinking,  "Well, OK, one in 300 chance of lowering my cholesterol.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> Why not, doc? Give me the prescription anyway."    </seg>
<seg id="76"> But you should ask at this point for another statistic,  and that is, "Tell me about the side effects." Right?    </seg>
<seg id="77"> So for this particular drug,  the side effects occur in five percent of the patients.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> And they include terrible things --  debilitating muscle and joint pain, gastrointestinal distress --  but now you're thinking, "Five percent,  not very likely it's going to happen to me,  I'll still take the drug."    </seg>
<seg id="79"> But wait a minute.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> Remember under stress you're not thinking clearly.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> So think about how you're going to work through this ahead of time,  so you don't have to manufacture the chain of reasoning on the spot.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> 300 people take the drug, right? One person's helped,  five percent of those 300 have side effects,  that's 15 people.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> You're 15 times more likely to be harmed by the drug  than you are to be helped by the drug.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> Now, I'm not saying whether you should take the statin or not.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> I'm just saying you should have this conversation with your doctor.    </seg>
<seg id="86"> Medical ethics requires it,  it's part of the principle of informed consent.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> You have the right to have access to this kind of information  to begin the conversation about whether you want to take the risks or not.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> Now you might be thinking  I've pulled this number out of the air for shock value,  but in fact it's rather typical, this number needed to treat.    </seg>
<seg id="89"> For the most widely performed surgery on men over the age of 50,  removal of the prostate for cancer,  the number needed to treat is 49.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> That's right, 49 surgeries are done for every one person who's helped.    </seg>
<seg id="91"> And the side effects in that case occur in 50 percent of the patients.    </seg>
<seg id="92"> They include impotence, erectile dysfunction,  urinary incontinence, rectal tearing,  fecal incontinence.    </seg>
<seg id="93"> And if you're lucky, and you're one of the 50 percent who has these,  they'll only last for a year or two.    </seg>
<seg id="94"> So the idea of the pre-mortem is to think ahead of time  to the questions that you might be able to ask  that will push the conversation forward.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> You don't want to have to manufacture all of this on the spot.    </seg>
<seg id="96"> And you also want to think about things like quality of life.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> Because you have a choice oftentimes,  do you I want a shorter life that's pain-free,  or a longer life that might have a great deal of pain towards the end?    </seg>
<seg id="98"> These are things to talk about and think about now,  with your family and your loved ones.    </seg>
<seg id="99"> You might change your mind in the heat of the moment,  but at least you're practiced with this kind of thinking.    </seg>
<seg id="100"> Remember, our brain under stress releases cortisol,  and one of the things that happens at that moment  is a whole bunch on systems shut down.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> There's an evolutionary reason for this.    </seg>
<seg id="102"> Face-to-face with a predator, you don't need your digestive system,  or your libido, or your immune system,  because if you're body is expending metabolism on those things  and you don't react quickly,  you might become the lion's lunch, and then none of those things matter.    </seg>
<seg id="103"> Unfortunately,  one of the things that goes out the window during those times of stress  is rational, logical thinking,  as Danny Kahneman and his colleagues have shown.    </seg>
<seg id="104"> So we need to train ourselves to think ahead  to these kinds of situations.    </seg>
<seg id="105"> I think the important point here is recognizing that all of us are flawed.    </seg>
<seg id="106"> We all are going to fail now and then.    </seg>
<seg id="107"> The idea is to think ahead to what those failures might be,  to put systems in place that will help minimize the damage,  or to prevent the bad things from happening in the first place.    </seg>
<seg id="108"> Getting back to that snowy night in Montreal,  when I got back from my trip,  I had my contractor install a combination lock next to the door,  with a key to the front door in it, an easy to remember combination.    </seg>
<seg id="109"> And I have to admit,  I still have piles of mail that haven't been sorted,  and piles of emails that I haven't gone through.    </seg>
<seg id="110"> So I'm not completely organized,  but I see organization as a gradual process,  and I'm getting there.    </seg>
<seg id="111"> Thank you very much.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2357" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/christine_sun_kim_the_enchanting_music_of_sign_language</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Artist and TED Fellow Christine Sun Kim was born deaf, and she was taught to believe that sound wasn't a part of her life, that it was a hearing person's thing. Through her art, she discovered similarities between American Sign Language and music, and she realized that sound doesn't have to be known solely through the ears -- it can be felt, seen and experienced as an idea. In this endearing talk, she invites us to open our eyes and ears and participate in the rich treasure of visual language.</description> 
<keywords>talks, TED Fellows, art, communication, composing, language, music, sound</keywords> 
<talkid>2357</talkid> 
<title>Christine Sun Kim: The enchanting music of sign language</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> Interpreter: Piano, "p," is my favorite musical symbol.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> It means to play softly.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> If you're playing a musical instrument and you notice a "p" in the score,  you need to play softer.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> Two p's -- even softer.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> Four p's -- extremely soft.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> This is my drawing of a p-tree,  which demonstrates  no matter how many thousands upon thousands of p's there may be,  you'll never reach complete silence.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> That's my current definition of silence:  a very obscure sound.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> I'd like to share a little bit  about the history of American Sign Language, ASL,  plus a bit of my own background.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> French sign language was brought to America during the early 1800s,  and as time went by, mixed with local signs,  it evolved into the language we know today as ASL.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> So it has a history of about 200 years.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> I was born deaf,  and I was taught to believe that sound wasn't a part of my life.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> And I believed it to be true.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> Yet, I realize now that that wasn't the case at all.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> Sound was very much a part of my life,  really, on my mind every day.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> As a Deaf person living in a world of sound,  it's as if I was living in a foreign country,  blindly following its rules, customs, behaviors and norms  without ever questioning them.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> So how is it that I understand sound?    </seg>
<seg id="17"> Well, I watch how people behave and respond to sound.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> You people are like my loudspeakers, and amplify sound.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> I learn and mirror that behavior.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> At the same time, I've learned that I create sound,  and I've seen how people respond to me.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> Thus I've learned, for example ...    </seg>
<seg id="22"> "Don't slam the door!"    </seg>
<seg id="23"> "Don't make too much noise when you're eating from the potato-chip bag!"    </seg>
<seg id="24">   "Don't burp,  and when you're eating,  make sure you don't scrape your utensils on the plate."    </seg>
<seg id="25"> All of these things I term "sound etiquette."    </seg>
<seg id="26"> Maybe I think about sound etiquette  more than the average hearing person does.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> I'm hyper-vigilant around sound.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> And I'm always waiting in eager nervous anticipation  around sound, about what's to come next.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> Hence, this drawing.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> TBD, to be decided.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> TBC, to be continued.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> TBA, to be announced.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> And you notice the staff --  there are no notes contained in the lines.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> That's because the lines already contain sound  through the subtle smudges and smears.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> In Deaf culture, movement is equivalent to sound.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> This is a sign for "staff" in ASL.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> A typical staff contains five lines.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> Yet for me, signing it with my thumb sticking up like that  doesn't feel natural.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> That's why you'll notice in my drawings, I stick to four lines on paper.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> In the year 2008, I had the opportunity to travel to Berlin, Germany,  for an artist residency there.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> Prior to this time, I had been working as a painter.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> During this summer, I visited different museums and gallery spaces,  and as I went from one place to the next,  I noticed there was no visual art there.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> At that time, sound was trending, and this struck me ...    </seg>
<seg id="44"> there was no visual art,  everything was auditory.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> Now sound has come into my art territory.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> Is it going to further distance me from art?    </seg>
<seg id="47"> I realized that doesn't have to be the case at all.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> I actually know sound.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> I know it so well  that it doesn't have to be something just experienced through the ears.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> It could be felt tactually,  or experienced as a visual,  or even as an idea.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> So I decided to reclaim ownership of sound  and to put it into my art practice.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> And everything that I had been taught regarding sound,  I decided to do away with and unlearn.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> I started creating a new body of work.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> And when I presented this to the art community,  I was blown away with the amount of support and attention I received.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> I realized:  sound is like money,  power, control --  social currency.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> In the back of my mind, I've always felt that sound was your thing,  a hearing person's thing.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> And sound is so powerful  that it could either disempower me and my artwork,  or it could empower me.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> I chose to be empowered.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> There's a massive culture around spoken language.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> And just because I don't use my literal voice to communicate,  in society's eyes it's as if I don't have a voice at all.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> So I need to work with individuals who can support me as an equal  and become my voice.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> And that way, I'm able to maintain relevancy in society today.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> So at school, at work and institutions,  I work with many different ASL interpreters.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> And their voice becomes my voice and identity.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> They help me to be heard.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> And their voices hold value and currency.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> Ironically, by borrowing out their voices,  I'm able to maintain a temporary form of currency,  kind of like taking out a loan with a very high interest rate.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> If I didn't continue this practice,  I feel that I could just fade off into oblivion  and not maintain any form of social currency.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> So with sound as my new art medium,  I delved into the world of music.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> And I was surprised to see the similarities between music and ASL.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> For example,  a musical note  cannot be fully captured and expressed on paper.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> And the same holds true for a concept in ASL.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> They're both highly spatial and highly inflected --  meaning that subtle changes  can affect the entire meaning  of both signs and sounds.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> I'd like to share with you a piano metaphor,  to have you have a better understanding of how ASL works.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> So, envision a piano.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> ASL is broken down into many different grammatical parameters.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> If you assign a different parameter to each finger as you play the piano --  such as facial expression, body movement,  speed, hand shape and so on,  as you play the piano --  English is a linear language,  as if one key is being pressed at a time.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> However, ASL is more like a chord --  all 10 fingers need to come down simultaneously  to express a clear concept or idea in ASL.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> If just one of those keys were to change the chord,  it would create a completely different meaning.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> The same applies to music in regards to pitch, tone and volume.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> In ASL, by playing around with these different grammatical parameters,  you can express different ideas.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> For example, take the sign TO-LOOK-AT.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> This is the sign TO-LOOK-AT.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> I'm looking at you.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> Staring at you.    </seg>
<seg id="86">     Oh -- busted.    </seg>
<seg id="87">   Uh-oh.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> What are you looking at?    </seg>
<seg id="89"> Aw, stop.    </seg>
<seg id="90">   I then started thinking,  "What if I was to look at ASL through a musical lens?"    </seg>
<seg id="91"> If I was to create a sign and repeat it over and over,  it could become like a piece of visual music.    </seg>
<seg id="92"> For example, this is the sign for "day,"  as the sun rises and sets.    </seg>
<seg id="93"> This is "all day."    </seg>
<seg id="94"> If I was to repeat it and slow it down,  visually it looks like a piece of music.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> All ... day.    </seg>
<seg id="96"> I feel the same holds true for "all night."    </seg>
<seg id="97"> "All night."    </seg>
<seg id="98"> This is ALL-NIGHT, represented in this drawing.    </seg>
<seg id="99"> And this led me to thinking about three different kinds of nights:  "last night,"  "overnight,"   "all night long."    </seg>
<seg id="100">   I feel like the third one has a lot more musicality than the other two.    </seg>
<seg id="101">   This represents how time is expressed in ASL  and how the distance from your body can express the changes in time.    </seg>
<seg id="102"> For example,  1H is one hand, 2H is two hand,  present tense happens closest and in front of the body,  future is in front of the body and the past is to your back.    </seg>
<seg id="103"> So, the first example is "a long time ago."    </seg>
<seg id="104"> Then "past,"  "used to"  and the last one, which is my favorite,  with the very romantic and dramatic notion to it,  "once upon a time."    </seg>
<seg id="105">   "Common time"  is a musical term  with a specific time signature of four beats per measure.    </seg>
<seg id="106"> Yet when I see the word "common time,"  what automatically comes to mind for me is "at the same time."    </seg>
<seg id="107"> So notice RH: right hand, LH: left hand.    </seg>
<seg id="108"> We have the staff across the head and the chest.    </seg>
<seg id="109"> [Head: RH, Flash claw]  [Common time]  [Chest: LH, Flash claw]  I'm now going to demonstrate a hand shape called the "flash claw."    </seg>
<seg id="110"> Can you please follow along with me?    </seg>
<seg id="111"> Everybody, hands up.    </seg>
<seg id="112"> Now we're going to do it in both the head and the chest,  kind of like "common time" or at the same time.    </seg>
<seg id="113"> Yes, got it.    </seg>
<seg id="114"> That means "to fall in love" in International [Sign].    </seg>
<seg id="115">   International [Sign], as a note,  is a visual tool to help communicate  across cultures and sign languages around the world.    </seg>
<seg id="116"> The second one I'd like to demonstrate is this --  please follow along with me again.    </seg>
<seg id="117"> And now this.    </seg>
<seg id="118"> This is "colonization" in ASL.    </seg>
<seg id="119">   Now the third --  please follow along again.    </seg>
<seg id="120"> And again.    </seg>
<seg id="121"> This is "enlightenment" in ASL.    </seg>
<seg id="122"> So let's do all three together.    </seg>
<seg id="123"> "Fall in love,"  "colonization"  and "enlightenment."    </seg>
<seg id="124"> Good job, everyone.    </seg>
<seg id="125">   Notice how all three signs are very similar,  they all happen at the head and the chest,  but they convey quite different meanings.    </seg>
<seg id="126"> So it's amazing to see how ASL is alive and thriving,  just like music is.    </seg>
<seg id="127"> However, in this day and age,  we live in a very audio-centric world.    </seg>
<seg id="128"> And just because ASL has no sound to it,  it automatically holds no social currency.    </seg>
<seg id="129"> We need to start thinking harder about what defines social currency  and allow ASL to develop its own form of currency --  without sound.    </seg>
<seg id="130"> And this could possibly be a step to lead to a more inclusive society.    </seg>
<seg id="131"> And maybe people will understand  that you don't need to be deaf to learn ASL,  nor do you have to be hearing to learn music.    </seg>
<seg id="132"> ASL is such a rich treasure  that I'd like you to have the same experience.    </seg>
<seg id="133"> And I'd like to invite you to open your ears,  to open your eyes,  take part in our culture  and experience our visual language.    </seg>
<seg id="134"> And you never know,  you might just fall in love with us.    </seg>
<seg id="135">   Thank you.    </seg>
<seg id="136"> Denise Kahler-Braaten: Hey, that's me.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2363" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/cesar_harada_how_i_teach_kids_to_love_science</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: At the Harbour School in Hong Kong, TED Senior Fellow Cesar Harada teaches citizen science and invention to the next generation of environmentalists. He's moved his classroom into an industrial mega-space where imaginative kids work with wood, metal, chemistry, biology, optics and, occasionally, power tools to create solutions to the threats facing the world's oceans. There, he instills a universal lesson that his own parents taught him at a young age: "You can make a mess, but you have to clean up after yourself."</description> 
<keywords>talks, TED Fellows, collaboration, design, education, environment, global issues, green, innovation, invention, oceans, water</keywords> 
<talkid>2363</talkid> 
<title>Cesar Harada: How I teach kids to love science</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> When I was a kid, my parents would tell me,  "You can make a mess, but you have to clean up after yourself."    </seg>
<seg id="2"> So freedom came with responsibility.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> But my imagination would take me to all these wonderful places,  where everything was possible.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> So I grew up in a bubble of innocence --  or a bubble of ignorance, I should say,  because adults would lie to us to protect us from the ugly truth.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> And growing up, I found out that adults make a mess,  and they're not very good at cleaning up after themselves.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> Fast forward, I am an adult now,  and I teach citizen science and invention at the Hong Kong Harbour School.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> And it doesn't take too long  before my students walk on a beach and stumble upon piles of trash.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> So as good citizens, we clean up the beaches --  and no, he is not drinking alcohol, and if he is, I did not give it to him.    </seg>
<seg id="9">   And so it's sad to say,  but today more than 80 percent of the oceans have plastic in them.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> It's a horrifying fact.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> And in past decades,  we've been taking those big ships out and those big nets,  and we collect those plastic bits that we look at under a microscope,  and we sort them,  and then we put this data onto a map.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> But that takes forever, it's very expensive,  and so it's quite risky to take those big boats out.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> So with my students, ages six to 15,  we've been dreaming of inventing a better way.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> So we've transformed our tiny Hong Kong classroom into a workshop.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> And so we started building this small workbench,  with different heights, so even really short kids can participate.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> And let me tell you, kids with power tools are awesome and safe.    </seg>
<seg id="17">   Not really.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> And so, back to plastic.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> We collect this plastic and we grind it to the size we find it in the ocean,  which is very small because it breaks down.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> And so this is how we work.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> I let the imaginations of my students run wild.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> And my job is to try to collect the best of each kid's idea  and try to combine it into something that hopefully would work.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> And so we have agreed that instead of collecting plastic bits,  we are going to collect only the data.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> So we're going to get an image of the plastic with a robot --  so robots, kids get very excited.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> And the next thing we do -- we do what we call "rapid prototyping."    </seg>
<seg id="26"> We are so rapid at prototyping  that the lunch is still in the lunchbox when we're hacking it.    </seg>
<seg id="27">   And we hack table lamps and webcams, into plumbing fixtures  and we assemble that into a floating robot that will be slowly moving through water  and through the plastic that we have there --  and this is the image that we get in the robot.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> So we see the plastic pieces floating slowly through the sensor,  and the computer on board will process this image,  and measure the size of each particle,  so we have a rough estimate of how much plastic there is in the water.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> So we documented this invention step by step  on a website for inventors called Instructables,  in the hope that somebody would make it even better.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> What was really cool about this project was that the students saw a local problem,  and boom -- they are trying to immediately address it.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> [I can investigate my local problem]  But my students in Hong Kong are hyperconnected kids.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> And they watch the news, they watch the Internet,  and they came across this image.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> This was a child, probably under 10, cleaning up an oil spill bare-handed,  in the Sundarbans, which is the world's largest mangrove forest in Bangladesh.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> So they were very shocked,  because this is the water they drink, this is the water they bathe in,  this is the water they fish in -- this is the place where they live.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> And also you can see the water is brown, the mud is brown and oil is brown,  so when everything is mixed up,  it's really hard to see what's in the water.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> But, there's a technology that's rather simple,  that's called spectrometry,  that allows you see what's in the water.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> So we built a rough prototype of a spectrometer,  and you can shine light through different substances  that produce different spectrums,  so that can help you identify what's in the water.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> So we packed this prototype of a sensor,  and we shipped it to Bangladesh.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> So what was cool about this project  was that beyond addressing a local problem,  or looking at a local problem,  my students used their empathy and their sense of being creative  to help, remotely, other kids.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> [I can investigate a remote problem]  So I was very compelled by doing the second experiments,  and I wanted to take it even further --  maybe addressing an even harder problem, and it's also closer to my heart.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> So I'm half Japanese and half French,  and maybe you remember in 2011 there was a massive earthquake in Japan.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> It was so violent that it triggered several giant waves --  they are called tsunami --  and those tsunami destroyed many cities on the eastern coast of Japan.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> More than 14,000 people died in an instant.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> Also, it damaged the nuclear power plant of Fukushima,  the nuclear power plant just by the water.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> And today, I read the reports  and an average of 300 tons  are leaking from the nuclear power plant into the Pacific Ocean.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> And today the whole Pacific Ocean has traces of contamination of cesium-137.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> If you go outside on the West Coast, you can measure Fukushima everywhere.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> But if you look at the map, it can look like most of the radioactivity  has been washed away from the Japanese coast,  and most of it is now -- it looks like it's safe, it's blue.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> Well, reality is a bit more complicated than this.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> So I've been going to Fukushima every year since the accident,  and I measure independently and with other scientists,  on land, in the river --  and this time we wanted to take the kids.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> So of course we didn't take the kids, the parents wouldn't allow that to happen.    </seg>
<seg id="52">   But every night we would report to "Mission Control" --  different masks they're wearing.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> It could look like they didn't take the work seriously, but they really did  because they're going to have to live with radioactivity their whole life.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> And so what we did with them  is that we'd discuss the data we collected that day,  and talk about where we should be going next --  strategy, itinerary, etc...    </seg>
<seg id="55"> And to do this, we built a very rough topographical map  of the region around the nuclear power plant.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> And so we built the elevation map,  we sprinkled pigments to represent real-time data for radioactivity,  and we sprayed water to simulate the rainfall.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> And with this we could see that the radioactive dust  was washing from the top of the mountain into the river system,  and leaking into the ocean.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> So it was a rough estimate.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> But with this in mind, we organized this expedition,  which was the closest civilians have been to the nuclear power plant.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> We are sailing 1.5 kilometers away from the nuclear power plant,  and with the help of the local fisherman,  we are collecting sediment from the seabed  with a custom sediment sampler we've invented and built.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> We pack the sediment into small bags,  we then dispatch them to hundreds of small bags  that we send to different universities,  and we produce the map of the seabed radioactivity,  especially in estuaries where the fish will reproduce,  and I will hope that we will have improved  the safety of the local fishermen and of your favorite sushi.    </seg>
<seg id="62">   You can see a progression here --  we've gone from a local problem to a remote problem to a global problem.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> And it's been super exciting to work at these different scales,  with also very simple, open-source technologies.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> But at the same time, it's been increasingly frustrating  because we have only started to measure the damage that we have done.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> We haven't even started to try to solve the problems.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> And so I wonder if we should just take a leap  and try to invent better ways to do all these things.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> And so the classroom started to feel a little bit small,  so we found an industrial site in Hong Kong,  and we turned it into the largest mega-space  focused on social and environmental impact.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> It's in central Hong Kong,  and it's a place we can work with wood, metal, chemistry,  a bit of biology, a bit of optics,  basically you can build pretty much everything there.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> And its a place where adults and kids can play together.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> It's a place where kids' dreams can come true,  and where adults can be kids again.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> Student: Acceleration! Acceleration!    </seg>
<seg id="72"> Cesar Harada: We're asking questions such as,  can we invent the future of mobility with renewable energy?    </seg>
<seg id="73"> For example.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> by transforming very standard wheelchairs into cool, electric vehicles?    </seg>
<seg id="75"> So plastic, oil and radioactivity are horrible, horrible legacies,  but the very worst legacy that we can leave our children is lies.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> We can no longer afford to shield the kids from the ugly truth  because we need their imagination to invent the solutions.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> So citizen scientists, makers, dreamers --  we must prepare the next generation  that cares about the environment and people,  and that can actually do something about it.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2344" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/neri_oxman_design_at_the_intersection_of_technology_and_biology</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Designer and architect Neri Oxman is leading the search for ways in which digital fabrication technologies can interact with the biological world. Working at the intersection of computational design, additive manufacturing, materials engineering and synthetic biology, her lab is pioneering a new age of symbiosis between microorganisms, our bodies, our products and even our buildings.</description> 
<keywords>talks, architecture, biology, design, innovation, materials, microbiology, nature, product design, technology</keywords> 
<talkid>2344</talkid> 
<title>Neri Oxman: Design at the intersection of technology and biology</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> Two twin domes,  two radically opposed design cultures.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> One is made of thousands of steel parts,  the other of a single silk thread.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> One is synthetic, the other organic.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> One is imposed on the environment,  the other creates it.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> One is designed for nature, the other is designed by her.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> Michelangelo said that when he looked at raw marble,  he saw a figure struggling to be free.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> The chisel was Michelangelo's only tool.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> But living things are not chiseled.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> They grow.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> And in our smallest units of life, our cells, we carry all the information  that's required for every other cell to function and to replicate.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> Tools also have consequences.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> At least since the Industrial Revolution, the world of design has been dominated  by the rigors of manufacturing and mass production.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> Assembly lines have dictated a world made of parts,  framing the imagination of designers and architects  who have been trained to think about their objects as assemblies  of discrete parts with distinct functions.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> But you don't find homogenous material assemblies in nature.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> Take human skin, for example.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> Our facial skins are thin with large pores.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> Our back skins are thicker, with small pores.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> One acts mainly as filter,  the other mainly as barrier,  and yet it's the same skin: no parts, no assemblies.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> It's a system that gradually varies its functionality  by varying elasticity.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> So here this is a split screen to represent my split world view,  the split personality of every designer and architect operating today  between the chisel and the gene,  between machine and organism, between assembly and growth,  between Henry Ford and Charles Darwin.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> These two worldviews, my left brain and right brain,  analysis and synthesis, will play out on the two screens behind me.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> My work, at its simplest level,  is about uniting these two worldviews,  moving away from assembly  and closer into growth.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> You're probably asking yourselves:  Why now?    </seg>
<seg id="24"> Why was this not possible 10 or even five years ago?    </seg>
<seg id="25"> We live in a very special time in history,  a rare time,  a time when the confluence of four fields is giving designers access to tools  we've never had access to before.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> These fields are computational design,  allowing us to design complex forms with simple code;  additive manufacturing, letting us produce parts  by adding material rather than carving it out;  materials engineering, which lets us design the behavior of materials  in high resolution;  and synthetic biology,  enabling us to design new biological functionality by editing DNA.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> And at the intersection of these four fields,  my team and I create.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> Please meet the minds and hands  of my students.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> We design objects and products and structures and tools across scales,  from the large-scale,  like this robotic arm with an 80-foot diameter reach  with a vehicular base that will one day soon print entire buildings,  to nanoscale graphics made entirely of genetically engineered microorganisms  that glow in the dark.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> Here we've reimagined the mashrabiya,  an archetype of ancient Arabic architecture,  and created a screen where every aperture is uniquely sized  to shape the form of light and heat moving through it.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> In our next project,  we explore the possibility of creating a cape and skirt --  this was for a Paris fashion show with Iris van Herpen --  like a second skin that are made of a single part,  stiff at the contours, flexible around the waist.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> Together with my long-term 3D printing collaborator Stratasys,  we 3D-printed this cape and skirt with no seams between the cells,  and I'll show more objects like it.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> This helmet combines stiff and soft materials  in 20-micron resolution.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> This is the resolution of a human hair.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> It's also the resolution of a CT scanner.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> That designers have access  to such high-resolution analytic and synthetic tools,  enables to design products that fit not only the shape of our bodies,  but also the physiological makeup of our tissues.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> Next, we designed an acoustic chair,  a chair that would be at once structural, comfortable  and would also absorb sound.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> Professor Carter, my collaborator, and I turned to nature for inspiration,  and by designing this irregular surface pattern,  it becomes sound-absorbent.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> We printed its surface out of 44 different properties,  varying in rigidity, opacity and color,  corresponding to pressure points on the human body.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> Its surface, as in nature, varies its functionality  not by adding another material or another assembly,  but by continuously and delicately varying material property.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> But is nature ideal?    </seg>
<seg id="42"> Are there no parts in nature?    </seg>
<seg id="43"> I wasn't raised in a religious Jewish home,  but when I was young,  my grandmother used to tell me stories from the Hebrew Bible,  and one of them stuck with me and came to define much of what I care about.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> As she recounts:  "On the third day of Creation, God commands the Earth  to grow a fruit-bearing fruit tree."    </seg>
<seg id="45"> For this first fruit tree, there was to be no differentiation  between trunk, branches, leaves and fruit.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> The whole tree was a fruit.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> Instead, the land grew trees that have bark and stems and flowers.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> The land created a world made of parts.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> I often ask myself,  "What would design be like if objects were made of a single part?    </seg>
<seg id="50"> Would we return to a better state of creation?"    </seg>
<seg id="51"> So we looked for that biblical material,  that fruit-bearing fruit tree kind of material, and we found it.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> The second-most abundant biopolymer on the planet is called chitin,  and some 100 million tons of it are produced every year  by organisms such as shrimps, crabs, scorpions and butterflies.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> We thought if we could tune its properties,  we could generate structures that are multifunctional  out of a single part.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> So that's what we did.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> We called Legal Seafood --    we ordered a bunch of shrimp shells,  we grinded them and we produced chitosan paste.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> By varying chemical concentrations,  we were able to achieve a wide array of properties --  from dark, stiff and opaque,  to light, soft and transparent.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> In order to print the structures in large scale,  we built a robotically controlled extrusion system with multiple nozzles.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> The robot would vary material properties on the fly  and create these 12-foot-long structures made of a single material,  100 percent recyclable.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> When the parts are ready, they're left to dry  and find a form naturally upon contact with air.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> So why are we still designing with plastics?    </seg>
<seg id="61"> The air bubbles that were a byproduct of the printing process  were used to contain photosynthetic microorganisms  that first appeared on our planet 3.5 billion year ago,  as we learned yesterday.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> Together with our collaborators at Harvard and MIT,  we embedded bacteria that were genetically engineered  to rapidly capture carbon from the atmosphere  and convert it into sugar.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> For the first time,  we were able to generate structures that would seamlessly transition  from beam to mesh,  and if scaled even larger, to windows.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> A fruit-bearing fruit tree.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> Working with an ancient material,  one of the first lifeforms on the planet,  plenty of water and a little bit of synthetic biology,  we were able to transform a structure made of shrimp shells  into an architecture that behaves like a tree.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> And here's the best part:  for objects designed to biodegrade,  put them in the sea, and they will nourish marine life;  place them in soil, and they will help grow a tree.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> The setting for our next exploration using the same design principles  was the solar system.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> We looked for the possibility of creating life-sustaining clothing  for interplanetary voyages.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> To do that, we needed to contain bacteria and be able to control their flow.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> So like the periodic table, we came up with our own table of the elements:  new lifeforms that were computationally grown,  and biologically augmented.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> I like to think of synthetic biology as liquid alchemy,  only instead of transmuting precious metals,  you're synthesizing new biological functionality inside very small channels.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> It's called microfluidics.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> We 3D-printed our own channels in order to control the flow  of these liquid bacterial cultures.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> In our first piece of clothing, we combined two microorganisms.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> The first is cyanobacteria.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> It lives in our oceans and in freshwater ponds.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> And the second, E. coli, the bacterium that inhabits the human gut.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> One converts light into sugar, the other consumes that sugar  and produces biofuels useful for the built environment.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> Now, these two microorganisms never interact in nature.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> In fact, they never met each other.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> They've been here, engineered for the first time,  to have a relationship inside a piece of clothing.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> Think of it as evolution not by natural selection,  but evolution by design.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> In order to contain these relationships,  we've created a single channel that resembles the digestive tract,  that will help flow these bacteria and alter their function along the way.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> We then started growing these channels on the human body,  varying material properties according to the desired functionality.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> Where we wanted more photosynthesis, we would design more transparent channels.    </seg>
<seg id="86"> This wearable digestive system, when it's stretched end to end,  spans 60 meters.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> This is half the length of a football field,  and 10 times as long as our small intestines.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> And here it is for the first time unveiled at TED --  our first photosynthetic wearable,  liquid channels glowing with life inside a wearable clothing.    </seg>
<seg id="89">   Thank you.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> Mary Shelley said, "We are unfashioned creatures, but only half made up."    </seg>
<seg id="91"> What if design could provide that other half?    </seg>
<seg id="92"> What if we could create structures that would augment living matter?    </seg>
<seg id="93"> What if we could create personal microbiomes  that would scan our skins, repair damaged tissue  and sustain our bodies?    </seg>
<seg id="94"> Think of this as a form of edited biology.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> This entire collection, Wanderers, that was named after planets,  was not to me really about fashion per se,  but it provided an opportunity to speculate about the future  of our race on our planet and beyond,  to combine scientific insight with lots of mystery  and to move away from the age of the machine  to a new age of symbiosis between our bodies,  the microorganisms that we inhabit,  our products and even our buildings.    </seg>
<seg id="96"> I call this material ecology.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> To do this, we always need to return back to nature.    </seg>
<seg id="98"> By now, you know that a 3D printer prints material in layers.    </seg>
<seg id="99"> You also know that nature doesn't.    </seg>
<seg id="100"> It grows. It adds with sophistication.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> This silkworm cocoon, for example,  creates a highly sophisticated architecture,  a home inside which to metamorphisize.    </seg>
<seg id="102"> No additive manufacturing today gets even close to this level of sophistication.    </seg>
<seg id="103"> It does so by combining not two materials,  but two proteins in different concentrations.    </seg>
<seg id="104"> One acts as the structure, the other is the glue, or the matrix,  holding those fibers together.    </seg>
<seg id="105"> And this happens across scales.    </seg>
<seg id="106"> The silkworm first attaches itself to the environment --  it creates a tensile structure --  and it then starts spinning a compressive cocoon.    </seg>
<seg id="107"> Tension and compression, the two forces of life,  manifested in a single material.    </seg>
<seg id="108"> In order to better understand how this complex process works,  we glued a tiny earth magnet  to the head of a silkworm, to the spinneret.    </seg>
<seg id="109"> We placed it inside a box with magnetic sensors,  and that allowed us to create this 3-dimensional point cloud  and visualize the complex architecture of the silkworm cocoon.    </seg>
<seg id="110"> However, when we placed the silkworm on a flat patch,  not inside a box,  we realized it would spin a flat cocoon  and it would still healthily metamorphisize.    </seg>
<seg id="111"> So we started designing different environments, different scaffolds,  and we discovered that the shape, the composition,  the structure of the cocoon, was directly informed by the environment.    </seg>
<seg id="112"> Silkworms are often boiled to death inside their cocoons,  their silk unraveled and used in the textile industry.    </seg>
<seg id="113"> We realized that designing these templates allowed us to give shape to raw silk  without boiling a single cocoon.    </seg>
<seg id="114">   They would healthily metamorphisize,  and we would be able to create these things.    </seg>
<seg id="115"> So we scaled this process up to architectural scale.    </seg>
<seg id="116"> We had a robot spin the template out of silk,  and we placed it on our site.    </seg>
<seg id="117"> We knew silkworms migrated toward darker and colder areas,  so we used a sun path diagram to reveal the distribution  of light and heat on our structure.    </seg>
<seg id="118"> We then created holes, or apertures,  that would lock in the rays of light and heat,  distributing those silkworms on the structure.    </seg>
<seg id="119"> We were ready to receive the caterpillars.    </seg>
<seg id="120"> We ordered 6,500 silkworms from an online silk farm.    </seg>
<seg id="121"> And after four weeks of feeding, they were ready to spin with us.    </seg>
<seg id="122"> We placed them carefully at the bottom rim of the scaffold,  and as they spin they pupate, they mate, they lay eggs,  and life begins all over again -- just like us but much, much shorter.    </seg>
<seg id="123"> Bucky Fuller said that tension is the great integrity,  and he was right.    </seg>
<seg id="124"> As they spin biological silk over robotically spun silk,  they give this entire pavilion its integrity.    </seg>
<seg id="125"> And over two to three weeks,  6,500 silkworms spin 6,500 kilometers.    </seg>
<seg id="126"> In a curious symmetry, this is also the length of the Silk Road.    </seg>
<seg id="127"> The moths, after they hatch, produce 1.5 million eggs.    </seg>
<seg id="128"> This could be used for 250 additional pavilions for the future.    </seg>
<seg id="129"> So here they are, the two worldviews.    </seg>
<seg id="130"> One spins silk out of a robotic arm,  the other fills in the gaps.    </seg>
<seg id="131"> If the final frontier of design is to breathe life into the products  and the buildings around us,  to form a two-material ecology,  then designers must unite these two worldviews.    </seg>
<seg id="132"> Which brings us back, of course, to the beginning.    </seg>
<seg id="133"> Here's to a new age of design, a new age of creation,  that takes us from a nature-inspired design  to a design-inspired nature,  and that demands of us for the first time  that we mother nature.    </seg>
<seg id="134"> Thank you.    </seg>
<seg id="135">   Thank you very much. Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2341" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/emilie_wapnick_why_some_of_us_don_t_have_one_true_calling</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: What do you want to be when you grow up? Well, if you're not sure you want to do just one thing for the rest of your life, you're not alone. In this illuminating talk, writer and artist Emilie Wapnick describes the kind of people she calls "multipotentialites" -- who have a range of interests and jobs over one lifetime. Are you one?</description> 
<keywords>talks, TEDx, creativity, curiosity, education, identity, personal growth, work</keywords> 
<talkid>2341</talkid> 
<title>Emilie Wapnick: Why some of us don't have one true calling</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> Raise your hand if you've ever been asked the question  "What do you want to be when you grow up?"    </seg>
<seg id="2"> Now if you had to guess,  how old would you say you were when you were first asked this question?    </seg>
<seg id="3"> You can just hold up fingers.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> Three. Five. Three. Five. Five. OK.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> Now, raise your hand if the question  "What do you want to be when you grow up?"    </seg>
<seg id="6"> has ever caused you any anxiety.    </seg>
<seg id="7">   Any anxiety at all.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> I'm someone who's never been able to answer the question  "What do you want to be when you grow up?"    </seg>
<seg id="9"> See, the problem wasn't that I didn't have any interests --  it's that I had too many.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> In high school, I liked English and math and art and I built websites  and I played guitar in a punk band called Frustrated Telephone Operator.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> Maybe you've heard of us.    </seg>
<seg id="12">   This continued after high school,  and at a certain point, I began to notice this pattern in myself  where I would become interested in an area  and I would dive in, become all-consumed,  and I'd get to be pretty good at whatever it was,  and then I would hit this point where I'd start to get bored.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> And usually I would try and persist anyway,  because I had already devoted so much time and energy  and sometimes money into this field.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> But eventually this sense of boredom,  this feeling of, like, yeah, I got this, this isn't challenging anymore --  it would get to be too much.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> And I would have to let it go.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> But then I would become interested in something else,  something totally unrelated, and I would dive into that,  and become all-consumed, and I'd be like, "Yes! I found my thing,"  and then I would hit this point again where I'd start to get bored.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> And eventually, I would let it go.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> But then I would discover something new and totally different,  and I would dive into that.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> This pattern caused me a lot of anxiety,  for two reasons.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> The first was that I wasn't sure  how I was going to turn any of this into a career.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> I thought that I would eventually have to pick one thing,  deny all of my other passions,  and just resign myself to being bored.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> The other reason it caused me so much anxiety  was a little bit more personal.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> I worried that there was something wrong with this,  and something wrong with me for being unable to stick with anything.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> I worried that I was afraid of commitment,  or that I was scattered, or that I was self-sabotaging,  afraid of my own success.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> If you can relate to my story and to these feelings,  I'd like you to ask yourself a question  that I wish I had asked myself back then.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> Ask yourself where you learned to assign the meaning of wrong or abnormal  to doing many things.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> I'll tell you where you learned it:  you learned it from the culture.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> We are first asked the question "What do you want to be when you grow up?"    </seg>
<seg id="29"> when we're about five years old.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> And the truth is that no one really cares what you say when you're that age.    </seg>
<seg id="31">   It's considered an innocuous question,  posed to little kids to elicit cute replies,  like, "I want to be an astronaut," or "I want to be a ballerina,"  or "I want to be a pirate."    </seg>
<seg id="32"> Insert Halloween costume here.    </seg>
<seg id="33">   But this question gets asked of us again and again as we get older  in various forms -- for instance, high school students might get asked  what major they're going to pick in college.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> And at some point,  "What do you want to be when you grow up?"    </seg>
<seg id="35"> goes from being the cute exercise it once was  to the thing that keeps us up at night.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> Why?    </seg>
<seg id="37"> See, while this question inspires kids to dream about what they could be,  it does not inspire them to dream about all that they could be.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> In fact, it does just the opposite,  because when someone asks you what you want to be,  you can't reply with 20 different things,  though well-meaning adults will likely chuckle and be like,  "Oh, how cute, but you can't be a violin maker and a psychologist.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> You have to choose."    </seg>
<seg id="40"> This is Dr. Bob Childs --    and he's a luthier and psychotherapist.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> And this is Amy Ng, a magazine editor turned illustrator, entrepreneur,  teacher and creative director.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> But most kids don't hear about people like this.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> All they hear  is that they're going to have to choose.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> But it's more than that.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> The notion of the narrowly focused life  is highly romanticized in our culture.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> It's this idea of destiny or the one true calling,  the idea that we each have one great thing  we are meant to do during our time on this earth,  and you need to figure out what that thing is  and devote your life to it.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> But what if you're someone who isn't wired this way?    </seg>
<seg id="48"> What if there are a lot of different subjects that you're curious about,  and many different things you want to do?    </seg>
<seg id="49"> Well, there is no room for someone like you in this framework.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> And so you might feel alone.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> You might feel like you don't have a purpose.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> And you might feel like there's something wrong with you.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> There's nothing wrong with you.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> What you are is a multipotentialite.    </seg>
<seg id="55">     A multipotentialite is someone with many interests and creative pursuits.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> It's a mouthful to say.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> It might help if you break it up into three parts:  multi, potential, and ite.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> You can also use one of the other terms that connote the same idea,  such as polymath, the Renaissance person.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> Actually, during the Renaissance period,  it was considered the ideal to be well-versed in multiple disciplines.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> Barbara Sher refers to us as "scanners."    </seg>
<seg id="61"> Use whichever term you like, or invent your own.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> I have to say I find it sort of fitting that as a community,  we cannot agree on a single identity.    </seg>
<seg id="63">   It's easy to see your multipotentiality  as a limitation or an affliction that you need to overcome.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> But what I've learned through speaking with people  and writing about these ideas on my website,  is that there are some tremendous strengths to being this way.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> Here are three  multipotentialite super powers.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> One: idea synthesis.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> That is, combining two or more fields  and creating something new at the intersection.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> Sha Hwang and Rachel Binx drew from their shared interests  in cartography, data visualization, travel, mathematics and design,  when they founded Meshu.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> Meshu is a company that creates custom geographically-inspired jewelry.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> Sha and Rachel came up with this unique idea  not despite, but because of their eclectic mix of skills and experiences.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> Innovation happens at the intersections.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> That's where the new ideas come from.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> And multipotentialites, with all of their backgrounds,  are able to access a lot of these points of intersection.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> The second multipotentialite superpower  is rapid learning.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> When multipotentialites become interested in something,  we go hard.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> We observe everything we can get our hands on.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> We're also used to being beginners,  because we've been beginners so many times in the past,  and this means that we're less afraid of trying new things  and stepping out of our comfort zones.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> What's more, many skills are transferable across disciplines,  and we bring everything we've learned to every new area we pursue,  so we're rarely starting from scratch.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> Nora Dunn is a full-time traveler and freelance writer.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> As a child concert pianist, she honed an incredible ability  to develop muscle memory.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> Now, she's the fastest typist she knows.    </seg>
<seg id="82">   Before becoming a writer, Nora was a financial planner.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> She had to learn the finer mechanics of sales  when she was starting her practice,  and this skill now helps her write compelling pitches to editors.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> It is rarely a waste of time to pursue something you're drawn to,  even if you end up quitting.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> You might apply that knowledge in a different field entirely,  in a way that you couldn't have anticipated.    </seg>
<seg id="86"> The third multipotentialite superpower  is adaptability;  that is, the ability to morph into whatever you need to be  in a given situation.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> Abe Cajudo is sometimes a video director, sometimes a web designer,  sometimes a Kickstarter consultant, sometimes a teacher,  and sometimes, apparently, James Bond.    </seg>
<seg id="88">   He's valuable because he does good work.    </seg>
<seg id="89"> He's even more valuable because he can take on various roles,  depending on his clients' needs.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> Fast Company magazine identified adaptability  as the single most important skill to develop in order to thrive  in the 21st century.    </seg>
<seg id="91"> The economic world is changing so quickly and unpredictably  that it is the individuals and organizations that can pivot  in order to meet the needs of the market that are really going to thrive.    </seg>
<seg id="92"> Idea synthesis, rapid learning and adaptability:  three skills that multipotentialites are very adept at,  and three skills that they might lose if pressured to narrow their focus.    </seg>
<seg id="93"> As a society, we have a vested interest in encouraging multipotentialites  to be themselves.    </seg>
<seg id="94"> We have a lot of complex, multidimensional problems in the world right now,  and we need creative, out-of-the-box thinkers to tackle them.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> Now, let's say that you are, in your heart, a specialist.    </seg>
<seg id="96"> You came out of the womb knowing you wanted to be a pediatric neurosurgeon.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> Don't worry -- there's nothing wrong with you, either.    </seg>
<seg id="98">   In fact, some of the best teams are comprised of a specialist  and multipotentialite paired together.    </seg>
<seg id="99"> The specialist can dive in deep and implement ideas,  while the multipotentialite brings a breadth of knowledge to the project.    </seg>
<seg id="100"> It's a beautiful partnership.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> But we should all be designing lives and careers  that are aligned with how we're wired.    </seg>
<seg id="102"> And sadly, multipotentialites are largely being encouraged  simply to be more like their specialist peers.    </seg>
<seg id="103"> So with that said,  if there is one thing you take away from this talk,  I hope that it is this:  embrace your inner wiring, whatever that may be.    </seg>
<seg id="104"> If you're a specialist at heart,  then by all means, specialize.    </seg>
<seg id="105"> That is where you'll do your best work.    </seg>
<seg id="106"> But to the multipotentialites in the room,  including those of you who may have just realized  in the last 12 minutes that you are one --    to you I say:  embrace your many passions.    </seg>
<seg id="107"> Follow your curiosity down those rabbit holes.    </seg>
<seg id="108"> Explore your intersections.    </seg>
<seg id="109"> Embracing our inner wiring leads to a happier, more authentic life.    </seg>
<seg id="110"> And perhaps more importantly --  multipotentialites, the world needs us.    </seg>
<seg id="111"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2340" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/samuel_cohen_alzheimer_s_is_not_normal_aging_and_we_can_cure_it</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: More than 40 million people worldwide suffer from Alzheimer's disease, and that number is expected to increase drastically in the coming years. But no real progress has been made in the fight against the disease since its classification more than 100 years ago. Scientist Samuel Cohen shares a new breakthrough in Alzheimer's research from his lab as well as a message of hope. "Alzheimer's is a disease," Cohen says, "and we can cure it."</description> 
<keywords>talks, aging, health, medical research, medicine, neuroscience</keywords> 
<talkid>2340</talkid> 
<title>Samuel Cohen: Alzheimer's is not normal aging  and we can cure it</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> In the year 1901,  a woman called Auguste was taken to a medical asylum in Frankfurt.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> Auguste was delusional  and couldn't remember even the most basic details of her life.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> Her doctor was called Alois.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> Alois didn't know how to help Auguste,  but he watched over her until, sadly, she passed away in 1906.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> After she died, Alois performed an autopsy  and found strange plaques and tangles in Auguste's brain --  the likes of which he'd never seen before.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> Now here's the even more striking thing.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> If Auguste had instead been alive today,  we could offer her no more help than Alois was able to 114 years ago.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> Alois was Dr. Alois Alzheimer.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> And Auguste Deter  was the first patient to be diagnosed with what we now call Alzheimer's disease.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> Since 1901, medicine has advanced greatly.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> We've discovered antibiotics and vaccines to protect us from infections,  many treatments for cancer, antiretrovirals for HIV,  statins for heart disease and much more.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> But we've made essentially no progress at all in treating Alzheimer's disease.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> I'm part of a team of scientists  who has been working to find a cure for Alzheimer's for over a decade.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> So I think about this all the time.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> Alzheimer's now affects 40 million people worldwide.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> But by 2050, it will affect 150 million people --  which, by the way, will include many of you.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> If you're hoping to live to be 85 or older,  your chance of getting Alzheimer's will be almost one in two.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> In other words, odds are you'll spend your golden years  either suffering from Alzheimer's  or helping to look after a friend or loved one with Alzheimer's.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> Already in the United States alone,  Alzheimer's care costs 200 billion dollars every year.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> One out of every five Medicare dollars get spent on Alzheimer's.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> It is today the most expensive disease,  and costs are projected to increase fivefold by 2050,  as the baby boomer generation ages.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> It may surprise you that, put simply,  Alzheimer's is one of the biggest medical and social challenges of our generation.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> But we've done relatively little to address it.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> Today, of the top 10 causes of death worldwide,  Alzheimer's is the only one we cannot prevent, cure or even slow down.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> We understand less about the science of Alzheimer's than other diseases  because we've invested less time and money into researching it.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> The US government spends 10 times more every year  on cancer research than on Alzheimer's  despite the fact that Alzheimer's costs us more  and causes a similar number of deaths each year as cancer.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> The lack of resources stems from a more fundamental cause:  a lack of awareness.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> Because here's what few people know but everyone should:  Alzheimer's is a disease, and we can cure it.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> For most of the past 114 years,  everyone, including scientists, mistakenly confused Alzheimer's with aging.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> We thought that becoming senile  was a normal and inevitable part of getting old.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> But we only have to look at a picture  of a healthy aged brain compared to the brain of an Alzheimer's patient  to see the real physical damage caused by this disease.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> As well as triggering severe loss of memory and mental abilities,  the damage to the brain caused by Alzheimer's  significantly reduces life expectancy and is always fatal.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> Remember Dr. Alzheimer found strange plaques and tangles  in Auguste's brain a century ago.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> For almost a century, we didn't know much about these.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> Today we know they're made from protein molecules.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> You can imagine a protein molecule  as a piece of paper that normally folds into an elaborate piece of origami.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> There are spots on the paper that are sticky.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> And when it folds correctly, these sticky bits end up on the inside.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> But sometimes things go wrong, and some sticky bits are on the outside.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> This causes the protein molecules to stick to each other,  forming clumps that eventually become large plaques and tangles.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> That's what we see in the brains of Alzheimer's patients.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> We've spent the past 10 years at the University of Cambridge  trying to understand how this malfunction works.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> There are many steps, and identifying which step to try to block is complex --  like defusing a bomb.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> Cutting one wire might do nothing.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> Cutting others might make the bomb explore.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> We have to find the right step to block,  and then create a drug that does it.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> Until recently, we for the most part  have been cutting wires and hoping for the best.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> But now we've got together a diverse group of people --  medics, biologists, geneticists, chemists, physicists, engineers and mathematicians.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> And together, we've managed to identify a critical step in the process  and are now testing a new class of drugs which would specifically block this step  and stop the disease.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> Now let me show you some of our latest results.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> No one outside of our lab has seen these yet.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> Let's look at some videos of what happened when we tested these new drugs in worms.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> So these are healthy worms,  and you can see they're moving around normally.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> These worms, on the other hand,  have protein molecules sticking together inside them --  like humans with Alzheimer's.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> And you can see they're clearly sick.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> But if we give our new drugs to these worms at an early stage,  then we see that they're healthy, and they live a normal lifespan.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> This is just an initial positive result, but research like this  shows us that Alzheimer's is a disease that we can understand and we can cure.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> After 114 years of waiting,  there's finally real hope for what can be achieved  in the next 10 or 20 years.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> But to grow that hope, to finally beat Alzheimer's, we need help.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> This isn't about scientists like me --  it's about you.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> We need you to raise awareness that Alzheimer's is a disease  and that if we try, we can beat it.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> In the case of other diseases,  patients and their families have led the charge for more research  and put pressure on governments, the pharmaceutical industry,  scientists and regulators.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> That was essential for advancing treatment for HIV in the late 1980s.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> Today, we see that same drive to beat cancer.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> But Alzheimer's patients are often unable to speak up for themselves.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> And their families, the hidden victims, caring for their loved ones night and day,  are often too worn out to go out and advocate for change.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> So, it really is down to you.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> Alzheimer's isn't, for the most part, a genetic disease.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> Everyone with a brain is at risk.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> Today, there are 40 million patients like Auguste,  who can't create the change they need for themselves.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> Help speak up for them,  and help demand a cure.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2330" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/mandy_len_catron_falling_in_love_is_the_easy_part</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Did you know you can fall in love with anyone just by asking them 36 questions? Mandy Len Catron tried this experiment, it worked, and she wrote a viral article about it . But  is that real love? Did it last? And whats the difference between falling in love and staying in love?</description> 
<keywords>talks, TEDx, love, media, writing</keywords> 
<talkid>2330</talkid> 
<title>Mandy Len Catron: Falling in love is the easy part</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> I published this article  in the New York Times Modern Love column in January of this year.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> "To Fall in Love With Anyone, Do This."    </seg>
<seg id="3"> And the article is about a psychological study  designed to create romantic love in the laboratory,  and my own experience trying the study myself  one night last summer.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> So the procedure is fairly simple:  two strangers take turns asking each other 36 increasingly personal questions  and then they stare into each other's eyes  without speaking for four minutes.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> So here are a couple of sample questions.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> Number 12: If you could wake up tomorrow having gained any one quality or ability,  what would it be?    </seg>
<seg id="7"> Number 28: When did you last cry in front of another person?    </seg>
<seg id="8"> By yourself?    </seg>
<seg id="9"> As you can see, they really do get more personal as they go along.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> Number 30, I really like this one:  Tell your partner what you like about them;  be very honest this time,  saying things you might not say to someone you just met.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> So when I first came across this study a few years earlier,  one detail really stuck out to me,  and that was the rumor that two of the participants  had gotten married six months later,  and they'd invited the entire lab to the ceremony.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> So I was of course very skeptical  about this process of just manufacturing romantic love,  but of course I was intrigued.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> And when I got the chance to try this study myself,  with someone I knew but not particularly well,  I wasn't expecting to fall in love.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> But then we did, and --    And I thought it made a good story, so I sent it to the Modern Love column  a few months later.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> Now, this was published in January,  and now it is August,  so I'm guessing that some of you are probably wondering,  are we still together?    </seg>
<seg id="16"> And the reason I think you might be wondering this  is because I have been asked this question  again and again and again for the past seven months.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> And this question is really what I want to talk about today.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> But let's come back to it.    </seg>
<seg id="19">   So the week before the article came out,  I was very nervous.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> I had been working on a book about love stories  for the past few years,  so I had gotten used to writing about my own experiences  with romantic love on my blog.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> But a blog post might get a couple hundred views at the most,  and those were usually just my Facebook friends,  and I figured my article in the New York Times  would probably get a few thousand views.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> And that felt like a lot of attention  on a relatively new relationship.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> But as it turned out, I had no idea.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> So the article was published online  on a Friday evening,  and by Saturday, this had happened to the traffic on my blog.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> And by Sunday, both the Today Show and Good Morning America had called.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> Within a month, the article would receive over 8 million views,  and I was, to say the least,  underprepared for this sort of attention.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> It's one thing to work up the confidence to write honestly  about your experiences with love,  but it is another thing to discover  that your love life has made international news --    and to realize that people across the world  are genuinely invested in the status of your new relationship.    </seg>
<seg id="28">   And when people called or emailed, which they did every day for weeks,  they always asked the same question first:  are you guys still together?    </seg>
<seg id="29"> In fact, as I was preparing this talk,  I did a quick search of my email inbox  for the phrase "Are you still together?"    </seg>
<seg id="30"> and several messages popped up immediately.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> They were from students and journalists  and friendly strangers like this one.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> I did radio interviews and they asked.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> I even gave a talk, and one woman shouted up to the stage,  "Hey Mandy, where's your boyfriend?"    </seg>
<seg id="34"> And I promptly turned bright red.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> I understand that this is part of the deal.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> If you write about your relationship in an international newspaper,  you should expect people to feel comfortable asking about it.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> But I just wasn't prepared for the scope of the response.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> The 36 questions seem to have taken on a life of their own.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> In fact, the New York Times published a follow-up article  for Valentine's Day,  which featured readers' experiences of trying the study themselves,  with varying degrees of success.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> So my first impulse in the face of all of this attention  was to become very protective of my own relationship.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> I said no to every request for the two of us  to do a media appearance together.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> I turned down TV interviews,  and I said no to every request for photos of the two us.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> I think I was afraid that we would become  inadvertent icons for the process of falling in love,  a position I did not at all feel qualified for.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> And I get it:  people didn't just want to know if the study worked,  they wanted to know if it really worked:  that is, if it was capable of producing love that would last,  not just a fling, but real love, sustainable love.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> But this was a question I didn't feel capable of answering.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> My own relationship was only a few months old,  and I felt like people were asking the wrong question in the first place.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> What would knowing whether or not we were still together really tell them?    </seg>
<seg id="48"> If the answer was no,  would it make the experience of doing these 36 questions  any less worthwhile?    </seg>
<seg id="49"> Dr. Arthur Aron first wrote about these questions  in this study here in 1997,  and here, the researcher's goal was not to produce romantic love.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> Instead, they wanted to foster  interpersonal closeness among college students,  by using what Aron called  "sustained, escalating, reciprocal, personalistic self-disclosure."    </seg>
<seg id="51"> Sounds romantic, doesn't it?    </seg>
<seg id="52"> But the study did work.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> The participants did feel closer after doing it,  and several subsequent studies have also used Aron's fast friends protocol  as a way to quickly create trust and intimacy between strangers.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> They've used it between members of the police and members of community,  and they've used it between people of opposing political ideologies.    </seg>
<seg id="55"> The original version of the story,  the one that I tried last summer,  that pairs the personal questions with four minutes of eye contact,  was referenced in this article,  but unfortunately it was never published.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> So a few months ago, I was giving a talk  at a small liberal arts college,  and a student came up to me afterwards  and he said, kind of shyly,  "So, I tried your study, and it didn't work."    </seg>
<seg id="57"> He seemed a little mystified by this.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> "You mean, you didn't fall in love with the person you did it with?" I asked.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> "Well..." He paused.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> "I think she just wants to be friends."    </seg>
<seg id="61"> "But did you become better friends?" I asked.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> "Did you feel like you got to really know each other after doing the study?"    </seg>
<seg id="63"> He nodded.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> "So, then it worked," I said.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> I don't think this is the answer he was looking for.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> In fact, I don't think this is the answer that any of us are looking for  when it comes to love.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> I first came across this study  when I was 29  and I was going through a really difficult breakup.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> I had been in the relationship since I was 20,  which was basically my entire adult life,  and he was my first real love,  and I had no idea how or if I could make a life without him.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> So I turned to science.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> I researched everything I could find about the science of romantic love,  and I think I was hoping that it might somehow inoculate me from heartache.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> I don't know if I realized this at the time --  I thought I was just doing research for this book I was writing --  but it seems really obvious in retrospect.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> I hoped that if I armed myself with the knowledge of romantic love,  I might never have to feel as terrible and lonely as I did then.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> And all this knowledge has been useful in some ways.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> I am more patient with love. I am more relaxed.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> I am more confident about asking for what I want.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> But I can also see myself more clearly,  and I can see that what I want is sometimes more  than can reasonably be asked for.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> What I want from love is a guarantee,  not just that I am loved today  and that I will be loved tomorrow,  but that I will continue to be loved by the person I love indefinitely.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> Maybe it's this possibility of a guarantee  that people were really asking about  when they wanted to know if we were still together.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> So the story that the media told about the 36 questions  was that there might be a shortcut to falling in love.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> There might be a way to somehow mitigate some of the risk involved,  and this is a very appealing story,  because falling in love feels amazing,  but it's also terrifying.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> The moment you admit to loving someone,  you admit to having a lot to lose,  and it's true that these questions do provide a mechanism  for getting to know someone quickly,  which is also a mechanism for being known,  and I think this is the thing that most of us really want from love:  to be known, to be seen, to be understood.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> But I think when it comes to love,  we are too willing to accept the short version of the story.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> The version of the story that asks, "Are you still together?"    </seg>
<seg id="84"> and is content with a yes or no answer.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> So rather than that question,  I would propose we ask some more difficult questions,  questions like:  How do you decide who deserves your love  and who does not?    </seg>
<seg id="86"> How do you stay in love when things get difficult,  and how do you know when to just cut and run?    </seg>
<seg id="87"> How do you live with the doubt  that inevitably creeps into every relationship,  or even harder,  how do you live with your partner's doubt?    </seg>
<seg id="88"> I don't necessarily know the answers to these questions,  but I think they're an important start at having a more thoughtful conversation  about what it means to love someone.    </seg>
<seg id="89"> So, if you want it,  the short version of the story of my relationship is this:  a year ago, an acquaintance and I did a study  designed to create romantic love,  and we fell in love,  and we are still together,  and I am so glad.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> But falling in love is not the same thing as staying in love.    </seg>
<seg id="91"> Falling in love is the easy part.    </seg>
<seg id="92"> So at the end of my article, I wrote, "Love didn't happen to us.    </seg>
<seg id="93"> We're in love because we each made the choice to be."    </seg>
<seg id="94"> And I cringe a little when I read that now,  not because it isn't true,  but because at the time, I really hadn't considered  everything that was contained in that choice.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> I didn't consider how many times we would each have to make that choice,  and how many times I will continue to have to make that choice  without knowing whether or not he will always choose me.    </seg>
<seg id="96"> I want it to be enough to have asked and answered 36 questions,  and to have chosen to love someone so generous and kind and fun  and to have broadcast that choice in the biggest newspaper in America.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> But what I have done instead is turn my relationship  into the kind of myth I don't quite believe in.    </seg>
<seg id="98"> And what I want, what perhaps I will spend my life wanting,  is for that myth to be true.    </seg>
<seg id="99"> I want the happy ending implied by the title to my article,  which is, incidentally,  the only part of the article that I didn't actually write.    </seg>
<seg id="100">   But what I have instead is the chance to make the choice to love someone,  and the hope that he will choose to love me back,  and it is terrifying,  but that's the deal with love.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2319" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/dustin_yellin_a_journey_through_the_mind_of_an_artist</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Dustin Yellin makes mesmerizing artwork that tells complex, myth-inspired stories. How did he develop his style? In this disarming talk, he shares the journey of an artist -- starting from age 8 -- and his idiosyncratic way of thinking and seeing. Follow the path that leads him up to his latest major work .</description> 
<keywords>talks, art, collaboration, creativity</keywords> 
<talkid>2319</talkid> 
<title>Dustin Yellin: A journey through the mind of an artist</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> I was raised by lesbians in the mountains,  and I sort of came like a forest gnome to New York City a while back.    </seg>
<seg id="2">   Really messed with my head, but I'll get into that later.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> I'll start with when I was eight years old.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> I took a wood box,  and I buried a dollar bill, a pen and a fork inside this box in Colorado.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> And I thought some strange humanoids or aliens in 500 years would find this box  and learn about the way our species exchanged ideas,  maybe how we ate our spaghetti.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> I really didn't know.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> Anyway, this is kind of funny,  because here I am, 30 years later, and I'm still making boxes.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> Now, at some point I was in Hawaii --  I like to hike and surf and do all that weird stuff,  and I was making a collage for my ma.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> And I took a dictionary and I ripped it up,  and I made it into a sort of Agnes Martin grid,  and I poured resin all over it and a bee got stuck.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> Now, she's afraid of bees and she's allergic to them,  so I poured more resin on the canvas, thinking I could hide it or something.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> Instead, the opposite happened:  It sort of created a magnification,  like a magnifying glass, on the dictionary text.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> So what did I do? I built more boxes.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> This time, I started putting electronics, frogs,  strange bottles I'd find in the street -- anything I could find --  because I was always finding things my whole life,  and trying to make relationships and tell stories between these objects.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> So I started drawing around the objects,  and I realized: Holy moly, I can draw in space!    </seg>
<seg id="15"> I can make free-floating lines,  like the way you would draw around a dead body at a crime scene.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> So I took the objects out,  and I created my own taxonomy of invented specimens.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> First, botanical -- which you can kind of get a sense of.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> Then I made some weird insects and creatures.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> It was really fun; I was just drawing on the layers of resin.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> And it was cool, because I was actually starting to have shows and stuff,  I was making some money, I could take my girlfriend for dinner,  and like, go to Sizzler.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> It was some good shit, man.    </seg>
<seg id="22">   At some point, I got up to the human form,  life-size resin sculptures with drawings of humans inside the layers.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> This was great, except for one thing:  I was going to die.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> I didn't know what to do, because the resin was going to kill me.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> And I went to bed every night thinking about it.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> So I tried using glass.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> I started drawing on the layers of glass,  almost like if you drew on a window, then you put another window,  and another window, and you had all these windows together  that made a three-dimensional composition.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> And this really worked, because I could stop using the resin.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> So I did this for years,  which culminated in a very large work, which I call "The Triptych."    </seg>
<seg id="30"> "The Triptych" was largely inspired  by Hieronymus Bosch's "[The] Garden of Earthly Delights,"  which is a painting in the [Museo del] Prado in Spain.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> Do you guys know this painting?    </seg>
<seg id="32"> Good, it's a cool painting.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> It's kind of ahead of its time, they say.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> So, "The Triptych." I'll walk you through this piece.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> It weighs 24,000 pounds.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> It's 18 feet long.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> It's double-sided, so it's 36 feet of composition.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> It's kind of weird.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> Well, that's the blood fountain.    </seg>
<seg id="40">   To the left, you have Jesus and the locusts.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> There's a cave  where all these animal-headed creatures travel between two worlds.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> They go from the representational world,  to this analog-mesh underworld, where they're hiding.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> This is where the animal-headed creatures are by the lighthouse,  and they're all about to commit mass suicide into the ocean.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> The ocean is made up of thousands of elements.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> This is a bird god tied up to a battleship.    </seg>
<seg id="46">   Billy Graham is in the ocean;  the Horizon from the oil spill; Waldo; Osama Bin Laden's shelter --  if you look really hard, in the ocean.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> Anyway, this is a lady creature.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> She's coming out of the ocean, and she's spitting oil into one hand  and she has clouds coming out of her other hand.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> Her hands are like scales,  and she has the mythological reference of the Earth and cosmos in balance.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> So that's one side of "The Triptych."    </seg>
<seg id="51"> It's a little narrative thing.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> That's her hand that she's spitting into.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> And then, when you go to the other side,  she has like a trunk, like a bird's beak,  and she's spitting clouds out of her trunk.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> Then she has an 18-foot-long serpent's tail that connects "The Triptych."    </seg>
<seg id="55"> Anyway, her tail catches on fire from the back of the volcano.    </seg>
<seg id="56">   I don't know why that happened.    </seg>
<seg id="57">   That happens, you know.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> Her tail terminates in a cycloptic eyeball,  made out of 1986 terrorist cards.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> Have you guys seen those?    </seg>
<seg id="60"> They were made in the 1980's, they're like baseball cards of terrorists.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> Way ahead of their time.    </seg>
<seg id="62">   That will bring you to my latest project.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> I'm in the middle of two projects:  One's called "Psychogeographies."    </seg>
<seg id="64"> It's about a six-year project to make 100 of these humans.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> Each one is an archive of our culture,  through our ripped-up media and matter,  whether it's encyclopedias or dictionaries or magazines.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> But each one acts as a sort of an archive in the shape of a human,  and they travel in groups of 20, 4, or 12 at a time.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> They're like cells -- they come together, they divide.    </seg>
<seg id="68"> And you kind of walk through them. It's taking me years.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> Each one is basically a 3,000-pound microscope slide  with a human stuck inside.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> This one has a little cave in his chest.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> That's his head; there's the chest, you can kind of see the beginning.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> I'm going to go down the body for you:  There's a waterfall coming out of his chest,  covering his penis -- or not-penis, or whatever it is,  a kind of androgynous thing.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> I'll take you quickly through these works,  because I can't explain them for too long.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> There are the layers, you can kind of see it.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> That's a body getting split in half.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> This one has two heads,  and it's communicating between the two heads.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> You can see the pills coming out,  going into one head from this weird statue.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> There's a little forest scene inside the chest cavity.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> Can you see that?    </seg>
<seg id="80"> Anyway, this talk's all about these boxes,  like the boxes we're in.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> This box we're in, the solar system is a box.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> This brings you to my latest box.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> It's a brick box. It's called Pioneer Works.    </seg>
<seg id="84">   Inside of this box is a physicist,  a neuroscientist, a painter, a musician,  a writer, a radio station, a museum, a school,  a publishing arm to disseminate all the content we make there into the world;  a garden.    </seg>
<seg id="85"> We shake this box up,  and all these people kind of start hitting each other like particles.    </seg>
<seg id="86"> And I think that's the way you change the world.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> You redefine your insides and the box that you're living in.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> And you come together to realize that we're all in this together,  that this delusion of difference --  this idea of countries, of borders, of religion -- doesn't work.    </seg>
<seg id="89"> We're all really made up of the same stuff, in the same box.    </seg>
<seg id="90"> And if we don't start exchanging that stuff sweetly and nicely,  we're all going to die real soon.    </seg>
<seg id="91"> Thank you very much.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2313" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/patience_mthunzi_could_we_cure_hiv_with_lasers</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Swallowing pills to get medication is a quick, painless and often not entirely effective way of treating disease. A potentially better way? Lasers. In this passionate talk, TED Fellow Patience Mthunzi explains her idea to use lasers to deliver drugs directly to cells infected with HIV. It's early days yet, but could a cure be on the horizon?</description> 
<keywords>talks, AIDS, HIV, health, health care, innovation, medical research, medicine, molecular biology, pharmaceuticals, science</keywords> 
<talkid>2313</talkid> 
<title>Patience Mthunzi: Could we cure HIV with lasers?</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> What do you do when you have a headache?    </seg>
<seg id="2"> You swallow an aspirin.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> But for this pill to get to your head, where the pain is,  it goes through your stomach, intestines and various other organs first.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> Swallowing pills is the most effective and painless way of delivering  any medication in the body.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> The downside, though, is that swallowing any medication leads to its dilution.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> And this is a big problem, particularly in HIV patients.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> When they take their anti-HIV drugs,  these drugs are good for lowering the virus in the blood,  and increasing the CD4 cell counts.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> But they are also notorious for their adverse side effects,  but mostly bad, because they get diluted by the time they get to the blood,  and worse, by the time they get to the sites  where it matters most: within the HIV viral reservoirs.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> These areas in the body -- such as the lymph nodes,  the nervous system, as well as the lungs --  where the virus is sleeping,  and will not readily get delivered in the blood  of patients that are under consistent anti-HIV drugs therapy.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> However, upon discontinuation of therapy,  the virus can awake and infect new cells in the blood.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> Now, all this is a big problem in treating HIV with the current drug treatment,  which is a life-long treatment that must be swallowed by patients.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> One day, I sat and thought,  "Can we deliver anti-HIV directly within its reservoir sites,  without the risk of drug dilution?"    </seg>
<seg id="13"> As a laser scientist, the answer was just before my eyes:  Lasers, of course.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> If they can be used for dentistry,  for diabetic wound-healing and surgery,  they can be used for anything imaginable,  including transporting drugs into cells.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> As a matter of fact, we are currently using laser pulses  to poke or drill extremely tiny holes,  which open and close almost immediately in HIV-infected cells,  in order to deliver drugs within them.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> "How is that possible?" you may ask.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> Well, we shine a very powerful but super-tiny laser beam  onto the membrane of HIV-infected cells  while these cells are immersed in liquid containing the drug.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> The laser pierces the cell, while the cell swallows the drug  in a matter of microseconds.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> Before you even know it,  the induced hole becomes immediately repaired.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> Now, we are currently testing this technology in test tubes  or in Petri dishes,  but the goal is to get this technology in the human body,  apply it in the human body.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> "How is that possible?" you may ask.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> Well, the answer is: through a three-headed device.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> Using the first head, which is our laser,  we will make an incision in the site of infection.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> Using the second head, which is a camera,  we meander to the site of infection.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> Finally, using a third head, which is a drug-spreading sprinkler,  we deliver the drugs directly at the site of infection,  while the laser is again used to poke those cells open.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> Well, this might not seem like much right now.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> But one day, if successful, this technology can lead  to complete eradication of HIV in the body.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> Yes. A cure for HIV.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> This is every HIV researcher's dream --  in our case, a cure lead by lasers.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2309" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/benedetta_berti_the_surprising_way_groups_like_isis_stay_in_power</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: ISIS, Hezbollah, Hamas. These three very different groups are known for violence  but thats only a portion of what they do, says policy analyst Benedetta Berti. They also attempt to win over populations with social work: setting up schools and hospitals, offering safety and security, and filling the gaps left by weak governments. Understanding the broader work of these groups suggests new strategies for ending the violence.</description> 
<keywords>talks, Middle East, TED Fellows, global issues, politics, terrorism, violence</keywords> 
<talkid>2309</talkid> 
<title>Benedetta Berti: The surprising way groups like ISIS stay in power</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> For the past decade,  I've been studying non-state armed groups:  armed organizations like terrorists, insurgents or militias.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> I document what these groups do when they're not shooting.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> My goal is to better understand these violent actors  and to study ways to encourage transition from violent engagement  to nonviolent confrontation.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> I work in the field, in the policy world and in the library.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> Understanding non-state armed groups is key to solving most ongoing conflict,  because war has changed.    </seg>
<seg id="6"> It used to be a contest between states.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> No longer.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> It is now a conflict between states and non-state actors.    </seg>
<seg id="9"> For example, of the 216 peace agreements  signed between 1975 and 2011,  196 of them were between a state and a non-state actor.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> So we need to understand these groups; we need to either engage them  or defeat them in any conflict resolution process that has to be successful.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> So how do we do that?    </seg>
<seg id="12"> We need to know what makes these organizations tick.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> We know a lot about how they fight, why they fight,  but no one looks at what they're doing when they're not fighting.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> Yet, armed struggle and unarmed politics are related.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> It is all part of the same organization.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> We cannot understand these groups, let alone defeat them,  if we don't have the full picture.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> And armed groups today are complex organizations.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> Take the Lebanese Hezbollah,  known for its violent confrontation against Israel.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> But since its creation in the early 1980s,  Hezbollah has also set up a political party,  a social-service network, and a military apparatus.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> known for its suicide attacks against Israel,  also runs the Gaza Strip since 2007.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> So these groups do way more than just shoot.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> They multi-task.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> They set up complex communication machines --  radio stations, TV channels,  Internet websites and social media strategies.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> And up here, you have the ISIS magazine,  printed in English and published to recruit.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> Armed groups also invest in complex fund-raising --  not looting, but setting up profitable businesses;  for example, construction companies.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> Now, these activities are keys.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> They allow these groups to increase their strength,  increase their funds,  to better recruit and to build their brand.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> Armed groups also do something else:  they build stronger bonds with the population  by investing in social services.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> They build schools, they run hospitals,  they set up vocational-training programs or micro-loan programs.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> Hezbollah offers all of these services and more.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> Armed groups also seek to win the population over  by offering something that the state is not providing:  safety and security.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> The initial rise of the Taliban in war-torn Afghanistan,  or even the beginning of the ascent of ISIS,  can be understood also by looking at these groups' efforts  to provide security.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> Now, unfortunately, in these cases,  the provision of security came at an unbearably high price  for the population.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> But in general, providing social services fills a gap,  a governance gap left by the government,  and allows these groups to increase their strength  and their power.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> For example, the 2006 electoral victory of the Palestinian Hamas  cannot be understood without acknowledging the group's social work.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> Now, this is a really complex picture,  yet in the West, when we look at armed groups,  we only think of the violent side.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> But that's not enough to understand these groups' strength,  strategy or long-term vision.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> These groups are hybrid.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> They rise because they fill a gap left by the government,  and they emerge to be both armed and political,  engage in violent struggle and provide governance.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> And the more these organizations are complex and sophisticated,  the less we can think of them as the opposite of a state.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> Now, what do you call a group like Hezbollah?    </seg>
<seg id="42"> They run part of a territory, they administer all their functions,  they pick up the garbage, they run the sewage system.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> Is this a state? Is it a rebel group?    </seg>
<seg id="44"> Or maybe something else, something different and new?    </seg>
<seg id="45"> And what about ISIS?    </seg>
<seg id="46"> The lines are blurred.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> We live in a world of states, non-states, and in-between,  and the more states are weak, like in the Middle East today,  the more non-state actors step in and fill that gap.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> This matters for governments, because to counter these groups,  they will have to invest more in non-military tools.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> Filling that governance gap  has to be at the center of any sustainable approach.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> This also matters very much for peacemaking and peacebuilding.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> If we better understand armed groups,  we will better know what incentives to offer  to encourage the transition from violence to nonviolence.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> So in this new contest between states and non-states,  military power can win some battles,  but it will not give us peace nor stability.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> To achieve these objectives,  what we need is a long-term investment in filling that security gap,  in filling that governance gap  that allowed these groups to thrive in the first place.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2284" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/roxane_gay_confessions_of_a_bad_feminist</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: When writer Roxane Gay dubbed herself a "bad feminist," she was making a joke, acknowledging that she couldn't possibly live up to the demands for perfection of the feminist movement. But she's realized that the joke rang hollow. In a thoughtful and provocative talk, she asks us to embrace all flavors of feminism -- and make the small choices that, en masse, might lead to actual change.</description> 
<keywords>talks, feminism, identity, women</keywords> 
<talkid>2284</talkid> 
<title>Roxane Gay: Confessions of a bad feminist</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> I am failing as a woman,  I am failing as a feminist.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> I have passionate opinions about gender equality,  but I worry that to freely accept the label of "feminist,"  would not be fair to good feminists.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> I'm a feminist, but I'm a rather bad one.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> Oh, so I call myself a Bad Feminist.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> Or at least, I wrote an essay,  and then I wrote a book called "Bad Feminist,"  and then in interviews, people started calling me The Bad Feminist.    </seg>
<seg id="6">   So, what started as a bit of an inside joke with myself  and a willful provocation,  has become a thing.    </seg>
<seg id="7"> Let me take a step back.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> When I was younger,  mostly in my teens and 20s,  I had strange ideas about feminists  as hairy, angry, man-hating, sex-hating women --  as if those are bad things.    </seg>
<seg id="9">   These days, I look at how women are treated the world over,  and anger, in particular, seems like a perfectly reasonable response.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> But back then,  when suggesting I might be a feminist.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> The feminist label was an accusation,  it was an "F" word, and not a nice one.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> I was labeled a woman who doesn't play by the rules,  who expects too much,  who thinks far too highly of myself,  by daring to believe I'm equal --  -- superior to a man.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> until you realize that you very much are that woman,  and cannot imagine being anyone else.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> As I got older, I began to accept  that I am, indeed, a feminist, and a proud one.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> I hold certain truths to be self-evident:  Women are equal to men.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> We deserve equal pay for equal work.    </seg>
<seg id="17"> We have the right to move through the world as we choose,  free from harassment or violence.    </seg>
<seg id="18"> We have the right to easy, affordable access to birth control,  and reproductive services.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> We have the right to make choices about our bodies,  free from legislative oversight or evangelical doctrine.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> We have the right to respect.    </seg>
<seg id="21"> There's more.    </seg>
<seg id="22"> When we talk about the needs of women,  we have to consider the other identities we inhabit.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> We are not just women.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> We are people with different bodies,  gender expressions, faiths, sexualities,  class backgrounds, abilities, and so much more.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> We need to take into account  these differences and how they affect us,  as much as we account for what we have in common.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> Without this kind of inclusion, our feminism is nothing.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> I hold these truths to be self-evident, but let me be clear:  I'm a mess.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> I am full of contradictions.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> There are many ways in which I'm doing feminism wrong.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> I have another confession.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> When I drive to work, I listen to thuggish rap at a very loud volume.    </seg>
<seg id="32">   Even though the lyrics are degrading to women --  these lyrics offend me to my core --  the classic Yin Yang Twins song "Salt Shaker" --  it is amazing.    </seg>
<seg id="33">   "Make it work with your wet t-shirt.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> Bitch, you gotta shake it 'til your camel starts to hurt!"    </seg>
<seg id="35">   Think about it.    </seg>
<seg id="36">   Poetry, right?    </seg>
<seg id="37"> I am utterly mortified by my music choices.    </seg>
<seg id="38">   I firmly believe in man work,  which is anything I don't want to do, including --   --  all domestic tasks,  but also: bug killing, trash removal, lawn care and vehicle maintenance.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> I want no part of any of that.    </seg>
<seg id="40">   Pink is my favorite color.    </seg>
<seg id="41"> I enjoy fashion magazines and pretty things.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> I watch "The Bachelor" and romantic comedies,  and I have absurd fantasies about fairy tales coming true.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> Some of my transgressions are more flagrant.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> If a woman wants to take her husband's name,  that is her choice, and it is not my place to judge.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> If a woman chooses to stay home to raise her children,  I embrace that choice, too.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> The problem is not that she makes herself economically vulnerable in that choice;  the problem is that our society is set up  to make women economically vulnerable when they choose.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> Let's deal with that.    </seg>
<seg id="48">   I reject the mainstream feminism  that has historically ignored or deflected the needs  of women of color, working-class women, queer women and transgender women,  in favor of supporting white, middle- and upper-class straight women.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> Listen, if that's good feminism -- I am a very bad feminist.    </seg>
<seg id="50">   There is also this:  As a feminist, I feel a lot of pressure.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> We have this tendency to put visible feminists on a pedestal.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> We expect them to pose perfectly.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> When they disappoint us,  we gleefully knock them from the very pedestal we put them on.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> Like I said, I am a mess --  consider me knocked off that pedestal  before you ever try to put me up there.    </seg>
<seg id="55">   Too many women,  particularly groundbreaking women and industry leaders,  are afraid to be labeled as feminists.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> They're afraid to stand up and say, "Yes, I am a feminist,"  for fear of what that label means,  for fear of being unable to live up to unrealistic expectations.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> Take, for example, Beyonc, or as I call her, The Goddess.    </seg>
<seg id="58">   She has emerged, in recent years, as a visible feminist.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> At the 2014 MTV Video Music Awards,  she performed in front of the word "feminist" 10 feet high.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> It was a glorious spectacle to see  this pop star openly embracing feminism  and letting young women and men know  that being a feminist is something to celebrate.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> As the moment faded, cultural critics began endlessly debating  whether or not Beyonc was, indeed, a feminist.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> They graded her feminism,  instead of simply taking a grown, accomplished woman at her word.    </seg>
<seg id="63">     We demand perfection from feminists,  because we are still fighting for so much,  we want so much,  we need so damn much.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> We go far beyond reasonable, constructive criticism,  to dissecting any given woman's feminism,  tearing it apart until there's nothing left.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> We do not need to do that.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> Bad feminism -- or really, more inclusive feminism -- is a starting point.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> But what happens next?    </seg>
<seg id="68"> We go from acknowledging our imperfections to accountability,  or walking the walk, and being a little bit brave.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> If I listen to degrading music,  I am creating a demand for which artists are more than happy  to contribute a limitless supply.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> These artists are not going to change  how they talk about women in their songs  until we demand that change by affecting their bottom line. Certainly, it is difficult.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> Why must it be so catchy?    </seg>
<seg id="72">   It's hard to make the better choice,  and it is so easy to justify a lesser one.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> But --  when I justify bad choices,  I make it harder for women to achieve equality,  the equality that we all deserve,  and I need to own that.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> I think of my nieces, ages three and four.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> They are gorgeous and headstrong, brilliant girls,  who are a whole lot of brave.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> I want them to thrive in a world where they are valued  for the powerful creatures they are.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> I think of them,  and suddenly, the better choice becomes far easier to make.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> We can all make better choices.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> We can change the channel when a television show  treats sexual violence against women like sport,  Game of Thrones.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> We can change the radio station  when we hear songs that treat women as nothing.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> We can spend our box office dollars elsewhere  when movies don't treat women  as anything more than decorative objects.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> where the athletes treat their partners like punching bags.    </seg>
<seg id="83">   In other ways, men -- and especially straight white men --  can say, "No, I will not publish with your magazine,  or participate in your project, or otherwise work with you,  both as participants and decision makers.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> I won't work with you until your publication,  or your organization, is more inclusive of all kinds of difference."    </seg>
<seg id="85"> Those of us who are underrepresented  and invited to participate in such projects,  can also decline to be included  until more of us are invited through the glass ceiling,  and we are tokens no more.    </seg>
<seg id="86"> Without these efforts,  without taking these stands,  our accomplishments are going to mean very little.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> We can commit these small acts of bravery  and hope that our choices trickle upward to the people in power --  editors, movie and music producers,  CEOs, lawmakers --  the people who can make bigger, braver choices  to create lasting, meaningful change.    </seg>
<seg id="88"> We can also boldly claim our feminism --  good, bad, or anywhere in between.    </seg>
<seg id="89"> The last line of my book "Bad Feminist" says,  "I would rather be a bad feminist than no feminist at all."    </seg>
<seg id="90"> This is true for so many reasons,  but first and foremost, I say this because once upon a time,  my voice was stolen from me,  and feminism helped me to get my voice back.    </seg>
<seg id="91"> There was an incident.    </seg>
<seg id="92"> I call it an incident so I can carry the burden of what happened.    </seg>
<seg id="93"> Some boys broke me,  when I was so young, I did not know  what boys can do to break a girl.    </seg>
<seg id="94"> They treated me like I was nothing.    </seg>
<seg id="95"> I began to believe I was nothing.    </seg>
<seg id="96"> They stole my voice, and in the after,  I did not dare to believe  that anything I might say could matter.    </seg>
<seg id="97"> But --  I had writing.    </seg>
<seg id="98"> And there, I wrote myself back together.    </seg>
<seg id="99"> I wrote myself toward a stronger version of myself.    </seg>
<seg id="100"> I read the words of women  who might understand a story like mine,  and women who looked like me,  and understood what it was like to move through the world with brown skin.    </seg>
<seg id="101"> I read the words of women who showed me I was not nothing.    </seg>
<seg id="102"> I learned to write like them,  and then I learned to write as myself.    </seg>
<seg id="103"> I found my voice again,  and I started to believe that my voice is powerful beyond measure.    </seg>
<seg id="104"> Through writing and feminism,  I also found that if I was a little bit brave,  another woman might hear me and see me and recognize  that none of us are the nothing the world tries to tell us we are.    </seg>
<seg id="105"> In one hand,  I hold the power to accomplish anything.    </seg>
<seg id="106"> And in my other,  I hold the humbling reality that I am just one woman.    </seg>
<seg id="107"> I am a bad feminist,  I am a good woman,  I am trying to become better in how I think,  and what I say, and what I do,  without abandoning everything that makes me human.    </seg>
<seg id="108"> I hope that we can all do the same.    </seg>
<seg id="109"> I hope that we can all be a little bit brave,  when we most need such bravery.    </seg>
</doc>
<doc docid="2286" genre="lectures">
<url>http://www.ted.com/talks/steve_silberman_the_forgotten_history_of_autism</url> 
<description>TED Talk Subtitles and Transcript: Decades ago, few pediatricians had heard of autism. In 1975, 1 in 5,000 kids was estimated to have it. Today, 1 in 68 is on the autism spectrum. What caused this steep rise? Steve Silberman points to a perfect storm of autism awareness  a pair of psychologists with an accepting view, an unexpected pop culture moment and a new clinical test. But to really understand, we have to go back further to an Austrian doctor by the name of Hans Asperger, who published a pioneering paper in 1944. Because it was buried in time, autism has been shrouded in misunderstanding ever since. </description> 
<keywords>talks, Autism spectrum disorder, cognitive science, culture, history</keywords> 
<talkid>2286</talkid> 
<title>Steve Silberman: The forgotten history of autism</title> 
<reviewer></reviewer> 
<translator></translator> 
<seg id="1"> Just after Christmas last year,  132 kids in California got the measles  by either visiting Disneyland  or being exposed to someone who'd been there.    </seg>
<seg id="2"> The virus then hopped the Canadian border,  infecting more than 100 children in Quebec.    </seg>
<seg id="3"> One of the tragic things about this outbreak  is that measles, which can be fatal to a child with a weakened immune system,  is one of the most easily preventable diseases in the world.    </seg>
<seg id="4"> An effective vaccine against it  has been available for more than half a century,  but many of the kids involved in the Disneyland outbreak  had not been vaccinated  because their parents were afraid  of something allegedly even worse:  autism.    </seg>
<seg id="5"> But wait -- wasn't the paper that sparked the controversy  about autism and vaccines  debunked, retracted,  and branded a deliberate fraud  by the British Medical Journal?    </seg>
<seg id="6"> Don't most science-savvy people  know that the theory that vaccines cause autism is B.S.?    </seg>
<seg id="7"> I think most of you do,  but millions of parents worldwide  continue to fear that vaccines put their kids at risk for autism.    </seg>
<seg id="8"> Why?    </seg>
<seg id="9"> Here's why.    </seg>
<seg id="10"> This is a graph of autism prevalence estimates rising over time.    </seg>
<seg id="11"> For most of the 20th century,  autism was considered an incredibly rare condition.    </seg>
<seg id="12"> The few psychologists and pediatricians who'd even heard of it  figured they would get through their entire careers  without seeing a single case.    </seg>
<seg id="13"> For decades, the prevalence estimates remained stable  at just three or four children in 10,000.    </seg>
<seg id="14"> But then, in the 1990s,  the numbers started to skyrocket.    </seg>
<seg id="15"> Fundraising organizations like Autism Speaks  routinely refer to autism as an epidemic,  as if you could catch it from another kid at Disneyland.    </seg>
<seg id="16"> So what's going on?    </seg>
<seg id="17"> If it isn't vaccines, what is it?    </seg>
<seg id="18"> If you ask the folks down at the Centers for Disease Control in Atlanta  what's going on,  they tend to rely on phrases like "broadened diagnostic criteria"  and "better case finding"  to explain these rising numbers.    </seg>
<seg id="19"> But that kind of language  doesn't do much to allay the fears of a young mother  who is searching her two-year-old's face for eye contact.    </seg>
<seg id="20"> If the diagnostic criteria had to be broadened,  why were they so narrow in the first place?    </seg>
<seg id="21"> Why were cases of autism so hard to find  before the 1990s?    </seg>
<seg id="22"> Five years ago, I decided to try to uncover the answers to these questions.    </seg>
<seg id="23"> I learned that what happened  has less to do with the slow and cautious progress of science  than it does with the seductive power of storytelling.    </seg>
<seg id="24"> For most of the 20th century,  clinicians told one story  about what autism is and how it was discovered,  but that story turned out to be wrong,  and the consequences of it  are having a devastating impact on global public health.    </seg>
<seg id="25"> There was a second, more accurate story of autism  which had been lost and forgotten  in obscure corners of the clinical literature.    </seg>
<seg id="26"> This second story tells us everything about how we got here  and where we need to go next.    </seg>
<seg id="27"> The first story starts with a child psychiatrist at Johns Hopkins Hospital  named Leo Kanner.    </seg>
<seg id="28"> In 1943, Kanner published a paper  describing 11 young patients who seemed to inhabit private worlds,  ignoring the people around them,  even their own parents.    </seg>
<seg id="29"> They could amuse themselves for hours  by flapping their hands in front of their faces,  but they were panicked by little things  like their favorite toy being moved from its usual place  without their knowledge.    </seg>
<seg id="30"> Based on the patients who were brought to his clinic,  Kanner speculated that autism is very rare.    </seg>
<seg id="31"> By the 1950s, as the world's leading authority on the subject,  he declared that he had seen less than 150 true cases of his syndrome  while fielding referrals from as far away as South Africa.    </seg>
<seg id="32"> That's actually not surprising,  because Kanner's criteria for diagnosing autism  were incredibly selective.    </seg>
<seg id="33"> For example, he discouraged giving the diagnosis to children who had seizures  but now we know that epilepsy is very common in autism.    </seg>
<seg id="34"> He once bragged that he had turned nine out of 10 kids  referred to his office as autistic by other clinicians  without giving them an autism diagnosis.    </seg>
<seg id="35"> Kanner was a smart guy,  but a number of his theories didn't pan out.    </seg>
<seg id="36"> He classified autism as a form of infantile psychosis  caused by cold and unaffectionate parents.    </seg>
<seg id="37"> These children, he said,  had been kept neatly in a refrigerator that didn't defrost.    </seg>
<seg id="38"> At the same time, however,  Kanner noticed that some of his young patients  had special abilities that clustered in certain areas  like music, math and memory.    </seg>
<seg id="39"> One boy in his clinic  could distinguish between 18 symphonies before he turned two.    </seg>
<seg id="40"> When his mother put on one of his favorite records,  he would correctly declare, "Beethoven!"    </seg>
<seg id="41"> But Kanner took a dim view of these abilities,  claiming that the kids were just regurgitating things  they'd heard their pompous parents say,  desperate to earn their approval.    </seg>
<seg id="42"> As a result, autism became a source of shame and stigma for families,  and two generations of autistic children  were shipped off to institutions for their own good,  becoming invisible to the world at large.    </seg>
<seg id="43"> Amazingly, it wasn't until the 1970s  that researchers began to test Kanner's theory that autism was rare.    </seg>
<seg id="44"> Lorna Wing was a cognitive psychologist in London  who thought that Kanner's theory of refrigerator parenting  were "bloody stupid," as she told me.    </seg>
<seg id="45"> She and her husband John were warm and affectionate people,  and they had a profoundly autistic daughter named Susie.    </seg>
<seg id="46"> Lorna and John knew how hard it was to raise a child like Susie  without support services,  special education,  and the other resources that are out of reach without a diagnosis.    </seg>
<seg id="47"> To make the case to the National Health Service  that more resources were needed for autistic children and their families,  Lorna and her colleague Judith Gould  decided to do something that should have been done 30 years earlier.    </seg>
<seg id="48"> They undertook a study of autism prevalence in the general population.    </seg>
<seg id="49"> They pounded the pavement in a London suburb called Camberwell  to try to find autistic children in the community.    </seg>
<seg id="50"> What they saw made clear that Kanner's model was way too narrow,  while the reality of autism was much more colorful and diverse.    </seg>
<seg id="51"> Some kids couldn't talk at all,  while others waxed on at length about their fascination with astrophysics, dinosaurs or the genealogy of royalty.    </seg>
<seg id="52"> In other words, these children didn't fit into nice, neat boxes,  as Judith put it,  and they saw lots of them,  way more than Kanner's monolithic model would have predicted.    </seg>
<seg id="53"> At first, they were at a loss to make sense of their data.    </seg>
<seg id="54"> How had no one noticed these children before?    </seg>
<seg id="55"> But then Lorna came upon a reference to a paper that had been published  in German in 1944,  the year after Kanner's paper,  and then forgotten,  buried with the ashes of a terrible time  that no one wanted to remember or think about.    </seg>
<seg id="56"> Kanner knew about this competing paper,  but scrupulously avoided mentioning it in his own work.    </seg>
<seg id="57"> It had never even been translated into English,  but luckily, Lorna's husband spoke German,  and he translated it for her.    </seg>
<seg id="58"> The paper offered an alternate story of autism.    </seg>
<seg id="59"> Its author was a man named Hans Asperger,  who ran a combination clinic and residential school  Asperger's ideas about teaching children with learning differences  were progressive even by contemporary standards.    </seg>
<seg id="60"> Mornings at his clinic began with exercise classes set to music,  and the children put on plays on Sunday afternoons.    </seg>
<seg id="61"> Instead of blaming parents for causing autism,  Asperger framed it as a lifelong, polygenetic disability  that requires compassionate forms of support and accommodations  over the course of one's whole life.    </seg>
<seg id="62"> Rather than treating the kids in his clinic like patients,  Asperger called them his little professors,  and enlisted their help in developing methods of education  that were particularly suited to them.    </seg>
<seg id="63"> Crucially, Asperger viewed autism as a diverse continuum  that spans an astonishing range of giftedness and disability.    </seg>
<seg id="64"> He believed that autism and autistic traits are common  and always have been,  seeing aspects of this continuum in familiar archetypes from pop culture  like the socially awkward scientist  and the absent-minded professor.    </seg>
<seg id="65"> He went so far as to say,  it seems that for success in science and art,  a dash of autism is essential.    </seg>
<seg id="66"> Lorna and Judith realized that Kanner had been as wrong about autism being rare  as he had been about parents causing it.    </seg>
<seg id="67"> Over the next several years,  they quietly worked with the American Psychiatric Association  to broaden the criteria for diagnosis  to reflect the diversity of what they called "the autism spectrum."    </seg>
<seg id="68"> In the late '80s and early 1990s,  their changes went into effect,  swapping out Kanner's narrow model  for Asperger's broad and inclusive one.    </seg>
<seg id="69"> These changes weren't happening in a vacuum.    </seg>
<seg id="70"> By coincidence, as Lorna and Judith worked behind the scenes  to reform the criteria,  people all over the world were seeing an autistic adult for the first time.    </seg>
<seg id="71"> Before "Rain Man" came out in 1988,  only a tiny, ingrown circle of experts knew what autism looked like,  but after Dustin Hoffman's unforgettable performance as Raymond Babbitt  earned "Rain Man" four Academy Awards,  pediatricians, psychologists,  teachers and parents all over the world knew what autism looked like.    </seg>
<seg id="72"> Coincidentally, at the same time,  the first easy-to-use clinical tests for diagnosing autism were introduced.    </seg>
<seg id="73"> You no longer had to have a connection to that tiny circle of experts  to get your child evaluated.    </seg>
<seg id="74"> The combination of "Rain Man,"  the changes to the criteria, and the introduction of these tests  created a network effect,  a perfect storm of autism awareness.    </seg>
<seg id="75"> The number of diagnoses started to soar,  just as Lorna and Judith predicted, indeed hoped, that it would,  enabling autistic people and their families  to finally get the support and services they deserved.    </seg>
<seg id="76"> Then Andrew Wakefield came along  to blame the spike in diagnoses on vaccines,  a simple, powerful,  and seductively believable story  that was as wrong as Kanner's theory  that autism was rare.    </seg>
<seg id="77"> If the CDC's current estimate,  that one in 68 kids in America are on the spectrum, is correct,  autistics are one of the largest minority groups in the world.    </seg>
<seg id="78"> In recent years, autistic people have come together on the Internet  to reject the notion that they are puzzles to be solved  by the next medical breakthrough,  coining the term "neurodiversity"  to celebrate the varieties of human cognition.    </seg>
<seg id="79"> One way to understand neurodiversity  is to think in terms of human operating systems.    </seg>
<seg id="80"> Just because a P.C. is not running Windows doesn't mean that it's broken.    </seg>
<seg id="81"> By autistic standards, the normal human brain  is easily distractable,  obsessively social,  and suffers from a deficit of attention to detail.    </seg>
<seg id="82"> To be sure, autistic people have a hard time  living in a world not built for them.    </seg>
<seg id="83"> [Seventy] years later, we're still catching up to Asperger,  who believed that the "cure" for the most disabling aspects of autism  is to be found in understanding teachers,  accommodating employers,  supportive communities,  and parents who have faith in their children's potential.    </seg>
<seg id="84"> An autistic [man] named Zosia Zaks once said,  "We need all hands on deck to right the ship of humanity."    </seg>
<seg id="85"> As we sail into an uncertain future,  we need every form of human intelligence on the planet  working together to tackle the challenges that we face as a society.    </seg>
<seg id="86"> We can't afford to waste a brain.    </seg>
<seg id="87"> Thank you.    </seg>
</doc>
</srcset>
</mteval>
